<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Space·Time Will Tell on Space·Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Space·Time Will Tell on Space·Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 19:01:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving stories with cards</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/why-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 19:01:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/why-cards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier, we have posted the &lt;a href=&#34;the-space-time-deck.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a set of cards, designed to help with improv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why cards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In theory, an improv Storyteller should be able to use anything as
support for improvisation. That&amp;rsquo;s true whether they&amp;rsquo;re performing for
an audience, or improvising a plot for an ongoing Role-Playing Game,
or improvising their character as a RPG player, or writing a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know the ideal improviser? His name is Keyser Söze. In
&lt;em&gt;Usual Suspects&lt;/em&gt;, he manages to come up with a plot twist just by
looking at his coffee cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114814/mediaviewer/rm1975465472?ref_=tt_ov_i&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, most of us aren&amp;rsquo;t Keyser Söze. We have ideas, many of them,
all the time, but we typically have so many of them tha it&amp;rsquo;s hard
for us to concentrate pick one, focus on it, and develop it until
it actually becomes a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we need to focus. While on stage, improv actors focus on the
topic or constraints of the improv and on
actors around them, ignoring the rest of the universe. Around a
table, or at a writing table, the problem remains the same, but
the situation is different – where most improv acts last only
a few minutes, or at most ninety minutes, typical gaming sessions
last at least 4 hours with no breaks, and hundreds of pages worth
of rulebooks, plots, character sheets and modules on the table.
Writing takes months or years during which too much focus
&lt;code&gt;MAKES JACK A DULL BOY&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at one card is one way to focus your thoughts, for just
a few seconds, by forcing yourself to express your thoughts in
relationship to this card. Focus helps you pick one single idea
from the mass teeming in your brain, which
is what you need to make that story interesting and fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more on using the Space·Time Deck (or other sources
of improv) for all your story-telling needs!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Space·Time Deck</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/the-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 17:43:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/the-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Space·Time Deck is a card deck designed to be used as an improv
tool, both for storytelling and role-playing games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Excuse. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;II. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;III. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IV. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;V. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VI. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-7.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VII. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-8.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VIII. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-9.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IX. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-10.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-11.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XI. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-12.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XII. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-13.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XIII. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-14.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XIV. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-15.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XV. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-16.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XVI. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-17.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XVII. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-18.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XVIII. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-19.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XIX. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-20.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XX. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XXI. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-22.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/back.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be posting more about this deck in future posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the oddly large margins are there by design. We&amp;rsquo;ll try and offer this deck
for on-demand printing, and such margins are required by printers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space·Time Deck itself:  David Teller. &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0: Edward Burne-Jones, Tile Design - Theseus and the Minotaur in the Labyrinth. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I: No image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;II: Hyeronymus Bosch, The Garden of Earthly Delights [detail]. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;III: Publicity photo of American actress Fay Wray promoting the 1933 feature film &lt;em&gt;King Kong&lt;/em&gt;. Believed to be Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IV: Peter Brueghel, The Tower of Babel. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VI: Grigory Goldstein, Lenin gave a famous speech to a crowd of Soviet troops in Sverdlov Square, Moscow, in 1919. In the foreground was Leon Trotsky and Lev Kamenev. During Joseph Stalin&amp;rsquo;s government, the photograph was edited. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VII: English: Mushroom cloud of &amp;lsquo;Gadget&amp;rsquo; over Trinity, seconds after detonation. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VIII: Eugène Delacroix — Erich Lessing Culture and Fine Arts Archives via artsy.net. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IX: Bartolo di Fredi – Collegiate Church of San Gimignano, Italy. from the Old Testament cycle: The Israelites safely cross the Red Sea, but Pharaoh and his troops are drowned. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X: Le voyage dans la Lune, George Méliès. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XI: Uncertain, either Levy &amp;amp; Fils or Kuhn. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XII: editor Austen Henry Layard , drawing by L. Gruner, &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Monuments of Nineveh, Second Series&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; plate 5, London, J. Murray, 1853. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XIII: RKO Radio Pictures, still photographer Alexander Kahle - &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/stream/internationalpho13holl#page/n4/mode/1up&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;International Photographer&lt;/a&gt;, Volume XII, Number 12, January 1941 (front cover). Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XIV: &amp;ldquo;Le Veau d&amp;rsquo;or&amp;rdquo; (allégorie du scandale de Panama), par Henri Meyer. Public Domain (source: Gallica / Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XV: Netherlandish (possibly Jacob Cornelisz. van Oostsanen) Laughing Fool ca. 1500 - Oil on panel, 13 &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;16&lt;/sub&gt; x 9 in Davis Museum at Wellesley College. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XVI: Unable to find authorship or copyright information. Believed to be Public Domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XVII: Terra Cotta Army replica at the Forbidden Gardens in Katy, Texas. Picture: Wikipedia user Vybr8. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/en:Creative_Commons&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt;. (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XVIII: Mignon Nevada as &amp;ldquo;Ophelia&amp;rdquo;, glass negative photograph, circa 1910. Public Domain (source: Library of Congress, Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XIX: Eduard von Grützner, Falstaff mit großer Weinkanne und Becher. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XX: Copper engraving of Doctor Schnabel [i.e Dr. Beak], a plague doctor in seventeenth-century Rome, with a satirical macaronic poem (‘Vos Creditis, als eine Fabel, / quod scribitur vom Doctor Schnabel’) in octosyllabic rhyming couplets. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XXI: No image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amigurimi Cthulhu: Wikipedia user Bastique, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/1.0/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Attribution-ShareAlike 1.0&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tardis: Wikipedia user Zir  &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Attribution-ShareAlike 2.5&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5-leggede demon: Illustration du Dictionnaire infernal de Jacques Auguste Simon Collin de Plancy par Louis Le Breton, 6eme édition, 1863. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clock hand: Re digitized vintage public domain illustration of a black and white human hand with a clock, made available by Dawn Hudson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comic book tutorial for Fate Core</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/fate-rules-comic-leaflet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:04:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/fate-rules-comic-leaflet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in improv/narrative role-playing games, you may
have heard of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evilhat.com/home/fate-core/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fate Core&lt;/a&gt;, a great ruleset made by &lt;a href=&#34;http://evilhat.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Evil Hat&lt;/a&gt; exactly for
this purpose. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, it&amp;rsquo;s excellent, and it&amp;rsquo;s missing a tutorial,
so here is one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/fate/generic_rules_p0.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/fate/generic_rules_p1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, it fits in one sheet, and it&amp;rsquo;s designed to be printed
and brought with you at your table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to make it available in other languages – if you wish to help,
don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also available as a &lt;a href=&#34;../../images/fate/generic_rules.pdf&#34;&gt;high-resolution pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evilhat.com/home/fate-core/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fate Core&lt;/a&gt; is available as pay-what-you-want,
so don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to take a look at the book!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial was initially developed as part of &lt;a href=&#34;../../categories/ronin-time-bureaucrats&#34;&gt;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit for the idea of a Fate Core summary of rules goes to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uptofourplayers.com/fate-core-rules/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Up to 4 players&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: Is there an afterlife?</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/rtb-afterlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 19:24:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/rtb-afterlife/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is there an afterlife?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, of course, there is, and you came to the right place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, at &lt;strong&gt;Time After Time After Time Corporation&lt;/strong&gt;, we pride ourselves of taking care of both your Dearly Departed and of those Death-is-too-good-for-him types. While our competition will simply recreate digitized automatons to give you the illusion of interacting with the dead, we, at Time After Time After Time Corporation, we pride ourselves of having the ability to capture and upload the very SoulMind &amp;trade; of the dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you sign with Time After Time After Time Corporation, we will assemble a team of highly trained Space·Time operatives, who will be sent at the exact place and instant of death. They will install an undetectable SoulStream &amp;trade; to scan and upload the the SoulMind &amp;trade; of the dead to one of our own, patented, absolutely secure, SoulSpheres &amp;trade;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer a comprehensive choice of culturally-appropriate Heavens and Hells for most beliefs throughout the past, present and future history of mankind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time After Time After Time Corporation, where we take care of the dead, for as many eternities as it takes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(extract of &lt;a href=&#34;https://legacy.gitbook.com/book/yoric/rogue-time-bureaucrats/details&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://yoric.gitbooks.io/rogue-time-bureaucrats/content/here-there-and-right-behind-you-the-bureaucracy.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here, There and Right Behind You: The Bureaucracy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 09:30:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;« &lt;em&gt;Nobody remembers with certainty in which year the Great Snafu took place, but people generally agree that it was on a September, or perhaps on a Saturday afternoon, on some even-numbered millenium. Also, it involved blowing up the Universe, which made pretty much everybody unhappy, except for a few people who had been waiting for this opportunity to loudly exclaim&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;I told you so&amp;rdquo;&lt;em&gt;, and even they were not happy for long.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, when the Universe was rebooted&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;with a 99.999% confidence value&amp;rdquo;&lt;em&gt;, the President was barred from Time Travel indefinitely and the Agency for Preservation of Space-Time Continuity was created. Brave Agents dashing around time and space in their Continuum Indirections, fighting off mad scientists, resolving the Y2K bugs before they could overwrite the Universe, bodyguarding baby dictators and generally maintaining the status quo.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All this took place (subjective) eons ago. Nowadays, the Agency is known as the Time Bureaucracy. With (subjective) years, administrations and fashions, the Bureaucracy has reinvented itself countless times. It has been a strict-but-efficient police, as well as a dusty museum of inventions past and future. It has become a travel agency for dignitaries, as well as a time-traveling gossip source. It has been the military arm of an everlasting dictatorship, as well as an encyclopaedia of entirely verified facts. It has been a time-agnostic anarchist commune, as well as a an undercover channel used to buy future technologies without having to go through the messy process of research. It has been used as a torture chamber and as a taxation office. It has been public and secret, fashionable and forgettable, progressive and repressive, pangenicist and eugenicist and pretty much every other combination.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Throughout its existence and despite all these reinventions, the Bureaucracy has devoted and continues to devote considerable efforts to fighting the main threat towards the continued existence of the Universe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This threat is, of course, every single past, future and alternate versions of the Bureaucracy. Because, well, they are so very wrong, aren&amp;rsquo;t they?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a conflict of surprisingly little violence, made of subtle manipulations and grand gestures, of infiltrations, desertions, propaganda, and paradoxes. A Cold War more than a battlefield.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to Space·Time!&lt;/em&gt; »&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m putting together a book with all the rules and background of Ronin Time Bureaucrats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s open-source, readable &lt;a href=&#34;https://legacy.gitbook.com/book/yoric/rogue-time-bureaucrats&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on gitbook&lt;/a&gt; and the source code is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Yoric/ronin-time-bureaucrats&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll try and post updates now and then on this blog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.github.io/categories/ronin-time-bureaucrats/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://yoric.gitbooks.io/rogue-time-bureaucrats/content/cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is David Teller&amp;rsquo;s blog dedicated to role-playing games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>