<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Space·Time Will Tell on Space·Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Space·Time Will Tell on Space·Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 12:05:58 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvising with the Space·Time Deck: V. Hello, you gorgeous!</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/deck-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 12:05:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/deck-5/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is an extract from &lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.github.io/plotonomicon&#34;&gt;the Plotonomicon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that we have just changed the picture from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.github.io/images/space-time-deck/old-card-6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old picture (The Slaughter of the Innocents) one was considered too
violent – while both are museum pieces,
the first one depicts mass murder of children, and was thus discarded
as not-safe-for-children&amp;rsquo;s-hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new version gets rid of almost all violence, and offers much more
symbolism, hence much more freedom of improv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;interpretations&#34;&gt;Interpretations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Default interpretations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The futility of running away from Destiny?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The burden of knowledge?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This picture depicts &lt;strong&gt;Oedipus&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Sphinx of Thebes&lt;/strong&gt; facing – or
perhaps embracing – each other. In Greek Mythology, Oedipus is the
son of Queen Jocasta and King Laius of Thebes. Before Oedipus&amp;rsquo;
birth, it was prophecized that he would murder his father
and marry his own mother. To avoid the fulfilling of this
prophecy, Oedipus&amp;rsquo; parents had him wounded at birth
and abandoned to die in the wilderness. Of course, Oedipus
survived and was adopted by loving parents – the Queen and
King of Corinth. When, as a young adult, Oedipus eventually learnt of the
prophecy, not knowing that he had been adopted, he fled his
home to, once again, forestall the prophecy.
Oedipus ended up meeting and killing King Laius, his real
father, defeating the Sphinx of Thebes, and, as savior of
Thebes, marrying the recently widowed Queen Jocasta. This
unknowingly incestuous marriage cursed the city of Thebes,
but it is only years later that Queen Jocasta and King Oedipus
realized, after a series of coincidences and revelations, that
they were mother and son. In shame, Jocasta killed herself,
and Oedipus blinded himself, walking the roads as a blind
beggar. Just to make sure that this story couldn&amp;rsquo;t have any
kind of happy ending, their children continued the curse -
life was hard in Ancient Greek Myths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the Sphinx, she was a guardian of sorts, who choked
and ate whoever could not answer her riddles, until she
met a man who could, at which point she killed herself.
In a later version of the story, she actually gave Oedipus
the answer to the riddle, because that was her only way out
this role of evil monster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-image&#34;&gt;The image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fight between a hero and a monster, or a dance
    of seduction, or two arrogant figures, or a woman, more forward
    than what society expects, and a younger man, surprised.
    Also, a desolate landscape, the only entrance to a mysterious
    city. Also, a guardian of secrets, willing to shed her charge.
    Also, a blundering teenager, surprised by a question or a
    secret whispered and about to be trapped into power.
    Also, the clinging hand of a victim not fully dead yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-burden-of-knowledge&#34;&gt;The burden of knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information, but an information that
    comes with a cost. Maybe the cost is upfront and visible, and the
    heroes will have to meet it to get the information. More
    likely, this information comes with a responsibility that
    the characters should not have wanted, perhaps in the
    form of a choice to make, or a long-ignored debt to own.
    Perhaps it is time for a character to learn of a bastard they
    have sired, or a child thought dead, or a lover or a friend
    or a mentor in hardship. Perhaps it is time for the heroes
    to make a choice where no option is acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-futility-of-running-away-from-destiny&#34;&gt;The futility of running away from Destiny&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If something was
    hunting down the heroes, or perhaps their antagonists,
    that something has arrived, or at
    least a good reason to believe that it cannot be escaped.
    Perhaps a countdown had started for some doomsday clock?
    Doomsday has arrived while the characters were looking
    away. Maybe a prophecy was under way, or a paradox? In
    either case, it is time to tie the knot. Or maybe it is
    something less scary that cannot be escaped anymore,
    something like love, or a conversation that needs to
    happen now, even in the middle of a dungeon. Or maybe
    it is time for a character to realize their role in the
    story and perhaps even to accept it – a hero may be
    born, or a villain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-going-beyond-the-enemy-lines&#34;&gt;Example: Going beyond the enemy lines&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;World War 2 in Europe. The sarge and his men have been tasked
with a secret mission. They have spent two days half-lost
beyond the enemy lines, and have finally just reached the hill
behind Château Maniais. They only have a few hours before
the Obersturmführer escapes towards Berlin. The sarge looks
at the Château from his goggles. &lt;em&gt;What does he see?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Either side:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entire surroundings of Château Maniais have been turned
into fortifications. Sandbags and barbwires everywhere,
guard towards and machine guns. The only path leads towards
the entrance and it is covered by Panzers. It&amp;rsquo;s going to
be a tough job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The landscape is desolate, but only one of the windows is alight.
At the window, two shapes seem to be dancing. One of them is
uniformed, clearly the Obersturmführer. The other one is a womanm,
probably his mistress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The burden of knowledge:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Obersturmführer&amp;rsquo;s retinue is getting ready to leave, that much
is obvious – they are currently cleaning house. Which, among
other things, means that they are taking a bunch of civilians – women,
all of them – to the trench behind the castle, to be executed.
The heroes have a chance to save them, if they act now, but
this might come at the cost of the mission. Or the sarge can
decide to stay mute, to spare the rest of the team from the
responsibility of letting these innocents be murdered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Obersturmführer is getting ready to leave alright, and he&amp;rsquo;s not
leaving empty-handed. The sarge witnesses two trucks being loaded
with paintings, gold bars, jewels. Now, some squad members could
decide to go for the gold after – or instead of – their mission.
This could be desertion. Or the sarge might decide not to tell them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The futility of running away from Destiny:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sarge takes one second to focus, then drops the goggles.
The Obersturmführer is right here, not twenty paces from the squad,
relieving himself in front of a tree, or perhaps smoking
a cigarette. Destiny has come for him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was only a matter of time before the squad was spotted.
Well, while the sarge was spotting, a sentry noticed something
in the bushes. A patrol is dispatched to the squad&amp;rsquo;s position,
right now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-the-shifting-maze&#34;&gt;Example: The shifting maze&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of random strangers has awakened in a deadly shifting maze,
in which they must band together to survive. Or not. &lt;em&gt;Why were they
put in the labyrinth?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Either side:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a social experiment, pure and simple.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a rite of passage. If they manage to make it through, well,
some secret will be revealed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The burden of knowledge:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the strangers knows more than he lets on. He&amp;rsquo;s somehow
responsible for everybody being here, perhaps because he built
the maze, or perhaps because he&amp;rsquo;s the target, and everybody else
was just caught with him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The maze is an interrogation device. This is not the first time
the strangers awake in the maze. They have died already, and died
again, and been cloned or resurrected. Each time, the maze rearranges
itself, trying to get the strangers to talk and share. This will
continue until one of the strangers finally reveals their secret.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The futility or running away from Destiny:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everybody is sent to the maze, at least once on their lifetime.
They don&amp;rsquo;t remember, because if they survive, their memory is erased.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All these strangers are actually dead. This is some form of purgatory or hell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-what-does-the-alchemist-want&#34;&gt;Example: What does the Alchemist want?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The heroes need the expertise of an alchemist to identify the Stone
of Power that they managed to trick away from the Lord of Wind Castle.
As it turns out, there is only one alchemist of renoun in the region,
and she serves in the Temple of the All-seeing. &lt;em&gt;What does she want?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Either side:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Alchemist is busy dealing with arcane knowledge. Maybe, if the
heroes somehow find a way to help her in her investigation, she
might make a little time to look at their babble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Alchemist is in the middle of a lover&amp;rsquo;s quarel. Her companion,
the professional hero, wants her tame and housebroken. She will have
none of that, and she has enough arrogance to match that of her
hero. For the moment, neither of the lover is willing to listen
to the heroes, but there may be a way to try and get them to
one-upman each other through piercing the enigma of the Stone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The burden of knowledge:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Alchemist is old, perhaps dying. She knows so many things,
and has nobody to pass that knowledge. At this stage, the Alchemist
wants – needs – an apprentice more than anything in this world.
Everything else is secondary, including answering the questions
of annoying heroes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oh, that Alchemist? You mean, your mom? Well, I&amp;rsquo;m sure she&amp;rsquo;d like
to hear about your latest adventures. Also, any grandchildren yet?
No? Well, it just happens so that she knows someone your age,
someone you should absolutely meet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The futility of running away from Destiny:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Stone of Power was created by the Alchemist, dozens of years
ago. When she found out what the Stone could do, she did her
best to destroy it or hide it. After all these years, the Stone
is returning to its creator. The Alchemist only wants one thing:
she wants to be far away from the Stone of Power!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Lord of Wind Castle is the former lover of the Alchemist.
When they broke up, he stole the Stone. The Alchemist wants
only one thing: the Stone itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Ronin Time Bureaucrats</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/ronin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:19:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/ronin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re currently working on a Role-Playing Game called &lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.github.io/tags/ronin-time-bureaucrats&#34;&gt;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect brains-over-brawn, improv and handwavy time paradoxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/ronin/Agency.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the latest draft (mostly complete, unformatted) &lt;a href=&#34;https://yoric.gitbooks.io/rogue-time-bureaucrats/content/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;.
Even in this unfinished form, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to leave feedbak!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: The Plotonomicon</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/plotonomicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:18:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/plotonomicon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re currently working on a book dedicated to improv in storytelling
and role-playing games: &lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.github.io/tags/plotonomicon&#34;&gt;The Plotonomicon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the latest draft (incomplete and unformatted) &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Space-TimeWillTell/Channeling-Keyser-Soze/blob/master/SUMMARY.md&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;.
Even in this unfinished form, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to leave feedbak!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re on DriveThruRPG!</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/now-on-drivethru/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:09:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/now-on-drivethru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks spent composing, recomposing and polishing
our &lt;a href=&#34;../fate-rules-comic-leaflet&#34;&gt;Fate comic book tutorial&lt;/a&gt;,
it&amp;rsquo;s now &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/252971/Fate-Core-Tutorial&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;available on DriveThruRPG&lt;/a&gt;
for pay-as-you-want, starting at $0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As previously, the license allows you to share, reproduce
and modify, provided you maintain credits, so feel free
to bring it to your playing table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re working on making it available print-on-demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all the fine folks on Reddit communities
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/RPGdesign/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;/u/RPGdesign&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/FATErpg/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;/u/FATErpg&lt;/a&gt; for the feedback,
and thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://evilhat.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Evil Hat&lt;/a&gt; for making
such a great game!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, back to working on the &lt;a href=&#34;../the-space-time-deck&#34;&gt;Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt; and its companion Plotonomicon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improv(is)ing stories with cards</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/why-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 19:01:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/why-cards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier, we have posted the &lt;a href=&#34;the-space-time-deck.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a set of cards, designed to help with improv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why cards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In theory, an improv Storyteller should be able to use anything as
support for improvisation. That&amp;rsquo;s true whether they&amp;rsquo;re performing for
an audience, or improvising a plot for an ongoing Role-Playing Game,
or improvising their character as a RPG player, or writing a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know the ideal improviser? His name is Keyser Söze. In
&lt;em&gt;Usual Suspects&lt;/em&gt;, he manages to come up with a plot twist just by
looking at his coffee cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/posts/why-cards/UsualSuspects.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114814/mediaviewer/rm1975465472&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, most of us aren&amp;rsquo;t Keyser Söze. We have ideas, many of them,
all the time, but we typically have so many of them tha it&amp;rsquo;s hard
for us to concentrate pick one, focus on it, and develop it until
it actually becomes a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we need to focus. While on stage, improv actors focus on the
topic or constraints of the improv and on
actors around them, ignoring the rest of the universe. Around a
table, or at a writing table, the problem remains the same, but
the situation is different – where most improv acts last only
a few minutes, or at most ninety minutes, typical gaming sessions
last at least 4 hours with no breaks, and hundreds of pages worth
of rulebooks, plots, character sheets and modules on the table.
Writing takes months or years during which too much focus
&lt;code&gt;MAKES JACK A DULL BOY&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at one card is one way to focus your thoughts, for just
a few seconds, by forcing yourself to express your thoughts in
relationship to this card. Focus helps you pick one single idea
from the mass teeming in your brain, which
is what you need to make that story interesting and fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more on using the Space·Time Deck (or other sources
of improv) for all your story-telling needs!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Space·Time Deck</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/the-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 17:43:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/the-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Space·Time Deck is a card deck designed to be used as an improv
tool, both for storytelling and role-playing games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Excuse. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;II. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;III. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IV. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;V. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VI. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-7.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VII. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-8.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VIII. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-9.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IX. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-10.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-11.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XI. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-12.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XII. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-13.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XIII. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-14.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XIV. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-15.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XV. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-16.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XVI. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-17.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XVII. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-18.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XVIII. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-19.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XIX. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-20.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XX. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XXI. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-22.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back. &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/back.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be posting more about this deck in future posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the oddly large margins are there by design. We&amp;rsquo;ll try and offer this deck
for on-demand printing, and such margins are required by printers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space·Time Deck itself:  David Teller. &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0: Edward Burne-Jones, Tile Design - Theseus and the Minotaur in the Labyrinth. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I: No image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;II: Hyeronymus Bosch, The Garden of Earthly Delights [detail]. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;III: Publicity photo of American actress Fay Wray promoting the 1933 feature film &lt;em&gt;King Kong&lt;/em&gt;. Believed to be Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IV: Peter Brueghel, The Tower of Babel. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;V: Gustave Moreau, Oedipus and the Sphinx. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia, Metropolitan Museum of Art).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VI: Grigory Goldstein, Lenin gave a famous speech to a crowd of Soviet troops in Sverdlov Square, Moscow, in 1919. In the foreground was Leon Trotsky and Lev Kamenev. During Joseph Stalin&amp;rsquo;s government, the photograph was edited. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VII: English: Mushroom cloud of &amp;lsquo;Gadget&amp;rsquo; over Trinity, seconds after detonation. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VIII: Eugène Delacroix — Erich Lessing Culture and Fine Arts Archives via artsy.net. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IX: Bartolo di Fredi – Collegiate Church of San Gimignano, Italy. from the Old Testament cycle: The Israelites safely cross the Red Sea, but Pharaoh and his troops are drowned. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X: Le voyage dans la Lune, George Méliès. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XI: Uncertain, either Levy &amp;amp; Fils or Kuhn. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XII: editor Austen Henry Layard , drawing by L. Gruner, &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Monuments of Nineveh, Second Series&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; plate 5, London, J. Murray, 1853. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XIII: RKO Radio Pictures, still photographer Alexander Kahle - &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/stream/internationalpho13holl#page/n4/mode/1up&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;International Photographer&lt;/a&gt;, Volume XII, Number 12, January 1941 (front cover). Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XIV: &amp;ldquo;Le Veau d&amp;rsquo;or&amp;rdquo; (allégorie du scandale de Panama), par Henri Meyer. Public Domain (source: Gallica / Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XV: Netherlandish (possibly Jacob Cornelisz. van Oostsanen) Laughing Fool ca. 1500 - Oil on panel, 13 &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;16&lt;/sub&gt; x 9 in Davis Museum at Wellesley College. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XVI: Unable to find authorship or copyright information. Believed to be Public Domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XVII: Terra Cotta Army replica at the Forbidden Gardens in Katy, Texas. Picture: Wikipedia user Vybr8. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/en:Creative_Commons&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt;. (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XVIII: Mignon Nevada as &amp;ldquo;Ophelia&amp;rdquo;, glass negative photograph, circa 1910. Public Domain (source: Library of Congress, Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XIX: Eduard von Grützner, Falstaff mit großer Weinkanne und Becher. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XX: Copper engraving of Doctor Schnabel [i.e Dr. Beak], a plague doctor in seventeenth-century Rome, with a satirical macaronic poem (‘Vos Creditis, als eine Fabel, / quod scribitur vom Doctor Schnabel’) in octosyllabic rhyming couplets. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XXI: No image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amigurimi Cthulhu: Wikipedia user Bastique, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/1.0/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Attribution-ShareAlike 1.0&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tardis: Wikipedia user Zir  &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Attribution-ShareAlike 2.5&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5-leggede demon: Illustration du Dictionnaire infernal de Jacques Auguste Simon Collin de Plancy par Louis Le Breton, 6eme édition, 1863. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clock hand: Re digitized vintage public domain illustration of a black and white human hand with a clock, made available by Dawn Hudson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comic book tutorial for Fate Core</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/fate-rules-comic-leaflet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:04:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/fate-rules-comic-leaflet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in improv/narrative role-playing games, you may
have heard of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evilhat.com/home/fate-core/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fate Core&lt;/a&gt;, a great ruleset made by &lt;a href=&#34;http://evilhat.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Evil Hat&lt;/a&gt; exactly for
this purpose. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, it&amp;rsquo;s excellent, and it&amp;rsquo;s missing a tutorial,
so here is one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/fate/generic_rules_p0.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/fate/generic_rules_p1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, it fits in one sheet, and it&amp;rsquo;s designed to be printed
and brought with you at your table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to make it available in other languages – if you wish to help,
don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also available as a &lt;a href=&#34;../../images/fate/generic_rules.pdf&#34;&gt;high-resolution pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evilhat.com/home/fate-core/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fate Core&lt;/a&gt; is available as pay-what-you-want,
so don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to take a look at the book!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial was initially developed as part of &lt;a href=&#34;../../categories/ronin-time-bureaucrats&#34;&gt;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit for the idea of a Fate Core summary of rules goes to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uptofourplayers.com/fate-core-rules/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Up to 4 players&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: Is there an afterlife?</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/rtb-afterlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 19:24:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/rtb-afterlife/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is there an afterlife?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, of course, there is, and you came to the right place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, at &lt;strong&gt;Time After Time After Time Corporation&lt;/strong&gt;, we pride ourselves of taking care of both your Dearly Departed and of those Death-is-too-good-for-him types. While our competition will simply recreate digitized automatons to give you the illusion of interacting with the dead, we, at Time After Time After Time Corporation, we pride ourselves of having the ability to capture and upload the very SoulMind &amp;trade; of the dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you sign with Time After Time After Time Corporation, we will assemble a team of highly trained Space·Time operatives, who will be sent at the exact place and instant of death. They will install an undetectable SoulStream &amp;trade; to scan and upload the the SoulMind &amp;trade; of the dead to one of our own, patented, absolutely secure, SoulSpheres &amp;trade;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer a comprehensive choice of culturally-appropriate Heavens and Hells for most beliefs throughout the past, present and future history of mankind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time After Time After Time Corporation, where we take care of the dead, for as many eternities as it takes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(extract of &lt;a href=&#34;https://legacy.gitbook.com/book/yoric/rogue-time-bureaucrats/details&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://yoric.gitbooks.io/rogue-time-bureaucrats/content/here-there-and-right-behind-you-the-bureaucracy.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here, There and Right Behind You: The Bureaucracy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 09:30:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;« &lt;em&gt;Nobody remembers with certainty in which year the Great Snafu took place, but people generally agree that it was on a September, or perhaps on a Saturday afternoon, on some even-numbered millenium. Also, it involved blowing up the Universe, which made pretty much everybody unhappy, except for a few people who had been waiting for this opportunity to loudly exclaim&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;I told you so&amp;rdquo;&lt;em&gt;, and even they were not happy for long.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, when the Universe was rebooted&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;with a 99.999% confidence value&amp;rdquo;&lt;em&gt;, the President was barred from Time Travel indefinitely and the Agency for Preservation of Space-Time Continuity was created. Brave Agents dashing around time and space in their Continuum Indirections, fighting off mad scientists, resolving the Y2K bugs before they could overwrite the Universe, bodyguarding baby dictators and generally maintaining the status quo.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All this took place (subjective) eons ago. Nowadays, the Agency is known as the Time Bureaucracy. With (subjective) years, administrations and fashions, the Bureaucracy has reinvented itself countless times. It has been a strict-but-efficient police, as well as a dusty museum of inventions past and future. It has become a travel agency for dignitaries, as well as a time-traveling gossip source. It has been the military arm of an everlasting dictatorship, as well as an encyclopaedia of entirely verified facts. It has been a time-agnostic anarchist commune, as well as a an undercover channel used to buy future technologies without having to go through the messy process of research. It has been used as a torture chamber and as a taxation office. It has been public and secret, fashionable and forgettable, progressive and repressive, pangenicist and eugenicist and pretty much every other combination.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Throughout its existence and despite all these reinventions, the Bureaucracy has devoted and continues to devote considerable efforts to fighting the main threat towards the continued existence of the Universe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This threat is, of course, every single past, future and alternate versions of the Bureaucracy. Because, well, they are so very wrong, aren&amp;rsquo;t they?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a conflict of surprisingly little violence, made of subtle manipulations and grand gestures, of infiltrations, desertions, propaganda, and paradoxes. A Cold War more than a battlefield.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to Space·Time!&lt;/em&gt; »&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m putting together a book with all the rules and background of Ronin Time Bureaucrats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s open-source, readable &lt;a href=&#34;https://legacy.gitbook.com/book/yoric/rogue-time-bureaucrats&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on gitbook&lt;/a&gt; and the source code is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Yoric/ronin-time-bureaucrats&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll try and post updates now and then on this blog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.github.io/categories/ronin-time-bureaucrats/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://yoric.gitbooks.io/rogue-time-bureaucrats/content/cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is David Teller&amp;rsquo;s blog dedicated to role-playing games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credits&lt;/strong&gt; The Clock Hand logo is based on a public domain illustration of a black and white human hand with a clock, made available by Dawn Hudson.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>