<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Space·Time Will Tell on Space·Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Space·Time Will Tell on Space·Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 13:45:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Space Time Deck</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 13:45:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Space·Time Deck is a deck of 67 cards and a few blanks, loosely inspired
from Tarot decks, and designed to aid with story improv, including
Role-Playing Games and other forms of Storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of the cards is designed to be interpreted on its own, and to be used
as part of a narrative role-playing ruleset. For both reasons, cards
have both illustrations and symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Space·Time Deck is used throughout &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/plotonomicon&#34;&gt;the Plotonomicon&lt;/a&gt;
for building plots, characters, places, factions, twists, etc. and
throughout &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/n-dimensional-tourists&#34;&gt;the N-Dimensional Tourists&lt;/a&gt;
as a base for resolving obstacles, conflicts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-cards&#34;&gt;Why cards?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first reason to use cards is that they are a natural support
for improv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In theory, in story improv, you should be able to use anything
around you as support for improvisation, anything you see or hear
or remember. In fact, the patron saint of improvisers is &lt;em&gt;Usual Suspects&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lsquo;
Keyser Söze, who manages to come up with a plot twist just by
looking at his coffee cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, most of us aren&amp;rsquo;t Keyser Söze. We have ideas, many of them,
all the time, but we typically have so many of them tha it&amp;rsquo;s hard
for us to pick one, focus on it, and develop it until it actually
becomes a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at one card is one way to focus your thoughts, for just
a few seconds, by forcing yourself to express your thoughts in
relationship to this card. Focus helps you pick one single idea
from the mass teeming in your brain, which
is what you need to make that story interesting and fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second reason for which we use cards is specific to gaming
and resolving obstacles or conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most role-playing games use dice for the purpose of resolving
obstacles or conflicts, and dice, once rolled, have a very limited
set of interpretations – typically only a number and a color.
Using cards that support open-ended interpretations gives us
much more freedom to build a story upon the workings of this
resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;composition&#34;&gt;Composition&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Space·Time Deck consists in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9 Cards of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock&#34;&gt;Rock Suit&lt;/a&gt;, unnumbered + 2 blanks – may symbolize stability, authority, power, physical strength, society, but also rigidity;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9 Cards of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper&#34;&gt;Paper Suit&lt;/a&gt;, unnumbered + 2 blanks – may symbolize knowledge, deduction, riches, but also fragility;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9 Cards of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-blades&#34;&gt;Blades Suit&lt;/a&gt;, unnumbered + 2 blanks – may symbolize forced change, violence and death;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9 Cards of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-serpent&#34;&gt;Serpent Suit&lt;/a&gt;, unnumbered + 2 blanks – may symbolize speed, stealth, adaptation, survival but also lies, forbidden knowledge, forbidden power, temptation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9 Cards of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-out-there&#34;&gt;Unknown Suit&lt;/a&gt;, unnumbered + 2 blanks – may symbolize imagination, intuition, perception, dreams, illusions, but also the unability to distinguish between facts and fiction;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;21 &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/post/the-space-time-deck/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Triumph Cards&lt;/a&gt;, numbered I to XXI, + 5 blanks;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/post/the-space-time-deck/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Excuse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each suit consists in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Ruler – may symbolize the power of taking decisions;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Dragon – the guardian of either the Ruler or the Treasure, and may symbolize the last, greatest obstacle in a quest;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Treasure – may symbolize that which you are seeking, whether riches, or knowledge, or peace, or anything else;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Soldier – may symbolize doing bad things on behalf of the Ruler, abandoning free will;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Builder – may symbolize the power of creation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Seeker – may symbolize the will of pursuing a quest;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Lover – may symbolize both desire and unity;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Servant – may symbolize forced obedience;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Home – may symbolize your origin;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Mover (blank) – may symbolize travel;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Child (blank) – may symbolize innocence;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blanks are designed to be customized. Add your characters,
places or factions or cosmic powers of importance
in your campaign, or anything that you believe matters,
as and when you see fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a professionally printed copy of the
Space·Time Deck and plan to use the deck for several campaigns,
you probably want to use unstickable stickers/sticky notes
for customization. Or, simply, got to your local RPG shop
and buy card protectors for all your cards, to make sure
that they cannot be distinguished at first sight, then
go ahead and print out custom cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, for whenever you need to determine if a card
somehow beats another one, there is a universal rule:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-4.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-4.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-horizontal-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 4, horizontal&#34;
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t show up on the diagram, it&amp;rsquo;s a stalemate)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;cards&#34;&gt;Cards&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each card consists in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an Illustration;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Title;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an upright Interpretation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a reversed Interpretation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suit cards also contain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Suit symbol;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Figure symbol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the Suit symbol or the Figure symbol may be in complete contradition with the Illustration, Title or Interpretations – or related only by the thinest of threads, possibly just a joke. If you are familiar with Tarot, you may find this surprising. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, this is by design: cards are there to provide starting blocks for improv, and to fit in open-ended stories with multiple narratives, not to force players into a single interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;interpreting-a-card&#34;&gt;Interpreting a card&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cards are good at helping you come up with answers to specific questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What does the Demagogue say in her speech?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why didn&amp;rsquo;t the police arrive in time?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What caused the plague?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What does the monster look like?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How does the engine breakdown?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a question, draw one card – orientation matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-a-triumph&#34;&gt;Example: A Triumph&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting: Cyberpunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question: &amp;ldquo;Who will the Syndicate send after the heroes?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Draw: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-10.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-10.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 10, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s now start observing things on the card:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the picture, a monster with the face of a woman (namely, the Sphinx of Thebes). So, let&amp;rsquo;s go for simplicity and decide that the assassin is a heavily modified woman. The Sphinx appears calm and in control of the situation, so let&amp;rsquo;s assume the same for the assassin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The interpretation facing us is &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;The futility of running away from destiny&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. This can mean that the assassin is going to catch up with the heroes, regardless of what they do. Or, it could mean that this assassin is someone that the heroes already know and whom they have avoided so far. Let&amp;rsquo;s go for both.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back to the picture, the monster and the young man (namely, Oedipus) seem to be embracing each other. So, let&amp;rsquo;s add to this the fact that the monster and one of the heroes are or have been lovers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still on the picture, a hand rising from a grave. There&amp;rsquo;s someone dead or dying between the heroes and the assassin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The card is reversed, so all of this is probably bad news for the heroes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By the way, we already have a name for the assassin: &amp;ldquo;The Sphinx&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the heroes do not have any such character in their backstory, it&amp;rsquo;s ok – backstories are highly malleable, so it is high time to ask one of them if they would please tell us more about their past love relationship with The Sphinx.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are, of course, other ways to interpret the card, and that&amp;rsquo;s entirely ok. Just pick one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-a-suit&#34;&gt;Example: A Suit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting: High Fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question: &amp;ldquo;What do the heroes find on the way to the Temple of Unlimited Horror?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Draw: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-66.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-66.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 66, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s now start observing the card:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the picture, some kind of oddly-shaped dragon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still on the picture, the dragon seems to have lost most of their HPs. So, let&amp;rsquo;s say that the heroes will encounter a gravely wounded dragon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The dragon is apparently fighting a child with a large sword. Let&amp;rsquo;s interpret this to mean that some irresponsible warrior has decided to kill the dragon, regardless of consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The interpretation &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Nope, the sword is mightier&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; could mean that this is all some kind of bet. So, maybe the warrior is trying to kill all the dragons in the region, just to make some kind of point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The card is also a Dragon Figure, so it may also be considered some kind of guardian. For some reason, the warrior and his retinue are obstacles on the road towards the Temple. Perhaps they have blockaded a road or an area that the heroes need to cross to reach the Temple.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here we go: in the course of the weeks that it takes them to travel to the Temple, the heroes find a trail of dead or dying dragon and dragon-like creatures, good and evil alike. They have all been hunted down by a young, irresponsible nobleman and his personal guard. This is the kind of action that will have bad, very bad consequences for the future of the entire kingdom. Also, in a more immediate matter, the personal guard of the nobleman is on the path of the heroes, and is going to prevent the heroes from progressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of bad consequences will the slaughter have? How are the personal guards going to cause problems for the heroes? Well, that sounds like questions for more cards!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plotonomicon: About This Book</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:22:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As all good things do, this book starts with a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the story of a Game Master (let&amp;rsquo;s call her Alice), who spent weeks preparing a campaign for her players. Maybe the Players&amp;rsquo;s Characters were to be a company of heroes, who would save the land from a dragon. Or maybe they were students in magics, who were expected to find the sinister secrets of the Sorcerous Highschool. Or maybe they were survivors of a zombie apocalypse, who were to spend each of their days hiding from hordes of shambling undead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of questing for the Magical Dragonsword, the company of heroes actually made a treaty with the dragon, or organized a coup and had the king send all &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; men to look after the item. Instead of looking for the secret passage that would lead them to the Layer of the Monster Under the School, they decided to test the laws of magic, until they blew up the school, or they ran to the teacher, telling her all she needed to know to fix the problem without putting children in harm&amp;rsquo;s way. Instead of waiting for the zombies to come at them, they grabbed a ship, and started a new pirate republic of the seas, or perhaps they decided to go for Cape Kennedy and try to launch their own expedition to the distant Moon Colony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, Alice, I sympathize, we all do. All of us GMs have been here. And I also have good news for you: that&amp;rsquo;s where the story really starts. Because now you are going to be able to build something even better, without the fear of railroading your players and without the stress of expecting that everything has to be prepared perfectly. Just as importantly, this is an opportunity for everybody to build the campaign &lt;em&gt;together&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also the story of a Player (let&amp;rsquo;s call him Bob), who had no idea what kind of character he wanted to play. Alice had told him that this game was about vampires, or knights, or space smugglers, but he didn&amp;rsquo;t really think of any reason to pick a story rather than another one, or a specific class, or set of skills. So Bob didn&amp;rsquo;t really have a good time during character creation, and since his character didn&amp;rsquo;t have a reason to be, he didn&amp;rsquo;t have much fun around the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, Bob, nice to meet you. Yeah, getting in a setting is tricky and getting in a character is basically impossible if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what you should be in that setting. So this book is for you, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo; also the story of a Writer, or a Storyteller (let&amp;rsquo;s call her Charlene), who had gotten her story started, but didn&amp;rsquo;t have fresh ideas for this antagonist, or that epic fight scene, or simply for finding out what laid behind the door that the hero had finally managed to open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi Alice, hi Bob, hi Charlene. Welcome to &lt;em&gt;The Plotonomicon&lt;/em&gt;. In this book, we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about getting ideas quickly and using them immediately, through techniques of improv. Some of these ideas will come from other players, others will come from the companion Space·Time Deck, and in many cases, you will realize that these are ideas that you already had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this book, we will describe situations that assume the existence of several players, each playing one character (or PC),
and one Game Master (or GM), playing the rest of the world, in particular the Non-Player Characters (or NPCs). Role-players will recognize the standard configuration of most Tabletop Role-Playing Games. However, this book is designed to be useful in more
situations than just standard Tabletop Role-Playing Games. If you are interested in other forms of storytelling, whether traditional (one storyteller in front of an audience), collaborative (several storytellers, weaving a story together, for each other or for an audience), or written (one writer or more, no audience), you should be able to adapt without difficulty most of the techniques described here to your favorite format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and one last thing: if you are looking for a ruleset for role-playing games, you won&amp;rsquo;t find any in this book, but don&amp;rsquo;t worry: the sister book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/n-dimensional-tourists&#34;&gt;The N-Dimensional Tourists&lt;/a&gt; has you covered – it contains a dedicated ruleset for role-playing with only the Space·Time Deck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Dimensional Tourists: Conflict Resolution</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-conflict-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:15:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-conflict-resolution/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-back.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-back.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-horizontal-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number back, horizontal&#34;
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These rules are part of the N-Dimensional Tourists ruleset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, this entry describes a mechanism to resolve Conflicts between
two parties or more during a role-playing game. It is designed to be generic
enough to cover pretty much any kind of Conflict with the same mechanism, while
remaining narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you&amp;rsquo;ll see in this chapter, this mechanism is freely inspired from both
Tarot and Blackjack – and it uses the &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/space-time-deck&#34;&gt;Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-conflicts&#34;&gt;About Conflicts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Conflict&lt;/strong&gt; is a scene in which two parties or more have
agendas, which cannot be fulfilled simultaneously. In most role-playing
games, the most common form of conflict is the combat, but that is by
no mean the only form possible: conflict could be car races, social wit,
political campaigns, chess, battlefield strategy, attempting to ruin your
opponent&amp;rsquo;s reputation or fortune, popularity contests, football matches,
etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflict does not have to be symmetrical. A guerilla may be attempting to
cause maximal damage to infrastructure while the government forces attempt
to destroy the guerilla forces. An outlying party may be attempting to
propagate its doctrine while the more traditional parties attempt to
maintain the status quo. A sniper may attempt to kill a target. A child
may be attempting to attract attention during a kidnapping attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflict does not have to be about killing or maiming. A chess game may
very well be a Conflict in which players are risking their reputation
and self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflicts assumes that both parties have some manner of assessing their
situation, and have some ability to act. In other words, as long as the
target of the sniper is not aware of the sniper, there is no conflict &lt;em&gt;between
the sniper and the target&lt;/em&gt;. In other words, if no other factors are in play,
the act of sniping will most likely be a simple case of &lt;strong&gt;Overcoming an obstacle&lt;/strong&gt;.
On the other hand, if the target is running away, there is a – very asummetrical —
conflict between the sniper and the target. Similarly, if an enemy patrol is
currently looking for an infiltrator, there is a conflict between the sniper&amp;rsquo;s
smarts, stealth and sniping ability and the enemy patrol&amp;rsquo;s smarts and detection
ability. Similarly, if the traditional parties are busy quelling a political
crisis or are unaware of the outlying party, there is no conflict between the
outlying party and the traditional parties – although there could be a
conflict between the outlying party and a specific candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflicts decide whether any of the parties manage to reach their desired
outcome. In the case of a race, the desired outcome is typically arriving
first. In the case of a gang fight, the desired outcome is typically getting
the other gang to end up broken and bleeding or fleeing. In the case of a
sniper vs. patrol, the desired outcome is typically evading the patrol and
killing the target vs. capturing the intruder before he has the chance to
cause damage. The players representing each party must have a clear idea
of the desired outcome for the conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/illustrations/Combat Knights 6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Credits: Flickr user Paul K&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are, of course, entirely free to change the desired outcome, but this
may end up completely changing the state of the conflict. For instance, if
the hidden sniper finds themself cornered, they may decide to change plan,
create maximum chaos and attempt to escape – but that&amp;rsquo;s a new conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;small-recap-of-character-attributes&#34;&gt;Small recap of character attributes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In N-Dimensional Tourists, each character is defined by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any number of &lt;strong&gt;Aspects&lt;/strong&gt;, which determine what the character can do;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 &lt;strong&gt;Attributes&lt;/strong&gt;, which determine how good a character is at their tasks;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any number of &lt;strong&gt;Specialties&lt;/strong&gt;, which let them use &lt;strong&gt;Attributes&lt;/strong&gt; in unusual manners;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least one &lt;strong&gt;Weakness&lt;/strong&gt;, which makes their life more complicated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Attributes are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rock&lt;/strong&gt; (stability, authority, power, physical strength);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper&lt;/strong&gt; (knowledge, deduction, riches);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blades&lt;/strong&gt; (violence, ability to effect change);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serpent&lt;/strong&gt; (speed, survival, stealth, lying);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unknown&lt;/strong&gt; (imagination, intuition, perception).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attributes range between 1 and 5. Other definitions are not numbered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, heroes start each session with a Reserve of 3 cards. We will see below one way to use these cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;required-material&#34;&gt;Required material&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflict resolution needs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Space·Time Deck;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a few tokens per party (a total of 10 tokens or 1d10 should be amply sufficient);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lots of space on the table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also want to take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;#cheat-sheet&#34;&gt;Cheat Sheet / Playing Mat&lt;/a&gt; below.
It will help you for your first few attempts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;resolving-the-conflict&#34;&gt;Resolving the Conflict&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a Conflict, each party attempts to reach a goal, by adopting shifting
tactics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key concept during a Conflict is the Advantage, which represents how close the
Dominant party is to having complete control of the Conflict. If the Conflict is
balanced, there is no Dominant party and the Advantage is 0. Otherwise, there
is a Dominant party, and its Advantage value is a positive number. Regardless of
how many parties are involved in the Conflict, only one party may have the Advantage.
Once a party has complete control of the Conflict, none can stop it from reaching
its goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Conflict takes place as a sequence of Rounds. Each Round represents all parties
attempting to execute their tactics to either grab the Advantage, if the Conflict
is Balanced, or otherwise strengthen/weaken the Advantage. Two successive Rounds may
represent entirely different durations, depending on what makes sense in the story –
one round may very well last ten minutes and the next one ten years, without problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To grab the Advantage, strengthen their Advantage or weaken the opponent&amp;rsquo;s Advantage,
each party may need to take risks. With risks come the possibility of Losses. Depending
on the Conflict, Losses may represent wounds, engine issues, delays, lack of information,
loss of soldiers, etc. As a
party accumulates Losses, it becomes weaker, hence making it easier for other parties
to beat them. Losses may end up with a party being Wiped Out. That&amp;rsquo;s not something
you want to see happen to your party, as this represents the worst possible outcome –
possibly death, or slavery, or social infamy, or life behind bars, depending on the
Conflict. Rather, most parties leave a Conflict by Conceding it, which may represent
for instance the party surrendering, fleeing, stepping down from power, etc. depending
on the Conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking risks is represented by a bidding mechanism – each card drawn increases the party&amp;rsquo;s
chance of achieving their tactics for the round, but also the chance of being hit by
Losses. Higher Advantage gives the Dominant party the ability to draw more cards before
they start taking risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, during the Conflict, a party finds itself in a situation in which it can suddenly
gain an advantage for reasons related to the story, rather than the cards themselves,
this party may take the opportunity, hence causing the Conflict to end immediately
and resume on different terms. This is called Reframing the Conflict. This is what
happens if a discussion leads to violence, or if a fleeing driver leaves the vehicle
to enter the subway, or if a political figure caught in a scandal declares a War
on Terror to distract the public opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s now see the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;establishing-parties-and-goals&#34;&gt;Establishing parties and goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do during a Conflict is to establish the parties and the goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, parties and goals are only acceptable if they make sense within the fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-kaiju&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider a Kaiju setting. This is Wednesday morning, so a giant monster is attacking Tokyo.
For some reason, everybody knows its name: Levinulon. The Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force is currently mobilizing. Tokyo&amp;rsquo;s Police is attempting to shoot at Levinulon using whatever is
at hand, but they have no chance of doing any damage. Civilians are fleeing. A gang of
criminals (&amp;ldquo;Family Z&amp;rdquo;) is taking advantage of the chaos to rob a bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the sides? Well, it depends on who is interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/posts/tourists-conflict-resolution/kaiju.png&#34; alt=&#34;Picture by Wikipedia User D J Shin – My Toy Museum – Licensed under Creative Commons Attribution ShareAlike 3.0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we are interested in Levinulon and the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force, then these are the two sides. Levinulon intends to destroy the city, while the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force intends to
save the city. The Police and civilians will certainly take damange, as well as Tokyo itself, but they have no means of altering the outcome of the Conflict. Rather, they will be used for narrative purposes, to show the progress of Levinulon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, maybe we are concentrating on the Conflict between Family Z and Police. Family Z intends
to grab the contents of the bank vaults and leave during the chaos, while the Police intends
arrest or shoot the gangsters. In this case,
the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force, Levinulon and the Civilizans will be there only for
narrative purposes, for instance to explain why the Police may end up losing Advantage
against such a low-profile gang (&amp;ldquo;all our communication channels are busy, we can&amp;rsquo;t
synchronize&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe we are concentrating on the efforts of Police officers to evacuate civilians towards safety bunkers. In this case, the parties are the Police officers and Generalized destruction.
Police officers intend to avoid Civilian losses, while Generalized destruction intends to
maximize it – of course, this only makes sense if Generalized destruction can somehow be interpreted as having a goal and tactics. This depends entirely on the kind of story you intend to tell. Here, the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force, Levinulon, the Civilians and Family Z are there purely for narrative purposes, and will serve to explain increasing or decreasing Advantage by
Police officers and Generalized destruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that none of these examples &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be a Conflict. The Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force
vs. Levinulon, or Family Z vs. the Police, or the Police vs. Civilian losses may very well
be represented as &lt;strong&gt;Overcoming Obstacles&lt;/strong&gt; if one of the sides is considered a simple obstacle
rather than an active Conflict Party. The GM gets to decide what feels more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, the US Covert Mech Operations are in Tokyo for an unrelated reason. They are going to join the Conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this make it a three-sided Conflict? Well, it depends on what the US Covert Mech Operations intend to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the US Covert Mech Operations join forces with the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force, then no. They are going to help with the initial Advantage, and they are going to have a narrative role, but for the purpose of rules, they are part of the same party as the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force. So, this remains a Conflict between two sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it is possible that the US Covert Mech Operations was in Tokyo for economic warfare purposes, and the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force has strict orders to disable their mechs and help the Police capture the US Covert Mech Operations agents, in addition to fighting Levinulon. The US Covert Mech Operations need to reach the Tokyo Stock Exchange and hack it before Levinulon destroys it, shooting down any Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force Officer that comes in the way. Meanwhile, Levinulon is quite happy to destroy everything. In this case, we have three sides in the Conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, it looks like a helicopter crew of All Nippon News Network has just arrived on the site. The objective of this helicopter crew is, of course, to gather the best possible images, which may mean putting itself in danger. A vicious GM may decide to make this helicopter crew yet another party. One of the objectives of the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force is to defend the All Nippon News Network Crew, which means preventing it from getting the best images. The US Covert Mech Operations must not leave any recorded trace, which also means destroying the helicopter crew. If so, the site has just become a four-sided Conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;establishing-advantage&#34;&gt;Establishing Advantage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each party gets to pick the Attribute they use for the Conflict, as long as it makes sense within the story. Driving Mechs to battle requires either Blades (for the violence), Serpent (for the quick reflexes) or Paper (for the strategy) – of course, you may only do so if you have an Aspect that implies that you can drive Mechs at all. Destroying Tokyo with sheer force requires either Blades (for the violence) or Stone (for the raw power). Leading Civilians to safety requires either Paper (for the strategy) or Stone (for the authority).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the numerical value of the Attribute of the party as a baseline. For each Aspect that the party has that makes sense within the Conflict, add 1. Similarly, for each Weakness that makes sense, remove 1. If the party doesn&amp;rsquo;t have its own Attributes but is composed of several characters, take as baseline the best Attribute across characters, and all the Aspects and Weaknesses that make sense, for all characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When creating NPCs or parties, it is common to write directly a specialized Attribute that may be used during such conflicts, e.g. Levinulon may have Destroy Everything at 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party with highest total starts with the Advantage. The value of the advantage is the number of ranks of difference between the highest total and the second-highest. Note that if this rank is 5 or more, the chances of the leading party winning are extremely strong, so it may not be necessary to actually have a Conflict. If no party has the highest total, the Conflict starts Balanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a Conflict with three parties or more, this may mean that a party that is comparatively much weaker than the others starts Balanced. This represents the fact that both stronger parties will be much busier fighting each other than fighting this smaller party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one of the Parties has an Advantage of &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; ranks, put as many tokens in front of the corresponding player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-kaiju-1&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us concentrate on the main event: the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force vs. Levinulon. As mentioned above, Levinulon has been defined with a specialized attribute Destroy Everything at 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force as a whole is defined with a Paper of 5, thanks to the excellent command team. On its character sheet, it also a &lt;em&gt;Well-trained team&lt;/em&gt; (+1), &lt;em&gt;The most agile mechs in the world&lt;/em&gt; (+1) and &lt;em&gt;Excellent knowledge of Tokyo&lt;/em&gt; (+1). Sadly, during the latest fight, it was determined that &lt;em&gt;The second-in-command is severely wounded&lt;/em&gt; – and is probably still in the hospital – (-1). The total is 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 8 - 7, Levinulon has a slight Advantage (1). The GM gets one token to materialize this Advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-1&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/posts/tourists-conflict-resolution/mech.png&#34; alt=&#34;Picture by Flickr User Brian Rinker – Licensed under Creative Commons Attribution Generic 2.0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s add the US Covert Mech Operations to the mix. It is a team of &lt;em&gt;Highly-trained Operatives&lt;/em&gt; (+1), with a Blades of 5. It also has &lt;em&gt;Deadly tactical weapons&lt;/em&gt; (+1), &lt;em&gt;Space-to-Ground support&lt;/em&gt; (+1), &lt;em&gt;Regenerative Alloy&lt;/em&gt; (+1). It has been established as Weakness that they also have &lt;em&gt;Limited Knowledge of Tokyo&lt;/em&gt; (-1). This gives them a total of 8, at equality with Levinulon. Consequently, in a three-sided Conflict, the Conflict starts Balanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody receives any token.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This remains true if we add the All Nippon News Network Crew, with a Serpent of 4 and &lt;em&gt;No Fear&lt;/em&gt; (+1) for a total of 5. Despite the fact that the Crew is so puny with respect of all the other parties, the rules don&amp;rsquo;t give it a specific disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that, despite the Balanced start, the All Nippon News Network Crew has no ability to actually attack Levinulon. Therefore, its goal simply cannot be to somehow beat Levinulon. Also, if the goal was to beat Levinulon, the All Nippon News Network Crew would have been considered part of the
same party as the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-reserve-for-npcs&#34;&gt;Preparing Reserve for NPCs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All player-controlled characters and parties have a Reserve of Cards, which they use to counter bad luck or make their own luck. That&amp;rsquo;s because they are, after all, main characters/parties. Antagonists typically also have a Reserve of Cards. Most antagonists are only expected to appear in a short part of the story, so they only get a smaller Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many Reserve Cards a non-player party gets is decided by the GM. A typical number is one Card per opposing faction that has a Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a non-player party gets Reserve Cards, draw them before the Conflict and put them on the party&amp;rsquo;s character sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-kaiju-2&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force has been defined, as a whole, with a single character sheet. It therefore has one Reserve, which may contain cards or be empty. Therefore, Levinulon draws one card and puts it in its Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force had been created as a set of 5 different characters with individual sheets, each characters would have one Reserve. Therefore, Levinulon would draw 5 cards into its Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-2&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to assume that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force has a single character sheet and Reserve;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the US Covert Mech Operations has a single character sheet and Reserve;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the All Nippon News Network Crew has a single character sheet and Reserve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, Levinulon draws 3 cards in its Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;resolving-the-conflict-1&#34;&gt;Resolving the Conflict&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A conflict is composed of rounds. During each round, each party has a tactics to either
grab the advantage (if the Conflict is Balanced), consolidate their advantage (if they
are the Dominant party) or weaken the advantage of the Dominant party (otherwise).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each round is composed of a succession of bids. Each bid is an opportunity for a party to
take more risks in the pursuit of their immediate tactics. Once bids are complete, parties
get to narrate what happened to their character during the round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;declaring-tactics&#34;&gt;Declaring tactics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before drawing cards, each party must describe their tactics for the round. Tactics may
change from round to round, and should always be a manner of achieving either control
of the Conflict or reaching the stated Goal of the party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tactics live purely in the fiction, rather than the rules – in other words, they have no
impact on the drawing of cards. However, they open the way to Reframing the Conflict
(see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/posts/tourists-conflict-resolution/Napoleon.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ludwig Elsholtz Napoleon I. mit seinen Generalen – Public Domain&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, tactics are only acceptable if they make sense within the fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-kaiju-3&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this two-sided Conflict:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon: &amp;ldquo;I will simply attempt to do as much damage as I can, trampling the subway if it&amp;rsquo;s close to me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force: &amp;ldquo;We move to intercept Levinulon and distract it from the crowds.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-3&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this four-sided Conflict:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon: &amp;ldquo;I will simply attempt to do as much damage as I can, trampling the subway if it&amp;rsquo;s close to me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force: &amp;ldquo;For the moment, we&amp;rsquo;re spreading around the area, attempting to find the best angle of attack.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US Covert Mech Operations: &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re pushing to maximum speed, trying to find a path to the Tokyo Stock Exchange before we can be seen on camera and before anybody or anything blocks our way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Nippon News Network Crew: &amp;ldquo;For the moment, we&amp;rsquo;re being cautious, we&amp;rsquo;re moving on top of a building, getting ready to jump into the action.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;balance-breaker-rounds&#34;&gt;Balance Breaker Rounds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance Breaker Rounds happen whenever no party has managed to grab the Advantage. Balance Breaker Rounds can cause minor Losses, but nothing more dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a balanced round, bidding proceeds as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each parties draws one card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If one of the parties has drawn the Excuse:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bidding is over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proceed to the end of the Round. The next round will be another Balance Breaker Round.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, if one of the card has drawn a card that beats all other cards

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This party now has an Advantage of 1. Give that party one token to represent this Advantage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bidding is over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proceed to the end of the round. The next round will be Unbalanced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bidding is over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proceed to the end of the Round. The next round will be another Balance Breaker Round.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-4.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-4.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-horizontal-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 4, horizontal&#34;
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This flow may be altered by taking advantage of Losses (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; discard the cards immediately. Reversed cards will be reused at the end of the Round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-4&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-19.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-19.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 19, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-9.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-9.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 9, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US Covert Mech Operations: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-79.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-79.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 79, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Nippon News Network Crew: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 21, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we see, the All Nippon News Network Crew has drawn the XVI of Triumph, which beats
all non-Triumph cards (in this case, the US Covert Mech Operations) and all Triumph
cards with lower numbers (Levinulon and Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The All Nippon News Network Crew has gained an Initiative of 1. The next round will therefore be an Unbalanced Round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three reversed cards will be collected and reused as temporary Losses below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;unbalanced-round&#34;&gt;Unbalanced Round&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a round starts Unbalanced in favor of a party (the Dominant), the objective of the Dominant
is to both use their power to drive the other parties (the Contenders) out of the game and to consolidate their advantage. Conversely, the objective of the other parties (the Contenders) is to stay in the game and decrease the advantage of the Dominant, hopefully returning it to Balance. To do this, the Dominant and the Contenders take part in a succession of &lt;em&gt;bids&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of an Unbalanced Round, if the Dominant has an advantage of &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;, the player must have &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; token in front of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bidding is the act of deciding to draw one card, then placing it in front of the player without changing its orientation. Drawing a card increases both the risk to the party and its ability to grab or consolidate advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contender parties speak first, in an arbitrary order (clockwise around the table works nicely),
each bidding or passing;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dominant may then bid or pass;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;repeats until one of the conditions below is encountered:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a party has just drawn the Excuse:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Advantage of the Dominant is decreased by 1, possibly returning the Conflict to Balanced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The player who drew the Excuse discards it, regardless of orientation, and draws another card for narrative purpose. If this card is reversed, it will be reused at the end of the Round.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proceed to the end of the Round.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, if the party has drawn 5 reversed cards during this round:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The party is Wiped Out and is now out of the Conflict.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If at least one party is still part of the Conflict and has not passed

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue bidding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proceed to the end of the Round.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, if all parties that are still in the Conflict have just passed

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If at least one Contender (including a Contender that has just been Wiped Out) has a set of cards that beats all the cards of the Dominant (each card of the Dominant needs to be beaten only by one card of the Contender)

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Advantage of the Dominant is decreased by 1, possibly returning the Conflict to Balanced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Advantage of the Dominant is increased by 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In either case, Proceed to the end of the Round.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-4.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-4.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-horizontal-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 4, horizontal&#34;
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Note that no stalemate is possible in an Unbalanced Round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This flow may be altered by Using the Advantage, or Using the other party&amp;rsquo;s Losses (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-kaiju-4&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have previously established that, in a two-sided Conflict, Levinulon has an Advantage of 1. So the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force draws first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-39.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-39.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 39, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-66.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-66.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 66, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force is currently losing, with its Paper beaten by the Blades. Consequently, it draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-79.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-79.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 79, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon is still winning as its Blades beat both the Paper and the Serpent, so it passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-19.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-19.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 19, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon is now beaten by the Triumph, so it draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-9.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-9.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 9, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

 At this stage, Levinulon could incur a Temporary Loss (see below). However, using its Advantage Token (see below), it turns the card around, into 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-9.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-9.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 9, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force is currently winning, with the highest Triumph, so it passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon draws: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-48.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-48.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 48, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

 It now has experiences at least a Temporary Loss (see below).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force is still winning, with the highest Triumph, so it passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon draws: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-13.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-13.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 13, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force is still winning, with the highest Triumph, so it passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon draws: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-76.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-76.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 76, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force is still winning, with the highest Triumph, so it passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon draws: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-12.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-12.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 12, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force is still winning, with the highest Triumph, so it passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon draws: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-70.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-70.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 70, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force is still winning, with the highest Triumph, so it passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon draws: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-15.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-15.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 15, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force is still winning, with the highest Triumph, so it passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon draws: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-11.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-11.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 11, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force is still winning, with the highest Triumph, so it passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon draws: 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 21, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

 At this stage, Levinulon has at least a Lasting Loss (see below).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force&amp;rsquo;s Triumph is now beaten by a higher Triumph. Reasoning that it has only about 10% chances of finding a Triumph higher than XVI. in the remaining cards, the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon still passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bidding is over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levinulon has increased its Advantage, but at the cost of a Lasting Loss (see below), while the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force has escaped without Loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-round-2&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger, round 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we left the four-sided Conflict, the All Nippon News Network Crew had an Advantage of 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-20.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-20.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 20, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US Covert Mech Operations team draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-40.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-40.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 40, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

, which means that it will suffer at least a Temporary Loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-14.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-14.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 14, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The All Nippon News Network Crew draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-78.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-78.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 78, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

 and uses its Advantage token to avoid a Temporary Loss (see below) by turning it to 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-78.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-78.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 78, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force has the lead and passes. If the All Nippon News Network Crew does not manage to beat this card, it will lose the Advantage in the next round.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US Covert Mech Operations team is content to let the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force take care of removing the All Nippon News Network Crew&amp;rsquo;s Advantage, and passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon similarly passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The All Nippon News Network Crew attempts to conserve the Advantage and draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-67.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-67.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 67, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force still has the lead and passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US Covert Mech Operations still passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon similarly passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The All Nippon News Network Crew continues its attempt to conserve the Advantage and draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-59.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-59.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 59, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force still has the lead and passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US Covert Mech Operations still passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon similarly passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The All Nippon News Network Crew continues its attempt to conserve the Advantage and draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-46.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-46.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 46, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force still has the lead and passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US Covert Mech Operations still passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon similarly passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The All Nippon News Network Crew continues its attempt to conserve the Advantage and draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-84.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-84.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 84, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

 With this card, the All Nippon News Network Crew now suffers from a Temporary Loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force still has the lead and passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US Covert Mech Operations still passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon similarly passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The All Nippon News Network Crew continues its attempt to conserve the Advantage and draws 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-62.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-62.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 62, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

 If The All Nippon News Network Crew draws a third reversed card, it will suffer a Lasting Loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force still has the lead and passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US Covert Mech Operations still passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon similarly passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reasoning that drawing another card would mean about 50% chances of a Lasting Loss and roughly 10% chances of beating the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force&amp;rsquo;s Triumph, the All Nippon News Network Crew stops taking risks for this round and passes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bidding is over. The All Nippon News Network has lost its Advantage of 1, meaning that the Conflict will now need a Balance Breaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-the-round&#34;&gt;Ending the Round&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All Rounds end the same way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Losses are counted;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outcomes are narrated;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a party may be victorious;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parties have an opportunity to either Concede the Conflict or reframe it;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cards that do not serve to mark Losses are shuffled back into the deck;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Reserve may be refilled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;determining-losses&#34;&gt;Determining Losses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflicts are risky. This is represented by reversed cards that accumulate,
resulting in Temporary Losses, Lasting Losses of increasing gravity, or
even Wipe Outs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, during the Round, a party has drawn&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0 reversed cards

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they have experienced no Loss;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 or 2 reversed card

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they have experienced a Temporary Loss;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;put either one of the cards on the table, on a line of cards reserved for Temporary Losses;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the party must narrate the Loss;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this Loss is Temporary – it will disappear as soon as it has been used by an adversary, or at the end of the Conflict;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 or 4 reserved cards

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they have experienced a Lasting Loss;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;put 3 of the cards on the table, on a second line of cards, reserved for Lasting Losses;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the party must narrate the Loss;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this Loss will carry over after the end of the Conflict, until it has somehow been cured;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;narratively,

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the first Loss of a party during a Conflict is something that will be very easy to cure/heal/fix – a little rest, maybe some first aid, etc. will do wonders;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the second Loss of a party during a Conflict is something that should be relatively easy to cure/heal/fix – the kind of Loss that can happen automatically between two scenarios, or by seeing a professional;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the third Loss of a party during a Conflict is something that should be difficult to cure/heal/fix – a scenario might be necessary to find a cure;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the fourth Loss of a party during a Conflict is something very hard to cure/heal/fix – an entire campaign might be necessary to find a cure;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;further Losses are permanent – they may never be cured, short of a miracle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few points to remember:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For narration purposes, use at least one of the cards that make this Loss. While this is not always possible, ideally, you should be able to weave a narrative that uses all the cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While you may narrate things that have happened to you because of other parties&amp;rsquo; actions, each player has sole narrative control upon their party. In other word, other players may overrule any description you make of their actions and successes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are the sole owner of your character&amp;rsquo;s narration, hence the only person who can describe your Losses. You get to determine whether a Loss is physical, psychological, emotional, material, etc. Just keep in mind the gravity of the Loss, as seen above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-kaiju-5&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first Round, Levinulon has drawn the following reversed cards:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-48.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-48.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 48, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 48&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-13.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-13.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 13, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 13&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 21, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 21&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s three reversed cards, so Levinulon experiences its first Lasting Loss:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon: &amp;ldquo;While stomping around Tokyo and causing general havoc, I knock out a major electricity relay and somehow electrocute myself. In a matter of seconds, the relay goes down, leaving me barely phased.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This establishes the Fact that Levinulon is (at least somewhat) vulnerable to electricity. All players will be able to weave this Fact in their narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is Levinulon&amp;rsquo;s first Lasting Loss of the conflict, it will be able to recover with only a little rest. However, a second Lasting Loss will be more consequent. There&amp;rsquo;s still hope for Tokyo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-round-1&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger, round 1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Balance Breaker, several parties drew reversed cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon drew&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-19.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-19.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 19, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 19&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force drew&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-9.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-9.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 9, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 9&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US Covert Mech Operations drew&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-79.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-79.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 79, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 79&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They all experience Temporary Losses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon: &amp;ldquo;In an attempt to go too fast, I stepped on a bridge, causing it to collapse with me on top of it. I&amp;rsquo;m so large that it&amp;rsquo;s not a problem, but it will take me a few seconds to get back on course.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force: &amp;ldquo;It took a few minutes for the communication center to reach Hazuki, so we arrived a bit late.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US Covert Mech Operations: &amp;ldquo;With the number of cameras and armed forces on scene, we risk an international incident, so our mobility is limited for the moment. Also, since Levinulon drew a card which clearly represents the Stock Exchange, if it&amp;rsquo;s ok, I&amp;rsquo;m going to assume that Levinulon is on our way and pretty close to the Stock Exchange, which makes things harder for us.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-round-2-1&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger, round 2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the second Round:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US Covert Mech Operations drew&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-40.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-40.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 40, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 40&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Nippon News Network Crew drew&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-84.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-84.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 84, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 84&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-62.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-62.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 62, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 62&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They each suffer one Temporary Loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;US Covert Mech Operations: &amp;ldquo;The police network channel that we were hacking to get traffic information has been disrupted by the destruction. We&amp;rsquo;ll have a few difficulties mapping our route.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All Nippon News Network Crew discards one of the cards, decides to interpret the Snakes card as a labyrinth: &amp;ldquo;Our pilot picked an approach route that keeps us out of the line of fire, but he needs to fly between buildings, which takes all his concentration.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;narrating-outcomes&#34;&gt;Narrating outcomes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of the Round, each party has narrated the tactics that they were going to employ during the Round. They now get to narrate what has happened, exactly, starting with whoever won the Round (if there is a winner), then whoever lost it (if there is a loser), then everybody else (if there is an everybody else).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few points to remember:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For narration purposes, use at least one of the cards that you have drawn during this Round. While this is not always possible, ideally, you should be able to weave a narrative that uses all the cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While you may narrate things that have happened to other parties because of or in reaction to your party&amp;rsquo;s tactics, each player has sole narrative control upon their party. In other word, other players may overrule any description you make of their actions and successes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whether your actions succeeded or failed is entirely up to you to decide. What the cards have determined is how the Advantage has progressed, but even whether you gained/lost, strengthened/weakened your advantage, you may well decide that all your individual actions have failed, or that they have succeeded, or that they have had unexpected results, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-kaiju-6&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you recall, the tactics were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon: &amp;ldquo;I will simply attempt to do as much damage as I can, trampling the subway if it’s close to me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force: &amp;ldquo;We move to intercept Levinulon and distract it from the crowds.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite its Lasting Loss, Levinulon has increased its Advantage, with a few cards including 

&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-15.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-15.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 15, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 15&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-70.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-70.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 70, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 70&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-12.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-12.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 12, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 12&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-76.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-76.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 76, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 76&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This not only suggests that the tactics have succeeded, but also that Levinulon has managed to destroy quite a lot of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon: &amp;ldquo;For the moment, I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying myself in this sandbox. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force has managed to grab my attention yet, and the electrical shock I have just sustained doesn&amp;rsquo;t manage to bring down my enthusiasm, so I&amp;rsquo;m happily stomping around, &lt;em&gt;Leaping like a Giant&lt;/em&gt;, leaving behind me &lt;em&gt;A very, very obvious trail&lt;/em&gt;, playing &lt;em&gt;Absolute Power&lt;/em&gt;. I assume that, in the imagination of the citizens, my &lt;em&gt;Rising to Power&lt;/em&gt; to become a very, very credible threat.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the player behind Levinulon could have decided an entirely different story, for instance fighting the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other side, the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force drew 

&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-39.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-39.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 39, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 39&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-79.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-79.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 79, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 79&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-19.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-19.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 19, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 19&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force: &amp;ldquo;Obviously, we failed to intercept Levinulon. That&amp;rsquo;s because of Levinulon&amp;rsquo;s accident with the power relay – we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get too close, either, to avoid damaging our Mechs. However, thanks to this incident, we believe that we have &lt;em&gt;Uncovered&lt;/em&gt; a weakness of Levinulon. We&amp;rsquo;re reporting this to the headquarters so that they can try and &lt;em&gt;Create&lt;/em&gt; a strategy or some gadgets to help us.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, these elements may be used in the rest of the Conflict: the weakness of Mechs to electricity, the constant communication with headquarters, the headquarters looking for a manner to use electricity against Levinulon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-round-1-1&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger, round 1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the 4-sided Balance Breaker, the parties had established the following tactics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon: &amp;ldquo;I will simply attempt to do as much damage as I can, trampling the subway if it&amp;rsquo;s close to me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force: &amp;ldquo;For the moment, we&amp;rsquo;re spreading around the area, attempting to find the best angle of attack.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US Covert Mech Operations: &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re pushing to maximum speed, trying to find a path to the Tokyo Stock Exchange before we can be seen on camera and before anybody or anything blocks our way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Nippon News Network Crew: &amp;ldquo;For the moment, we&amp;rsquo;re being cautious, we&amp;rsquo;re moving on top of a building, getting ready to jump into the action.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All Nippon News Network Crew then won the Round with&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 21, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 21&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Nippon News Network Crew: &amp;ldquo;We found a great angle with visibility on all the rampage. I don&amp;rsquo;t think we have noticed the US Covert Mech Operations yet, but we have a great footage to capture the &lt;em&gt;imagination&lt;/em&gt; of spectators. I think that we&amp;rsquo;re the only helicopter with such great footage, so we&amp;rsquo;re going to have great ratings!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levinulon lost with&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-19.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-19.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 19, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 19&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon: &amp;ldquo;I may have been a bit overeager there trying to reach the subway and stepping on that bridge. I&amp;rsquo;m wasting time getting back on course from that bridge collapse. Nothing awful, of course, I&amp;rsquo;ll be back with more mayhem in a second.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force lost with&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-9.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-9.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 9, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 9&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force: &amp;ldquo;Due to this delay, we&amp;rsquo;re arriving a bit late, but we&amp;rsquo;re now ready to step into the action.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US Covert Mech Operations team lost with&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-79.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-79.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 79, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 79&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US Covert Mech Operations: &amp;ldquo;Due to the necessity for discretion, we need to slow down.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-round-2-2&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger, round 2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the second Round, the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force won with&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-20.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-20.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 20, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 20&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force: &amp;ldquo;Let me confess something: at the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force, we don&amp;rsquo;t really like the press. Like the Police, we have to play nice with them, and show them a smiling face and cooperate, but we secretely hate these people. We have to get them out of danger right now, and if this means showing them a face that they won&amp;rsquo;t like either, that&amp;rsquo;s ok. So our commander takes the microphone and starts yelling something along the lines of &amp;lsquo;You, in the helicopter, you are in a restricted area. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t left the danger zone within five seconds, we&amp;rsquo;re going to open fire, and if you happen to be in our reticles, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up shot. This is your only warning!&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The All Nippon News Network Crew lost with&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-78.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-78.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 78, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 78&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-67.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-67.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 67, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 67&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-59.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-59.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 59, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 59&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-46.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-46.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 46, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 46&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-84.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-84.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 84, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 84&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-62.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-62.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 62, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 62&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Nippon News Network Crew: &amp;ldquo;Oh, gosh. We&amp;rsquo;re going to take this warning seriously and exercise &lt;em&gt;Caution&lt;/em&gt;. But, well, we&amp;rsquo;re the All Nippon News Network Crew, we &lt;em&gt;Make the Future Happen&lt;/em&gt; on TV or online, so we&amp;rsquo;re not giving up. Actually, that&amp;rsquo;s probably the reason for which we had to go in this labyrinth between buildings. So, we left the immediate fire zone, turned around the conflict, and we&amp;rsquo;re now hidden between these buildings, where we hope that nobody can see us, or at least shoot us down. It might also be a good angle to notice the US Covert Mech Operations, by the way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levinulon neither won nor lost with&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-14.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-14.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 14, upright&#34;
                
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 14&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon: &amp;ldquo;So, I&amp;rsquo;m back on my course of destruction. I believe that I&amp;rsquo;m actually much faster than the news crews, and they have difficulties catching up with me. Other than that, I&amp;rsquo;m merrily stomping on a school right now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US Covert Mech Operations neither won nor lost with&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-40.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-40.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 40, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 40&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US Covert Mech Operations: &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re still heading towards the Tokyo Stock Exchange. It&amp;rsquo;s tricky because of the chaos, and we have lost our traffic data, plus we still need to be discreet, but we&amp;rsquo;ll get there, eventually.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conceding-a-conflict&#34;&gt;Conceding a Conflict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being Wiped Out is not something to be taken lightly. The victor of the Conflict has complete narrative control of the situation and may decide whatever makes sense within the story – this may include killing all the party members, shaming them in front of their pears, leaving them no choice but exile, or dragging them to a convent to spend the rest of their lives in isolation, or driving them to bankrupcy&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the issue is not necessarily strictly fatal, it is clearly Very Bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason, this is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; how most Confrontations end. Rather, most parties will decide to Concede a Conflict rather than Wiped Out. Conceding is something that may happen at any end of round, provided that the party hasn&amp;rsquo;t been Wiped Out yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conceding the Conflict still means that the party has lost and that their objective now cannot be achieved anymore. It is costly. However, the players keep narrative control over their characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, in the interest of helping the story bounce back, Conceding a Conflict restores the Cards Reserve of the party that has just Conceded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; possible to return to the Conflict after having Conceded it. If this was your intention, take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;#reframing-a-conflict&#34;&gt;Reframing the Conflict&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-kaiju-later-round-wipe-out&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju, later round (Wipe Out)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s fast-forward our two-sided Conflict, to a point where the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force has suffered five consecutive reversed cards. The force is out of Reserve cards and doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any Advantage point, so there is no way to cancel this fifth reversed card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force has just been Wiped Out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The player behind Levinulon (in this case, the GM), has full control over what happens to the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force. This player may, for instance, decide that all team members are dead – and how they died. Incidentally, Levinulon has won and will destroy most of Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GM decides to keep the party alive, barely. Levinulon has no special interest in destroying the force itself, just the city. So, the mechs are destroyed, the headquarters of the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force have been trampled and destroyed in the process, killing most of the supporting NPCs and all of the infrastructure. That&amp;rsquo;s not all, as Levinulon also crushed the bunker hosting the Japanese Prime Minister, causing an unprecedented political crisis in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mech pilots somehow manage to get out of their mechs and to make their way towards an hospital outside of Tokyo. After a few days of watching the catastrophe on all TV channels and websites, they are all deeply depressed, some of them suicidal. To make things worse, the army dispatches the military police to round up the pilots and arrest them, on trumped up charges of treason, in the false hope that scapegoats and a hope of revenge will help the army keep some discipline in the country. Their story will continue with them in prison, waiting for word of their execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, being Wiped Out is that bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-later-round&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger, later round&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s now fast-forward our four-sided Conflict, to a point where the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force has suffered three Lasting Losses, two of them due to a firefight between itself and the US Covert Mech Operations team. Most of the Japanese Mechs are destroyed,
Levinulon is happily rampaging – and has the Advantage – and given their current condition, there isn&amp;rsquo;t anything that the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force can do about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The player beyind Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force decides to Concede. The combat is lost for the team, but as this is a Concession, the player can determine the terms of this loss, as long as it makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll somehow get in touch with the commander of the US Covert Mech Operations team. If necessary, I&amp;rsquo;ll use the loudspeakers. &amp;lsquo;Commander, I don&amp;rsquo;t know who you are, but I will call upon your honor. Me and my team are severely wounded, we need to withdraw immediately. Please, commander, whatever your mission is, you have won. I now beg you to spare my soldiers. And if you find it in yourself to concentrate your fire on the best that is now murdering the innocent citizens of Tokyo, please, please, do so.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since these terms require collaboration from the US Covert Mech Operations, the player may decide to reject them, in which case the
Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force player will need to come up with an alternative explanation of why the US Covert Mech Operations doesn&amp;rsquo;t manage to tear them to pieces. For instance, it is possible that a skyscraper suddenly falls on both teams, forcing them apart, and that the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force takes the opportunity to call for retreat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the player behind the US Covert Mech Operations decides to accept the conditions of the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force. The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force may limp away from the fight, hoping to eventually recover from their losses. Since there have been three Lasting Losses, getting back up to strength will require a campaign-long quest, attempting to gather political support, the technological knowledge and the rare material needed to build new and upgraded mechs, despite the loss of face just incurred, and possibly recruiting new team members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Conflict continues with only three sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite having surviving mechs, the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force may not return to the Conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;determining-victory&#34;&gt;Determining victory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only one party remains, all the other ones either have been Wiped Out or having Conceded, the last party standing is the victor, and achieves their objective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, the Conflict continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reframing-a-conflict&#34;&gt;Reframing a Conflict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many stories, a Conflict will end before being resolved, simply because the characters have changed their objectives, or their means. Perhaps a fisticuff has become a battle of wits or magic, or perhaps a poker game has ended with a character drawing their gun. Perhaps a chess player has decided to drug their opponent&amp;rsquo;s drink, threaten their family and invite pole dancers to provide a distraction and prevent them from thinking properly. Perhaps a time-traveller or a multiverse tourist has decided to abandon mundane manners to resolve a quarrel, and have decided to bring in a few dinosaurs to the car race. Perhaps two of the three cow-boys locked in a Mexican Stand-off have decided to join forces and finish their common enemy, at least until the unavoidable betrayal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps a party has found a last-minute idea to avoid being Wiped Out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of rules, all of these complete changes to the layout of the Conflict are called Reframing. Note that simply using a different tactics to achieve the same goals does not, by itself, Reframe a Conflict – that&amp;rsquo;s simply what happens naturally at every round. A Reframed Conflict must have &lt;em&gt;different goals&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;different means&lt;/em&gt;. The GM is in charge of validating whether a change in a Conflict is simply a new tactics or a full Reframing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a Conflict is Reframed, the Conflict stops immediately. Parties, goals and Advantage are re-established. Generally, this means that a party that had a high Advantage must restart with a lower Advantage, or possibly without any Advantage. If you have experienced Temporary Losses, they are discarded. If you have experienced Lasting Losses, copy them to your character sheet as Weaknesses, but discard the cards. Your next Lasting Loss will be, once again, something simple to heal/fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all of this is done, re-establish the Advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-later-round-1&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger, later round&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force has limped away from the fight, there are only three sides left, with the following objectives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon: Destroy Tokyo, including the Tokyo Stock Exchange, destroying anything that annoys it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US Covert Mech Operations: Infiltrate the Tokyo Stock Exchange, killing anything in their way, including witnesses, and outmanoeuvering Levinulon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Nippon News Network: Film everything, even if it means putting other parties in jeopardy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if the following changed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps the All Nippon News Network crew may change their objectives and decide to try and lead Levinulon away from the city. In this case, the US Covert Mech Operations will be able to get into the Tokyo Stock Exchange without trouble, hence removing them from the Conflict. This changes the parties in presence and the objectives, which means that the Conflict is Reframed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps the US Covert Mech Operations may decide to change weapons and use orbital fire support to attack Levinulon? That&amp;rsquo;s not a change in objectives, just one in tactics, so the Conflict proceeds as previously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if the US Covert Mech Operations decided that the only way to maintain anonymity was to abandon the mission and somehow call for gravity harpoons be dropped on Tokyo in the interest of fighting the monster? That is a drastic change in situation – rather than fighting its way towards the Tokyo Stock Exchange, the US Covert Mech Operations team now needs to leave Tokyo before the carpet bombing. This would also Reframe the Conflict – or perhaps change it into something altogether different from a Conflict, such as a race against the clock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if the US Covert Mech Operations and Levinulon somehow managed to communicate and reached an agreement? They would stop fighting each other, letting the US Covert Mech Operations reach its objectives and concentrate fire on witnesses and obstacles. This would also Reframe the Conflict – or, once again, perhaps change it into something altogether different.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if the US Covert Mech Operations and the All Nippon News Network somehow managed to join forces in an effort to destroy Levinulon? They would both abandon their objectives, Reframing the Conflict into a combined trap against the monster. Until, of course, the unavoidable betrayal by one side or the other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;changing-the-flow-of-the-round&#34;&gt;Changing the flow of the Round&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three ways to change the flow of a Round:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using the Advantage to minimize one&amp;rsquo;s Losses and/or maximize another party&amp;rsquo;s Losses;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using another party&amp;rsquo;s Losses to prevent them from achieving their tactics;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using Reserve cards to do either.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These three ways work both during a Balance Breaker or an Unbalanced Round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-the-advantage&#34;&gt;Using the Advantage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the Advantage means that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to take as many risks to achieve your goals. This is materialized by the ability for the party with the Advantage to &lt;em&gt;turn cards&lt;/em&gt; – to either reverse them (hence causing or increasing Losses for other parties) or un-reverse them (to avoid Losses).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an Advantage of &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; ranks, you may (un)reversing &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; cards during a Round. To remember this limit, if you have an  Advantage of &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;, you start the round with &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; Advantage Tokens (or, equivalently, one d10 set to &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;). Each time you turn one card, this costs you 1 Advantage Token. All Advantage Tokens not expended by the end of the round are lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, having many Advantage Tokens is a considerable boon. Recall that, if an adversary party has 5 cards in front of them and you can afford to spend 5 Advantage Tokens, you can simply decide that this party has been Wiped Out during the round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may only turn a card immediately after that card is drawn and placed on the table. Advantage does not work against Reserve Cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-balance-breaker&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger, Balance Breaker&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the four-sided conflict above, the All Nippon News Network Crew had drawn its first card reversed. Rather than facing an immediate Temporary Loss, it decided to use its sole Advantage Token to un-reverse the card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next round, there is no Advantage, so nobody will be able to turn a card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-kaiju-7&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the two-sided conflict above, Levinulon has used its sole Advantage Token to un-reverse its first reversed card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next Round, Levinulon has two Advantage tokens, so it will be able to do this operation twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-losses&#34;&gt;Using Losses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your Losses make your party weaker. This is materialized by the ability for adversary parties to reject cards drawn by your party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever your party experiences Losses, whether Temporary or Lasting, these Losses are represented by cards, &lt;em&gt;face visible&lt;/em&gt;, on your side of the table. A Temporary Loss is represented by 1 card, a Lasting Loss by 3 cards. As long as you have such cards, &lt;em&gt;face visible&lt;/em&gt;, when it is your turn to draw a card that another party doesn&amp;rsquo;t like, that other party may ask you to simply discard the card you have just placed. Since a Loss has been used against you, you get to turn one of the Loss cards in front of you face down, which means that it won&amp;rsquo;t be used against you again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, having many Losses makes it very hard to reach for the Advantage or to keep it. That&amp;rsquo;s in addition to the gravity of Lasting Losses, which you&amp;rsquo;ll carry over after the Conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a Temporary Loss has been turned face down, it is expended and you may discard the card. However, to keep track of Lasting Loss, you keep Lasting Losses in front of you, even after they have been turned face down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losses can only be used against you immediately after you have drawn a card. They do not affect Reserve Cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-kaiju-8&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first round of the two-sided Conflict, Levinulon has electrocuting itself, suffering a Lasting Loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Levinulon&amp;rsquo;s side of the table, the following cards are now visible&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-48.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-48.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 48, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 48&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-13.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-13.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 13, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 13&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 21, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 21&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;During the next round, Levinulon draws immediately&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-26.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-26.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 26, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the highest Triumph, which makes Levinulon pretty much unbeatable. That&amp;rsquo;s bad. Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force immediately requests a redraw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levinulon discards the card, hides one of it&amp;rsquo;s Lasting Losses cards&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-back.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-back.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number back, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number back&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-13.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-13.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 13, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 13&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 21, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 21&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;and redraws&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-5.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-5.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 5, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still a Triumph, but one that the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force has a chance of beating. The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force may decide to overrule this draw or to conserve the Losses for later use. Note that, even once these three cards are hidden, the Lasting Loss remains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-5&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the Balance Breaker Round, Levinulon, the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force and the US Covert Mech Operations have each suffered one Temporary Loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that the card drawn by the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force is hard to beat, the All Nippon News Network Crew could have decided to use the Temporary Loss of the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force to request a redraw. The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force would have then discarded both the Temporary Loss card and the Triumph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Temporary Loss is now gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-reserve-cards&#34;&gt;Using Reserve Cards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any story, there are major characters/parties and secondary ones. Major characters – including antagonists – are harder to shake away than mere extras. This is represented by parties involved in a conflict having Reserve Cards – or no Reserve Cards for secondary antagonists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A party may use their own Reserve Cards to replace a card that has just been put on the table, or turned, by any party, provided the following conditions are met:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if the party wishes to replace their own Card, they must narrate how one of their own Aspects, Weaknesses or Losses that are still on the table helps them in this circumstance;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if the party wishes to replace the Card of another party, they must narrate how one of the Aspects, Weaknesses or Losses that are still on the table of the other party hinders that party in this circumstance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, the Reserve Cards are one materialization of the Aspects, Weaknesses and Losses of all parties involved. If the conditions are met, the party may take one of their Reserve Cards and put it on top of the card that they intend to replace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reserve Cards are replenished as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;during the Conflict, whenever you win a round, you can draw a new Reserve Card immediately, as long as you do not go past the number of Reserve Cards on your character sheet;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;at the end of the Conflict, if you have Conceded, you can restore, you can draw

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;as many Reserve Card as were used against you to replace your cards during the Conflict, &lt;em&gt;even if this brings you past the number of cards indicated on your character sheet&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plus one more card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other ways to replenish Reserve Cards out of Conflict, which we won&amp;rsquo;t detail here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-kaiju-later-round&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju, later round&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force has started the Conflict with the following Reserve:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure
    class=&#34;yoric-hand &#34;&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-51.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-51.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 51, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 51&#34;
        /&gt;
    
        
        
        
        &lt;img
            src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-6.png&#34;
            data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-6.png&#34;
            data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
            
                
                
                    class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-hand-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                    alt=&#34;Card number 6, reversed&#34;
                
                
            
            alt=&#34;Card number 6&#34;
        /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force opens bidding by drawing&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-21.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-up-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 21, upright&#34;
            
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Levinulon decides that this bid is too powerful and immediately replaces this card with&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;img
        src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-51.png&#34;
        data-src=&#34;/images/space-time-deck/card-51.png&#34;
        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;
        
            
            
                class=&#34;lazyload yoric-stdeck yoric-single-card yoric-reversed-card&#34;
                alt=&#34;Card number 51, reversed&#34;
            
            
        
    /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h2 id=&#34;handling-multiple-players-or-characters-per-party&#34;&gt;Handling multiple players or characters per party&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/posts/tourists-conflict-resolution/party.png&#34; alt=&#34;Photo by Wikipedia user William Tung – Cosplay of DC Comics characters at San Diego Comic Con 2015. – Licensed under CC-BY-SA 2.0 – Source: Wikimedia Commons&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most commonly, the player&amp;rsquo;s characters will, together, be one party in the conflict. This does not change the rules above, but it does lead to interesting questions, such as: &amp;ldquo;who&amp;rsquo;s getting that permanent Loss on their character sheet?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;who&amp;rsquo;s spending one Reserve Card?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;who&amp;rsquo;s receiving one Reserve Card?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;drawing-cards&#34;&gt;Drawing Cards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules for drawing remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a Balance Breaker takes place, players should decide who draws the card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever it is the turn of the player&amp;rsquo;s party to to pass/bid, if the players collectively decide to bid, one of the players must take the responsibility of drawing the card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both cases, whoever drew the last card of the round for the party will receive the entire benefits (in terms of Reserve Cards) and pay the entire cost (in terms of Losses).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;losses&#34;&gt;Losses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules for Losses remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first Lasting Loss for the party is simple to heal/fix/recover, the second is harder, etc. even if they do not hit the same character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losses affect the ability of the entire party to work as a team, so a Card Loss experienced by one character may be used against another character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Wipe Out affects the entire party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reserve-cards&#34;&gt;Reserve Cards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any of the players may only use their own Reserve Cards. If they use a Reserve Card to cover one of their own cards, this must be narrated in relation to one of the Aspects, Weaknesses or Losses of the player&amp;rsquo;s character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the party won the round, the player who drew the last card for the party receives the bonus Reserve Card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reserve Cards used by opposing parties to cover the party&amp;rsquo;s cards are accounted for separately for each player. If you, as a player, drew the card that was covered, the Reserve Card gets, upside down, in front of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conceding-and-reframing-the-conflict&#34;&gt;Conceding and Reframing the Conflict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A character may Concede the Conflict individually. If so, the character gets one Reserve Card for Conceding, plus one for each Reserve Card used by opposing parties to cover the player&amp;rsquo;s cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the party Concedes the Conflict as a whole, this is equivalent to each character Conceding individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a single character manages to Reframe the Conflict, this affects all parties for the entire Conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;cheat-sheet&#34;&gt;Cheat Sheet&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For your first few Conflicts using these rules, you may find it easier to use this playing mat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/plotonomicon/playingmat.png&#34; alt=&#34;The N-Dimensional Tourist Playing Mat&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may see, it recapitulates all the rules we have seen and it indicates convenient
locations to place cards and tokens, to avoid confusing them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to print one for each player!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Dimensional Tourists: On your Character Sheet</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-attributes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 19:30:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-attributes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In N-Dimensional Tourists, each major character is defined by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Figure&lt;/strong&gt;, which is used during improv.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any number of &lt;strong&gt;Aspects&lt;/strong&gt;, which determine what the character can do;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 &lt;strong&gt;Attributes&lt;/strong&gt;, which determine how good a character is at their tasks;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any number of &lt;strong&gt;Specialties&lt;/strong&gt;, which let them use &lt;strong&gt;Attributes&lt;/strong&gt; in unusual manners;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least one &lt;strong&gt;Weakness&lt;/strong&gt;, which makes their life more complicated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minor non-player characters are typically described in even broader
strokes, at least until the story calls upon them to be defined in
more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and one last thing: a character isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily a human being. It can just
as well be a seven-headed alien, a religion, a mountain, a battlestation
or a conspiracy. As long as it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;major&lt;/em&gt; character, the rules are exactly
the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;Figure&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Figure&lt;/strong&gt; is just any card in the Space·Time Deck. Whenever your Figure
is drawn by any player, for any reason, whatever happened is strongly
related to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/space-time-deck&#34;&gt;Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt; is provided with a number of blank cards designed to
be customized. Do not hesitate to add your character to one of these cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aspects&#34;&gt;Aspects&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can think of an &lt;strong&gt;Aspect&lt;/strong&gt; as of something that would be written on your police record,
or any equivalent in your setting. An Aspect consists in a few words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By describing your character, Aspects enable you to do things that you would otherwise
not be able to do. For instance, a &lt;em&gt;Boy Magician&lt;/em&gt; will be both a Boy (with all
the knowledge that children have, and also forbidden from going into the girl&amp;rsquo;s
dormitories) and a Magician (with the ability to cast spells). By opposition,
a &lt;em&gt;Gender-ambiguous Knight and Plenipotentiary Emissary of His Majesty King Louis XV&lt;/em&gt;
will have a very different set of skills, equipment, knowledge, limitations
and certainly objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just by having this Aspect, the &lt;em&gt;Boy Magician&lt;/em&gt; will be able to cast spell
where the &lt;em&gt;Gender-ambiguous Knight and Plenipotentiary Emissary of His Majesty King Louis XV&lt;/em&gt; won&amp;rsquo;t. On the other hand, the latter will have the authority to speak in the name of the King, while the former will generally be ignored by adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aspects do not have to be qualities. You can be an &lt;em&gt;Ill-tempered Pirate Princess&lt;/em&gt;,
a &lt;em&gt;Lazy Ninja Student&lt;/em&gt; or a &lt;em&gt;Good-for-nothing Vampire Dandy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that Aspects are not reserved to characters. Places or Situations commonly have Aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;weaknesses&#34;&gt;Weaknesses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weaknesses&lt;/strong&gt; are special Aspects. Every character has at least one Weakness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being harmed during a Conflict, physically, socially or mentally, will give you additional Weaknesses. Whether these Weaknesses may be eventually cured depends on their gravity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could be &lt;em&gt;Physically weak&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;On the run from the Queen&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Branded with infamy&lt;/em&gt;,
or &lt;em&gt;Obsessed with Justice&lt;/em&gt;. You could have a &lt;em&gt;Broken arm&lt;/em&gt; or be a &lt;em&gt;PTSD Patient&lt;/em&gt; – either
of which might or might not heal, depending on the gravity and your setting&amp;rsquo;s ability
to deal with such trauma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;attributes&#34;&gt;Attributes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Attributes&lt;/strong&gt; are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rock&lt;/strong&gt; (stability, authority, power, physical strength);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper&lt;/strong&gt; (knowledge, deduction, riches);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blades&lt;/strong&gt; (violence, ability to effect change);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serpent&lt;/strong&gt; (speed, survival, stealth, deception);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unknown&lt;/strong&gt; (imagination, intuition, perception).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a Human Being, a Goddess of Olympus, or
a Lemming, you have the same Attributes and their
values range between 1 and 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human Beings, Gods of Olympus and Lemmings are differentiated
by their Aspects, their Specialties and their haircut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you&amp;rsquo;re attempting to &lt;strong&gt;Overcome an Obstacle&lt;/strong&gt; or to &lt;strong&gt;Resolve a Conflict&lt;/strong&gt;
in your favor, your Attributes and Aspects will determine your initial Advantage.
Higher Attributes and more Aspects that can be applied favorably in the context
mean that you&amp;rsquo;ll have higher chances of succeeding without complications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;specialties&#34;&gt;Specialties&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specialties are where the rules are customized to fit your character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each Specialty looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Because I&amp;rsquo;m a Vampire, I can perform physical attacks with my gaze, using Rock.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Because I&amp;rsquo;m a Time-Hopping Paradox Freak, I can get help temporary from my Future Self when I&amp;rsquo;m stuck, without damaging space-time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Because I&amp;rsquo;m a God, no mortal can harm me physically.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;reserve&#34;&gt;Reserve&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s face it, you are here to play major characters, not extras. The &lt;strong&gt;Reserve&lt;/strong&gt; is where you put
cards that give you this extra edge, making sure that you&amp;rsquo;re not going to disappear from the story
as easily as an extra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning characters have a Reserve of 3 Cards. This means that at the beginning of a gaming session,
they draw 3 cards from the Space·Time Deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More experienced characters may have a higher Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;now-what&#34;&gt;Now what?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all. We&amp;rsquo;ll see later how to use your Aspects, Attributes/Weaknesses, Specialties and Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Dimensional Tourists</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/n-dimensional-tourists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 19:30:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/n-dimensional-tourists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;N-Dimensional Tourists is a lightweight, generic ruleset for fiction-first, narrative roleplaying.
Instead of dice, it uses the Space·Time Deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/n-dimensional-tourists/logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;A N-Dimensional Tourist. Apparently lost.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s come back to the terms above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;lightweight&lt;/em&gt; – A character can be created in about 5 minutes. Besides character creation, there are essentially two
or three rules used during gameplay, to solve all situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;generic&lt;/em&gt; – This ruleset can be used for most universes or stories without any change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;fiction-first&lt;/em&gt; – If you have the choice between the story and the rules, the story wins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;narrative&lt;/em&gt; – Much of what happens to the world is decided by the players, rather than the GM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;the Space·Time Deck&lt;/em&gt; – A deck of card that uses some ideas from Tarot, some from Rock-Paper-Scissors-Lizard-Spock. Used for coming up with ideas, making the story progress and resolving conflicts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book concentrates on rules. &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/plotonomicon&#34;&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Plotonomicon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, its sister book, concentrates on stories. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to read both :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this ruleset is an original work, much of it is
inspired from the following Role-Playing Games:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fate Core&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Fate Accelerated&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amber Diceless&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;HeroQuest&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;HeroWars&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everway&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/space-time-deck&#34;&gt;The Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-attributes&#34;&gt;Characters and Attributes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating Player&amp;rsquo;s Characters (TBD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overcoming Obstacles (TBD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-conflict-resolution&#34;&gt;Resolving Conflicts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compelling characters (TBD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating the GM&amp;rsquo;s Characters (TBD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Character Progression (TBD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks (TBD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;appendix&#34;&gt;Appendix&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Character Sheet (TBD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/plotonomicon/playingmat.png&#34;&gt;Conflict Resolution Cheat Sheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Unknown</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-out-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 22:22:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-out-there/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Well, after the &lt;a href=&#34;../the-space-time-deck&#34;&gt;Triumphs&lt;/a&gt; and four suits (&lt;a href=&#34;../suit-paper&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-rock&#34;&gt;Rock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-blade&#34;&gt;Blade&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-serpents&#34;&gt;Serpent&lt;/a&gt;), it is time to conclude the Space·Time Deck with its last suit: the &lt;strong&gt;Suit of Unknown&lt;/strong&gt; (you are free to call it the &lt;strong&gt;Suit of Spock&lt;/strong&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unknown&lt;/strong&gt; symbolizes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;imagination;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;intuition;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perception;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;illusions;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dreams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you draw a card of this suit, you are encouraged to integrate any of these concepts
to your interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-43.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-44.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-45.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-46.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-47.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-48.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-49.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-50.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-51.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-52.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy bear&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-53.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cards&lt;/strong&gt; David Teller. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; (source: author).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out There logo&lt;/strong&gt; A resolution diagram of the game «Rock, Paper, Scissors, Lizard, Spock». Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;DMacs&lt;/code&gt;. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; Frank E. Schoonover - Cover of A Princess of Mars by Edgar Rice Burroughs, published by McClurg. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Princess_of_Mars_large.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; Photograph by Wikipedia User &lt;code&gt;Colin&lt;/code&gt; – Paisley Abbey gargoyle 10. Replacement from 1991. &amp;ldquo;Alien&amp;rdquo;. Licensed under the Creative Commons &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; license (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Paisley_Abbey_gargoyle_10.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt;  Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;Madman2001&lt;/code&gt; – A drawing of the lid of the tomb of Maya ruler Pacal the Great. Licensed under the Creative Commons &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Attribution-Share Alike 2.0 Generic&lt;/a&gt; license.
(source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Pacal_the_Great_tomb_lid.svg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; Henry Fuseli – Macbeth consulting the vision of the armed head. Oil on canvas with original inscribed frame, 1793. Licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/detail/FOLGERCM1~6~6~17235~101571:Macbeth-Consulting-the-Vision-of-th&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Folger Shakespeare Library&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; Plate found on page 7 of Marey Wollstonecraft Shelley&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein or the Modern Prometheus&lt;/em&gt;, captioned &amp;ldquo;FRANKENSTEIN AT WORK IN HIS LABORATORY.&amp;rdquo; Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Frankenstein,_pg_7.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Diego Delso – Aerial view of the &amp;ldquo;Owlman&amp;rdquo; aka &amp;ldquo;Astronaut&amp;rdquo;, the most enigmatic geoglyph of the Nazca Lines, which are located in the Nazca Desert in southern Peru.
Licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:L%C3%ADneas_de_Nazca,_Nazca,_Per%C3%BA,_2015-07-29,_DD_46.JPG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; Film poster &lt;em&gt;Plan 9 from Outer Space&lt;/em&gt;. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Plan_9_Alternative_poster.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Jean Pezzali – Crâne déformé pour des raisons esthétiques. Musée de Nasca. Licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Cr%C3%A2ned%C3%A9form%C3%A9.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; A &amp;ldquo;flat-Earth&amp;rdquo; map drawn by Orlando Ferguson in 1893. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://fr.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fichier:Orlando-Ferguson-flat-earth-map_edit.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; A good child and a bad child (wearing dunce cap with ass’s ears) in a schoolroom, from &lt;em&gt;The Affectionate Parent’s Gift&lt;/em&gt;, 1828. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Contrast_a_child_that%E2%80%99s_good_with_one_who_hates_his_book_and_school.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to jlorenzo, pnkfelix, nickwedig, Alamantus, mxfraud, GiantKumquat, Solal for their help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, Indie Rpg Planet!</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/hello-indie-rpg-planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 22:10:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/hello-indie-rpg-planet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks Alex Schroeder for putting together the &lt;a href=&#34;https://campaignwiki.org/indie/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Indie RPG Planet&lt;/a&gt;! I believe that the Indie RPG community was sorely missing something like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-52.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Serpents</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-serpents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 12:37:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-serpents/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Did you think the Space·Time Deck was done after&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href=&#34;../the-space-time-deck&#34;&gt;Triumphs&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-paper&#34;&gt;Suit of Paper&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-rock&#34;&gt;Suit of Rock&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-blade&#34;&gt;Suit of Blade&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Were it only that it were so simple!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the fourth suit: the &lt;strong&gt;Suit of Serpents&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serpents traditionally symbolize:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;speed;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stealth;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adaptation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;survival;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lies;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;forbidden knowledge;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;forbidden power;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;temptation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-77.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-78.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-79.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-80.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-81.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-82.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-83.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-84.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-85.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-86.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy bear&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-87.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cards&lt;/strong&gt; David Teller. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; (source: author).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serpent logo&lt;/strong&gt; A resolution diagram of the game «Rock, Paper, Scissors, Lizard, Spock». Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;DMacs&lt;/code&gt;. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; Merlin and Vivien in &lt;em&gt;The yellow book : an illustrated quarterly&lt;/em&gt;, 1895.
Believed to be Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/internetarchivebookimages/14787661353/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Flicker Commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt;  The samurai Hanagami Danjo no jo Arakage in Izumo stabbing a giant salamander with his short sword. Public Domain(source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Hanagami_Danjo_no_jo_Arakage_fighting_a_giant_salamander.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; Hans Canon – Der Salamander. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Hans_Canon_Der_Salamander.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; Émile Bayard – Mélusine. Illustration from &lt;em&gt;The History of Magic&lt;/em&gt;. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Melusine_(Bayard).jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; Illumination of a 15th century manuscript of Historia Regum Britanniae showing king of the Britons Vortigern and Ambros watching the fight between two dragons. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Vortigern-Dragons.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Jean-Pierre Dalbéra – Tenture de l&amp;rsquo;Apocalypse: Satan (le Dragon) remet à La Bête de la mer (à droite) le pouvoir figuré par un sceptre (détail du panneau III.40). Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Vortigern-Dragons.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; Isobel Lilian Gloag – &lt;em&gt;The Knight and the Mermaid&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Kiss of the Enchantress&lt;/em&gt;. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:The_knight_and_the_mermaid.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; Devotions to Nagadevata. Believed to be Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Brooklyn_Museum_-_Devotions_to_Nagadevata.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; Snakes &amp;amp; Ladders, Game of Heaven &amp;amp; Hell. This file is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International&lt;/a&gt; license (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Snakes_and_Ladders_(Game_of_Heaven_%26_Hell)_Wellcome_L0035004.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to jlorenzo, pnkfelix, nickwedig, Alamantus, mxfraud, GiantKumquat for their help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflict Resolution With the Space·Time Deck</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/conflict-resolution-with-the-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 17:35:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/conflict-resolution-with-the-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Most Role-Playing Games resolve conflicts with dice. But since
we have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/tags/space-time-deck&#34;&gt;Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt; at hand
(or any other kind of Tarot-like Deck), let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can
use it to bring about a different manner of resolving conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-conflicts&#34;&gt;About Conflicts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Conflict&lt;/strong&gt; is a scene in which two parties or more have
agendas, which cannot be fulfilled simultaneously. In most role-playing
games, the most common form of conflict is the combat, but that is by
no mean the only form possible: conflict could be car races, social wit,
political campaigns, chess, battlefield strategy, attempting to ruin your
opponent&amp;rsquo;s reputation or fortune, popularity contests, football matches,
etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflict does not have to be symmetrical. A guerilla may be attempting to
cause maximal damage to infrastructure while the government forces attempt
to destroy the guerilla forces. An outlying party may be attempting to
propagate its doctrine while the more traditional parties attempt to
maintain the status quo. A sniper may attempt to kill a target. A child
may be attempting to attract attention during a kidnapping attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflicts assumes that both parties have some manner of assessing their
situation, and have some ability to act. In other words, as long as the
target of the sniper is not aware of the sniper, there is no conflict &lt;em&gt;between
the sniper and the target&lt;/em&gt;. In other words, if no other factors are in play,
the act of sniping will most likely be a simple case of &lt;strong&gt;Overcoming an obstacle&lt;/strong&gt;.
On the other hand, if the target is running away, there is a – very asummetrical —
conflict between the sniper and the target. Similarly, if an enemy patrol is
currently looking for an infiltrator, there is a conflict between the sniper&amp;rsquo;s
smarts, stealth and sniping ability and the enemy patrol&amp;rsquo;s smarts and detection
ability. Similarly, if the traditional parties are busy quelling a political
crisis or are unaware of the outlying party, there is no conflict between the
outlying party and the traditional parties – although there could be a
conflict between the outlying party and a specific candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflicts decide whether any of the parties manage to reach their desired
outcome. In the case of a race, the desired outcome is typically arriving
first. In the case of a gang fight, the desired outcome is typically getting
the other gang to end up broken and bleeding or fleeing. In the case of a
sniper vs. patrol, the desired outcome is typically evading the patrol and
killing the target vs. capturing the intruder before he has the chance to
cause damage. The players representing each party must have a clear idea
of the desired outcome for the conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/illustrations/Combat Knights 6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Credits: Flickr user Paul K&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are, of course, entirely free to change the desired outcome, but this
may end up completely changing the state of the conflict. For instance, if
the hidden sniper finds themself cornered, they may decide to change plan,
create maximum chaos and attempt to escape – but that&amp;rsquo;s a new conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following conflict resolution mechanics are, by design, as minimal as
possible. They assume that the players already know how to estimate the difference
of strengths between the parties in a conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;setting-up-conflict&#34;&gt;Setting up Conflict&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the Conflict starts, the Table needs to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agree that the scene is a Conflict.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the Parties involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the Desired Outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the initial Balance of the Conflit. It may be either

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balanced&lt;/strong&gt; – while the parties may be widely different,
they have roughly the same chances of succeeding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unbalanced&lt;/strong&gt; – one party has a strong advantage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overwhelming&lt;/strong&gt; – one party is nearly certain of victory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not cover this last point – it is left up to the Table, depending
on how each Party is defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/illustrations/Bodleian_Libraries,_The_balance_of_power.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Credits: Digital Bodleian – Williams, C – The Balance of Power – Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;resolving-a-conflict&#34;&gt;Resolving a Conflict&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflict Resolution takes place in rounds. Rounds do &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; have a specific
duration. One round may last a few seconds while the next one lasts several
months - as long as it makes sense in-story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each Round starts with each party describing broadly their current tactics to
reach their Desired Outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Round will let the Table determine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;which party, if any, has advanced towards their Desired Outcome;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how it happened;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whether the Conflict continues, stops entirely or changes shape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;drawing-cards&#34;&gt;Drawing cards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the Conflict is &lt;strong&gt;Balanced&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each side picks a card of the Space·Time Deck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the Conflict is &lt;strong&gt;Unbalanced&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The advantaged side draws two cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each disadvantaged side draws one card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the Conflict is &lt;strong&gt;Overwhelming&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The advantaged side draws two cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each disadvantaged side also draws two cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once drawn, cards are visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;establishing-the-flow&#34;&gt;Establishing the flow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If any of the cards drawn is the Excuse

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Balance of Conflict moves towards &lt;strong&gt;Balanced&lt;/strong&gt;:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balanced -&amp;gt; Balanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unbalanced -&amp;gt; Balanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overwhelming -&amp;gt; Unbalanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discard the Excuse and draw another one for narration purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, if the Conflict is &lt;strong&gt;Balanced&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the card of a party beats the card of all other parties, the Balance moves in favor of the winning party

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balanced -&amp;gt; Unbalanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, the round is a stalemate, the Balance does not change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If, for &lt;em&gt;every one of the&lt;/em&gt; disadvantaged parties involved, there is one card of the advantaged side and one card of the disadvantaged side such that the the advantaged side wins, the Balance moves in favor of the side that is already advantaged

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balanced -&amp;gt; Unbalanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unbalanced -&amp;gt; Overwhelming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overwhelming -&amp;gt; Victory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If, for &lt;em&gt;every one of the&lt;/em&gt; disadvantaged party involved, all the combinations of one card of the advantaged side
and one card of the disadvantaged side imply that the advantaged side loses, the Balance moves towards &lt;strong&gt;Balanced&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unbalanced -&amp;gt; Balanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overwhelming -&amp;gt; Unbalanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, the Balance remains unchanged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/illustrations/Retaliations.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Credits: Flickr User neekoh.fi – Attribution 2.0 Generic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;narrating-the-outcome-of-the-round&#34;&gt;Narrating the outcome of the round&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage, each side knows whether their tactics have
succeeded or failed. The cards that they have drawn will
answer the Question: &lt;em&gt;How did my tactics succeed?&lt;/em&gt; or
&lt;em&gt;How did my tactics failed?&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, the player who drew the card picks the Answer
and the Facts. If the players decides to interpret the
card as meaning that reinforcements are coming, or that
a mysterious deity has blessed that quest, this is
entirely acceptable, as long as it makes sense with the
Facts that have already been established – so no deity
in a Film Noir set in our world&amp;rsquo;s 1920s, no reinforcements
if you are the last human alive. If playing with a GM,
the GM is the ultimate responsible for maintaining
consistency and Facts has the power to veto any
description if it causes a contradiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, this freedom does not extend to one side dictating
what other sides have been doing. In other words, if you
narrate that you have been dodging bullets from the Undead
Marines, the player in charge of the Undead Marines may
overrule the sentence and inform you that no, the Undead Marines were
launching grenades or were busy attempting experimenting with
vodka to see if they still could get drunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within these limitations, the player who drew the card has full
narrative authority. Again, the player is expected to interpret the
cards but only the player can decide on the actual interpretation.
This may mean that players will come up with uninteresting
interpretations from time to time. That&amp;rsquo;s ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/illustrations/640px-Ruse_with_an_Empty_City_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ruse with an Empty City&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deciding-whether-the-conflict-continues&#34;&gt;Deciding whether the Conflict continues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any side reached Victory, the Conflict is over,
congratulations, that side&amp;rsquo;s Desired Outcome has been
reached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, any side may decide to stop the Conflict.
This may represent a concession of defeat, such as
a thief escaping the scene empty-handed before being
caught. This may represent a postponed Conflict,
such as two duelling enemies being forced to hide
their weapons and bid each other farewell to avoid
the police. This may represent a party &lt;strong&gt;Reformulating
the Conflict&lt;/strong&gt;, as would be the case in a chess tournament
if one of the players decides to resort to threats
and blackmail against their opponent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the Conflict is Reformulated, the process restarts
from scratch: establish the Desired Outcomes, the
starting Balance of Conflict, then start drawing
cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very common case of Conflict Reformulation is the
fleeting alliance: wherever there are more than two
parties involved, two of the parties may decide to
temporarily join forces, with the Desired Outcome
of getting rid of a third side. Of course, two sides
who had temporarily joined forces may just as easily
break their alliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another common case is the Table deciding that the
Conflict has lasted enough and that it is now either
a stalemate or a victory. Again, if you are playing
with a GM, the GM gets final say on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RpgGeek: &lt;code&gt;SteamCraft&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;adularia25&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mawilson4&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ctimmins&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reddit: &lt;code&gt;Salindurthas&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Kaebl&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;bogglingsnog&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;matsmadison&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Scissors (or Blades)</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-scissors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 10:50:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-scissors/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After the &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-paper&#34;&gt;Suit of &lt;strong&gt;Paper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-rock&#34;&gt;Suit of &lt;strong&gt;Rock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, here comes the Suit of &lt;strong&gt;Scissor&lt;/strong&gt; (or perhaps Blades – name to be finalized).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt; Museum-level nudity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scissors/blade traditionally symbolize:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;forced change;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;violence;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;destiny;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;death.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-66.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-67.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-68.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-69.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-70.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-71.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-72.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-73.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-74.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-75.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy bear&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-76.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there
to delimit the safe-to-draw zone. Printed cards should have a little
white margin between the part you can see above and the border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cards&lt;/strong&gt; David Teller. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; (source: author).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scissors logo&lt;/strong&gt; A resolution diagram of the game «Rock, Paper, Scissors, Lizard, Spock». Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;DMacs&lt;/code&gt;. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; David Teniers the Younger - A monkey barber-surgeon&amp;rsquo;s establishment. Oil painting after. Public domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:A_monkey_barber-surgeon&#39;s_establishment._Oil_painting_after_Wellcome_V0017621.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia commons&lt;/a&gt;).
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/deed.en&lt;/a&gt;) (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; John Tenniel –  &amp;ldquo;The Jabberwocky&amp;rdquo;. An illustration to the poem Jabberwocky.
First published in Carroll, Lewis. 1871. Through the Looking-Glass, and What Alice Found There.
Public domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Jabberwocky.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; Grandville et Eugène Forest, illustrateurs. Michel Delaporte, lithographe. – Résurrection de la Censure. Public domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fichier:R%C3%A9surrection_de_la_censure.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; / Gallica).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; Ira Aldridge as Aaron in Shakespeare&amp;rsquo;s Titus Andronicus. Quote: &amp;ldquo;He dies upon my scimetar&amp;rsquo;s [sic] sharp point, / That touches this my first-born son and heir!&amp;rdquo; Act 4, sc. 2. Public domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Ira_Aldridge_as_Aaron_in_Titus_Andronicus.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia commons&lt;/a&gt; / Library of Congress).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;Fablesindia&lt;/code&gt; – A scuptor at work in Konark, Orissa, India.
Licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported license&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Sculptor_Orissa_India.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; Atelier d&amp;rsquo;Evrard d&amp;rsquo;Espinques –  Lancelot passant le pont de l&amp;rsquo;Épée, enluminure d&amp;rsquo;un manuscrit en quatre volumes réalisés pour Jacques d&amp;rsquo;Armagnac, duc de Nemours. Believed to be Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fichier:Lancelot_passant_le_pont_de_l&#39;%C3%89p%C3%A9e.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; / BnF).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; Photograph by Städel Museum – Max Liebermann – Simson und Delila. Believed to be Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:1902_Liebermann_Simson_und_Delia_anagoria.JPG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; Medieval illustration of men harvesting wheat with reaping-hooks, on a calendar page for August. Queen Mary&amp;rsquo;s Psalter (Ms. Royal 2. B. VII), fol. 78v[1]. Believed to be public domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Reeve_and_Serfs.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; First aid kit which belonged to King Edward VII. Licensed  under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:First_aid_kit_which_belonged_to_King_Edward_VII_Wellcome_M0004578.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International&lt;/a&gt; license (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:First_aid_kit_which_belonged_to_King_Edward_VII_Wellcome_M0004578.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt; / Wellcome Trust).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; No image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy Bear&lt;/strong&gt; No image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to jlorenzo, pnkfelix, nickwedig, Alamantus, mxfraud, GiantKumquat for their help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: Afterlife and the Time Adjustment Foundation</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-time-adjustment-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 17:40:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-time-adjustment-foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the Time Federation is forever limited by its Prime Directive, the militarist branches managed to get away with murder, kidnapping and torture by finessing paradoxes. Some cadres of the Time Federation wanted the ability to counter-attack, and managed to create a covert operations branch called the &lt;strong&gt;Time Adjustment Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;. And further is exactly where it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How bad have you been? How much evil did you do in your time? Are you a rapist? A serial killer? A slaver? Better even, a genocidal dictator? Fear not, Space·Time is so complicated that justice won&amp;rsquo;t be done. There are so many timelines and so many opportunities to cause Observable Contradictions that punishing you would be counter-productive. On the other hand, if you are bad enough, or at least if files and histories report you as sufficiently evil, the &lt;strong&gt;Time Adjustment Foundation&lt;/strong&gt; might well be after you and your deeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someday, while you&amp;rsquo;re looking away, things may change. The blood on your hand may be replaced with a synthetic imitation. The screams of your victims may be turned into recordings. Your victims themselves may turn out to be non-sentient recordings of their own lives. Your crimes may turn out to be simulations. Files and histories may be turned into fakes &lt;em&gt;with the exact same content&lt;/em&gt;. You, yourself, might be whisked away and replaced with a recording of your life, while you are punished, in some remote future far from contradictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all you know, you might already be innocent. But nobody will ever find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aspects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evil MUST NOT remain unundone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Victims will be much happier in Time Reservations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloaked Spaceships, armies of Replicants and life-long scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extract of &lt;a href=&#34;https://legacy.gitbook.com/book/yoric/rogue-time-bureaucrats/details&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://yoric.gitbooks.io/rogue-time-bureaucrats/content/here-there-and-right-behind-you-the-bureaucracy.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here, There and Right Behind You: The Bureaucracy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more about afterlife in Ronin Time Bureaucrats, see also &lt;a href=&#34;../rtb-afterlife&#34;&gt;the Time After Time After Time Corporation&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is part of the RPG Blog Carnival of October 2018: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ofdiceanddragons.com/character-death-resurrection-and-the-undead-october-2018-rpg-blog-carnival/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Character death, resurrection, and the undead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ofdiceanddragons.com/RPG-Carnival/RPGBlogCarnivalLogoSmall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;RPG Blog Carnival&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Rock</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After the &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-paper&#34;&gt;Suit of &lt;strong&gt;Paper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, here comes the Suit of &lt;strong&gt;Rock&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt; Museum-level nudity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rock traditionally symbolizes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stability;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reliability;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-54.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-55.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-56.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-57.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-58.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-59.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-60.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-61.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-62.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-63.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy bear&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-64.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there
to delimit the safe-to-draw zone. Printed cards should have a little
white margin between the part you can see above and the border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cards&lt;/strong&gt; David Teller. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; (source: author).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rock logo&lt;/strong&gt; A resolution diagram of the game «Rock, Paper, Scissors, Lizard, Spock». Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;DMacs&lt;/code&gt;. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; Edmonia Lewis – The Death of Cleopatra. This file is made available under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons CC0 1.0 Universal Public Domain Dedication&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Denis Bourez – Double-headed serpent, British Museum. This file is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic license&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;Sockenbaer&lt;/code&gt; - Roman-Germanic Matres and Matrones: Detail of a replica of an altar for the Mothers of Aufania (Matronae Aufaniae) from Nettersheim, Germany. This file is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; No information. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.maxpixel.net/Archer-Sculpture-Warrior-3290774&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MaxPixel&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;Wmpearl&lt;/code&gt; – The Fall of Icarus, 17th century, Musée Antoine Vivenel. Public domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; William Blake&amp;rsquo;s Newton (1795), colour print with pen &amp;amp; ink and watercolour. &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/mark/1.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Public Domain&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Newton-WilliamBlake.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; Jean-Léon Gérôme – Pygmalion and Galatea. &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/mark/1.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Public Domain&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Jean-L%C3%A9on_G%C3%A9r%C3%B4me,_Pygmalion_and_Galatea,_ca._1890.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; Bild aus Seite 016 in &amp;ldquo;Die Gartenlaube&amp;rdquo;. Image from page 016 of journal Die Gartenlaube, 1887. Public domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Die_Gartenlaube_(1887)_b_016.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; Gustave Doré – &lt;em&gt;Farinata degli Uberti addresses Dante&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Divine Comedy: The Inferno: Canto 10.&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/mark/1.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Public Domain&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Dore_woodcut_Divine_Comedy_01.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; No image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy Bear&lt;/strong&gt; No image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to jlorenzo, pnkfelix, nickwedig, Alamantus, mxfraud, GiantKumquat for their help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Paper</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 21:37:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, we introduced &lt;a href=&#34;../the-space-time-deck&#34;&gt;the Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;rsquo;s time for a second delivery: the Suit of &lt;strong&gt;Paper&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paper traditionally symbolizes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;knowledge and wisdom;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deduction;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;riches;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fragility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-32.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-33.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-34.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-35.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-36.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-37.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-38.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-39.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-40.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-41.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy bear&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-42.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there
to delimit the safe-to-draw zone. Printed cards should have a little
white margin between the part you can see above and the border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cards&lt;/strong&gt; David Teller. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; (source: author).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper logo&lt;/strong&gt; A resolution diagram of the game «Rock, Paper, Scissors, Lizard, Spock». Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;DMacs&lt;/code&gt;. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; Details of a transparent ruler with 4 scales : centimeters, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; inches. Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;Tangopaso&lt;/code&gt;. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; Scary picture prank of a big dog monster in form of an origami dragon. Author: &lt;code&gt;epSos.de&lt;/code&gt;. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; 500 Millionen Papiermark vom 1. September 1923. This image depicts a unit of currency issued by Germany. It is believed to be in the public domain (under § 5 Abs.1 UrhG) as an official work issued by a German federal or state authority, or by a predecessor state (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; Ishi-jo, wife of Oboshi Yoshio, one of the &amp;ldquo;47 loyal ronin.&amp;rdquo; Print by Kuniyoshi, from the series Seichi Gishin Den, 1848. This file is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/fr/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.0 France&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; Noah Building the Ark (Dalziels&amp;rsquo; Bible Gallery). This file is made available under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons CC0 1.0 Universal Public Domain Dedication&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; James Watt, inventor of the steam engine. Library of Contress. Public Domain (source: Picryl).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; Isaac Cruikshank – The Old Bachelor Alarmed By an Unexpected Present. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; Georges de la Tour – The Cheat with the Ace of Diamonds. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; Library of Alexandria (sepia) – This file is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International&lt;/a&gt; license (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to jlorenzo, pnkfelix, nickwedig, Alamantus, mxfraud, GiantKumquat for their help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: On the way to proof printing!</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/cards-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 10:04:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/cards-draft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;../the-space-time-deck&#34;&gt;22 Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt; are now on
their way to proof printing! We should receive the
proofs in early December. If everything is alright,
we should be able to sell them through DriveThru
by End of Year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An idea for a future Role-Playing Game: Toys of the Gods</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-toys-of-the-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 18:46:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-toys-of-the-gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are gods in this story, almighty or as near can be. This is not their story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These gods shape and make history of mankind, Earth and beyond. This is not the story of mankind, Earth or beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let it be known that the gods have children, and that some of these children will ascend to godhood, while others will stop mere heroes or monsters, and the rest will fail and fall. This is not the story of children, or heroes, or monsters, or failing and falling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let it be whispered that very few are the gods who show any kind of love for their children, that most will abandon them, and that some, in their wisdom and madness, will kill them at birth, to prevent the blood or their blood from falling in the hands of their siblings, their competitors, their pretenders. This is not the story of love, or abandon, or wisdom, or madness, or blood, or siblings, or competitors or pretenders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let it be claimed throughout the realms that these children, even those who grow up abandoned or ignored, are off-limit, and that no god, not even the most worthless one, will leave a child of theirs without a token, marking them as sacred, as beyond the reach of mortals and immortals a like. This is the story of these tokens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These is the story of these birthmarks, of these feathers abandoned in a crib, of these unbreakable capes marked with symbols from other worlds, of these necklaces and stuffed dolls and love letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is your story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For when the children are in danger, you wake up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>