<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Space·Time Will Tell on Space·Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Space·Time Will Tell on Space·Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:04:50 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A comic book tutorial for Fate Core</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/fate-rules-comic-leaflet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:04:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/fate-rules-comic-leaflet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in improv/narrative role-playing games, you may
have heard of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evilhat.com/home/fate-core/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fate Core&lt;/a&gt;, a great ruleset made by &lt;a href=&#34;http://evilhat.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Evil Hat&lt;/a&gt; exactly for
this purpose. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, it&amp;rsquo;s excellent, and it&amp;rsquo;s missing a tutorial,
so here is one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/fate/generic_rules_p0.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/fate/generic_rules_p1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, it fits in one sheet, and it&amp;rsquo;s designed to be printed
and brought with you at your table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to make it available in other languages – if you wish to help,
don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also available as a &lt;a href=&#34;../../images/fate/generic_rules.pdf&#34;&gt;high-resolution pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evilhat.com/home/fate-core/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fate Core&lt;/a&gt; is available as pay-what-you-want,
so don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to take a look at the book!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial was initially developed as part of &lt;a href=&#34;../../categories/ronin-time-bureaucrats&#34;&gt;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit for the idea of a Fate Core summary of rules goes to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uptofourplayers.com/fate-core-rules/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Up to 4 players&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: Is there an afterlife?</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/rtb-afterlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 19:24:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/rtb-afterlife/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is there an afterlife?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, of course, there is, and you came to the right place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, at &lt;strong&gt;Time After Time After Time Corporation&lt;/strong&gt;, we pride ourselves of taking care of both your Dearly Departed and of those Death-is-too-good-for-him types. While our competition will simply recreate digitized automatons to give you the illusion of interacting with the dead, we, at Time After Time After Time Corporation, we pride ourselves of having the ability to capture and upload the very SoulMind &amp;trade; of the dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you sign with Time After Time After Time Corporation, we will assemble a team of highly trained Space·Time operatives, who will be sent at the exact place and instant of death. They will install an undetectable SoulStream &amp;trade; to scan and upload the the SoulMind &amp;trade; of the dead to one of our own, patented, absolutely secure, SoulSpheres &amp;trade;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer a comprehensive choice of culturally-appropriate Heavens and Hells for most beliefs throughout the past, present and future history of mankind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time After Time After Time Corporation, where we take care of the dead, for as many eternities as it takes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(extract of &lt;a href=&#34;https://legacy.gitbook.com/book/yoric/rogue-time-bureaucrats/details&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://yoric.gitbooks.io/rogue-time-bureaucrats/content/here-there-and-right-behind-you-the-bureaucracy.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here, There and Right Behind You: The Bureaucracy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 09:30:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/post/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;« &lt;em&gt;Nobody remembers with certainty in which year the Great Snafu took place, but people generally agree that it was on a September, or perhaps on a Saturday afternoon, on some even-numbered millenium. Also, it involved blowing up the Universe, which made pretty much everybody unhappy, except for a few people who had been waiting for this opportunity to loudly exclaim&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;I told you so&amp;rdquo;&lt;em&gt;, and even they were not happy for long.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, when the Universe was rebooted&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;with a 99.999% confidence value&amp;rdquo;&lt;em&gt;, the President was barred from Time Travel indefinitely and the Agency for Preservation of Space-Time Continuity was created. Brave Agents dashing around time and space in their Continuum Indirections, fighting off mad scientists, resolving the Y2K bugs before they could overwrite the Universe, bodyguarding baby dictators and generally maintaining the status quo.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All this took place (subjective) eons ago. Nowadays, the Agency is known as the Time Bureaucracy. With (subjective) years, administrations and fashions, the Bureaucracy has reinvented itself countless times. It has been a strict-but-efficient police, as well as a dusty museum of inventions past and future. It has become a travel agency for dignitaries, as well as a time-traveling gossip source. It has been the military arm of an everlasting dictatorship, as well as an encyclopaedia of entirely verified facts. It has been a time-agnostic anarchist commune, as well as a an undercover channel used to buy future technologies without having to go through the messy process of research. It has been used as a torture chamber and as a taxation office. It has been public and secret, fashionable and forgettable, progressive and repressive, pangenicist and eugenicist and pretty much every other combination.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Throughout its existence and despite all these reinventions, the Bureaucracy has devoted and continues to devote considerable efforts to fighting the main threat towards the continued existence of the Universe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This threat is, of course, every single past, future and alternate versions of the Bureaucracy. Because, well, they are so very wrong, aren&amp;rsquo;t they?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a conflict of surprisingly little violence, made of subtle manipulations and grand gestures, of infiltrations, desertions, propaganda, and paradoxes. A Cold War more than a battlefield.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to Space·Time!&lt;/em&gt; »&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m putting together a book with all the rules and background of Ronin Time Bureaucrats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s open-source, readable &lt;a href=&#34;https://legacy.gitbook.com/book/yoric/rogue-time-bureaucrats&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on gitbook&lt;/a&gt; and the source code is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Yoric/ronin-time-bureaucrats&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll try and post updates now and then on this blog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.github.io/categories/ronin-time-bureaucrats/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://yoric.gitbooks.io/rogue-time-bureaucrats/content/cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is David Teller&amp;rsquo;s blog dedicated to role-playing games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>