<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Space·Time Will Tell on Space·Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Space·Time Will Tell on Space·Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 17:35:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Dimensional Tourists: Conflict Resolution</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-conflict-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 17:35:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-conflict-resolution/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-conflicts&#34;&gt;About Conflicts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;small-recap-of-character-attributes&#34;&gt;Small recap of character attributes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In N-Dimensional Tourists, each character is defined by:
- Any number of Traits, which determine what the character can do;
- 5 Attributes, which determine how good a character is at their tasks;
- Any number of Specialties, which match Attributes to specific tasks;
- At least one Weakness, which makes their life more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Attributes are:
- Rock (stability, authority, power, physical strength);
- Paper (knowledge, deduction, riches);
- Blades (violence, ability to effect change);
- Serpent (speed, survival, stealth);
- Unknown (imagination, intuition, perception).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attributes range between 1 and 5. Other definitions are not numbered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, heroes start each session with a Reserve of 3 cards. We will see below one way to use these cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;resolving-the-conflict&#34;&gt;Resolving the Conflict&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a Conflict, each party attempts to reach a goal, by adopting shifting
tactics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key concept during a Conflict is the Advantage, which represents how close the
Dominant party is to having complete control of the Conflict. If the Conflict is
balanced, there is no Dominant party and the Advantage is 0. Otherwise, there
is a Dominant party, and its Advantage value is a positive number. Regardless of
how many parties are involved in the Conflict, only one party may have the Advantage.
Once a party has complete control of the Conflict, none can stop it from reaching
its goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Conflict takes place as a sequence of Rounds. Each Round represents all parties
attempting to execute their tactics to either grab the Advantage, if the Conflict
is Balanced, or otherwise strengthen/weaken the Advantage. Two successive Rounds may
represent entirely different durations, depending on what makes sense in the story –
one round may very well last ten minutes and the next one ten years, without problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To grab the Advantage, strengthen their Advantage or weaken the opponent&amp;rsquo;s Advantage,
each party may need to take risks. With risks come the possibility of Losses. Depending
on the Conflict, Losses may represent wounds, engine issues, delays, lack of information,
loss of soldiers, etc. As a
party accumulates Losses, it becomes weaker, hence making it easier for other parties
to beat them. Losses may end up with a party being Wiped Out. That&amp;rsquo;s not something
you want to see happen to your party, as this represents the worst possible outcome –
possibly death, or slavery, or social infamy, or life behind bars, depending on the
Conflict. Rather, most parties leave a Conflict by Conceding it, which may represent
for instance the party surrendering, fleeing, stepping down from power, etc. depending
on the Conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking risks is represented by a bidding mechanism – each card drawn increases the party&amp;rsquo;s
chance of achieving their tactics for the round, but also the chance of being hit by
Losses. Higher Advantage gives the Dominant party the ability to draw more cards before
they start taking risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, during the Conflict, a party finds itself in a situation in which it can suddenly
gain an advantage for reasons related to the story, rather than the cards themselves,
this party may take the opportunity, hence causing the Conflict to end immediately
and resume on different terms. This is called Reframing the Conflict. This is what
happens if a discussion leads to violence, or if a fleeing driver leaves the vehicle
to enter the subway, or if a political figure caught in a scandal declares a War
on Terror to distract the public opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s now see the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;establishing-parties-and-goals&#34;&gt;Establishing parties and goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do during a Conflict is to establish the parties and the goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-kaiju&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider a Kaiju setting. This is Wednesday morning, so a giant monster is attacking Tokyo.
For some reason, everybody knows its name: Levinulon. The Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force is currently mobilizing. Tokyo&amp;rsquo;s Police is attempting to shoot at Levinulon using whatever is
at hand, but they have no chance of doing any damage. Civilians are fleeing. A gang of
criminals (&amp;ldquo;Family Z&amp;rdquo;) is taking advantage of the chaos to rob a bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the sides? Well, it depends on who is interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/posts/tourists-conflict-resolution/kaiju.png&#34; alt=&#34;Picture by Wikipedia User D J Shin – My Toy Museum – Licensed under Creative Commons Attribution ShareAlike 3.0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we are interested in Levinulon and the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force, then these are the two sides. Levinulon intends to destroy the city, while the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force intends to
save the city. The Police and civilians will certainly take damange, as well as Tokyo itself, but they have no means of altering the outcome of the Conflict. Rather, they will be used for narrative purposes, to show the progress of Levinulon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, maybe we are concentrating on the Conflict between Family Z and Police. Family Z intends
to grab the contents of the bank vaults and leave during the chaos, while the Police intends
arrest or shoot the gangsters. In this case,
the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force, Levinulon and the Civilizans will be there only for
narrative purposes, for instance to explain why the Police may end up losing Advantage
against such a low-profile gang (&amp;ldquo;all our communication channels are busy, we can&amp;rsquo;t
synchronize&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe we are concentrating on the efforts of Police officers to evacuate civilians towards safety bunkers. In this case, the parties are the Police officers and Generalized destruction.
Police officers intend to avoid Civilian losses, while Generalized destruction intends to
maximize it – of course, this only makes sense if Generalized destruction can somehow be interpreted as having a goal and tactics. This depends entirely on the kind of story you intend to tell. Here, the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force, Levinulon, the Civilians and Family Z are there purely for narrative purposes, and will serve to explain increasing or decreasing Advantage by
Police officers and Generalized destruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that none of these examples &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be a Conflict. The Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force
vs. Levinulon, or Family Z vs. the Police, or the Police vs. Civilian losses may very well
be represented as &lt;strong&gt;Overcoming Obstacles&lt;/strong&gt; if one of the sides is considered a simple obstacle
rather than an active Conflict Party. The GM gets to decide what feels more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, the US Covert Mech Operations are in Tokyo for an unrelated reason. They are going to join the Conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this make it a three-sided Conflict? Well, it depends on what the US Covert Mech Operations intend to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the US Covert Mech Operations join forces with the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force, then no. They are going to help with the initial Advantage, and they are going to have a narrative role, but for the purpose of rules, they are part of the same party as the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force. So, this remains a Conflict between two sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it is possible that the US Covert Mech Operations was in Tokyo for economic warfare purposes, and the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force has strict orders to disable their mechs and help the Police capture the US Covert Mech Operations agents, in addition to fighting Levinulon. The US Covert Mech Operations need to reach the Tokyo Stock Exchange and hack it before Levinulon destroys it, shooting down any Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force Officer that comes in the way. Meanwhile, Levinulon is quite happy to destroy everything. In this case, we have three sides in the Conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, it looks like a helicopter crew of Tokyo News has just arrived on the site. The objective of this helicopter crew is, of course, to gather the best possible images, which may mean putting itself in danger. A vicious GM may decide to make this helicopter crew yet another party. One of the objectives of the Mechanized Tokyo Defense Force is to defend the Tokyo News Crew, which means preventing it from getting the best images. The US Covert Mech Operations must not leave any recorded trace, which also means destroying the helicopter crew. If so, the site has just become a four-sided Conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;establishing-advantage&#34;&gt;Establishing advantage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each party gets to pick the Attribute they use for the Conflict, as long as it makes sense within the story. Driving Mechs to battle requires either Blades (for the violence), Serpent (for the quick reflexes) or Paper (for the strategy) – of course, you may only do so if you have an Trait that implies that you can drive Mechs at all. Destroying Tokyo with sheer force requires either Blades (for the violence) or Stone (for the raw power). Leading Civilians to safety requires either Paper (for the strategy) or Stone (for the authority).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the numerical value of the Attribute of the party as a baseline. For each Trait that the party has that makes sense within the Conflict, add 1. Similarly, for each Weakness that makes sense, remove 1. If the party doesn&amp;rsquo;t have its own Attributes but is composed of several characters, take as baseline the best Attribute across characters, and all the Traits and Weaknesses that make sense, for all characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When creating NPCs or parties, it is common to write directly a specialized Attribute that may be used during such conflicts, e.g. Levinulon may have Destroy Everything at 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party with highest total starts with the Advantage. The value of the advantage is the number of ranks of difference between the highest total and the second-highest. Note that if this rank is 5 or more, the chances of the leading party winning are extremely strong, so it may not be necessary to actually have a Conflict. If no party has the highest total, the Conflict starts Balanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a Conflict with three parties or more, this may mean that a party that is comparatively much weaker than the others starts Balanced. This represents the fact that both stronger parties will be much busier fighting each other than fighting this smaller party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-kaiju-1&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us concentrate on the main event: the Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force vs. Levinulon. As mentioned above, Levinulon has been defined with a specialized attribute Destroy Everything at 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force as a whole is defined with a Paper of 5, thanks to the excellent command team. On its character sheet, it also a &lt;em&gt;Well-trained team&lt;/em&gt; (+1), &lt;em&gt;The most agile mechs in the world&lt;/em&gt; (+1) and &lt;em&gt;Excellent knowledge of Tokyo&lt;/em&gt; (+1). Sadly, during the latest fight, it was determined that &lt;em&gt;The second-in-command is severely wounded&lt;/em&gt; – and is probably still in the hospital – (-1). The total is 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 8 - 7, Levinulon has a slight Advantage (1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-1&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/posts/tourists-conflict-resolution/mech.png&#34; alt=&#34;Picture by Flickr User Brian Rinker – Licensed under Creative Commons Attribution Generic 2.0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s add the US Covert Mech Operations to the mix. It is a team of &lt;em&gt;Highly-trained Operatives&lt;/em&gt; (+1), with a Blades of 5. It also has &lt;em&gt;Deadly tactical weapons&lt;/em&gt; (+1), &lt;em&gt;Space-to-Ground support&lt;/em&gt; (+1), &lt;em&gt;Regenerative Alloy&lt;/em&gt; (+1). It has been established as Weakness that they also have &lt;em&gt;Limited Knowledge of Tokyo&lt;/em&gt; (-1). This gives them a total of 8, at equality with Levinulon. Consequently, in a three-sided Conflict, the Conflict starts Balanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This remains true if we add the Tokyo News Crew, with a Serpent of 4 and &lt;em&gt;No Fear&lt;/em&gt; (+1) for a total of 5. Despite the fact that the Crew is so puny with respect of all the other parties, the rules don&amp;rsquo;t give it a specific disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;resolving-the-conflict-1&#34;&gt;Resolving the Conflict&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A conflict is composed of rounds. During each round, each party has a tactics to either
grab the advantage (if the Conflict is Balanced), consolidate their advantage (if they
are the Dominant party) or weaken the advantage of the Dominant party (otherwise).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each round is composed of a succession of bids. Each bid is an opportunity for a party to
take more risks in the pursuit of their immediate tactics. Once bids are complete, parties
get to narrate what happened to their character during the round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;declaring-tactics&#34;&gt;Declaring tactics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before drawing cards, each party must describe their tactics for the round. Tactics may
change from round to round, and should always be a manner of achieving either control
of the Conflict or reaching the stated Goal of the party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tactics live purely in the fiction, rather than the rules – in other words, they have no
impact on the drawing of cards. However, they open the way to Reframing the Conflict
(see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/posts/tourists-conflict-resolution/Napoleon.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ludwig Elsholtz Napoleon I. mit seinen Generalen – Public Domain&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-kaiju-2&#34;&gt;Example: Kaiju&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Levinulon: &amp;ldquo;I will simply attempt to do as much damage as I can, trampling the subway if it&amp;rsquo;s close to me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokyo Mechanized Defense Force: &amp;ldquo;We move to intercept Levinulon and distract it from the crowds.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-here-comes-a-new-challenger-2&#34;&gt;Example: Here comes a new challenger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;balanced-round&#34;&gt;Balanced round&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balanced rounds happen whenever all parties are equally matched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;unbalanced-round&#34;&gt;Unbalanced round&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a round starts Unbalanced in favor of a party (the Dominant), the objective of the Dominant
is to both use their power to drive the other parties (the Contenders) out of the game and to consolidate their advantage. Conversely, the objective of the other parties (the Contenders) is to decrease the advantage of the Dominant, hopefully returning it to Balance. To do this, the Dominant and the Contenders take part in a succession of &lt;em&gt;bids&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bidding is the act of deciding to draw one card, then placing it in front of the player without changing its orientation. Drawing a card increases both the risk to the party and its ability to grab or consolidate advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contender parties speak first, in an arbitrary order (clockwise around the table works nicely),
each bidding or passing;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dominant may then bid or pass;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this repeats until all Contenders and the Dominant have all passed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This flow may be altered by Using the Advantage, or Using the other party&amp;rsquo;s Weaknesses (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bidding ends once:
- the Excuse shows up; or
- all parties have passed; or
- all parties but one have been Taken Out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See below for interpretations of all these endings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bidding-ends&#34;&gt;Bidding ends&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the Excuse shows up, the Advantage of the Dominant is automatically decreased by 1, possibly
returning the Conflict to Balance. The player who drew the Excuse discards it and draws another
card for narrative purposes. If this card is reversed, it counts when collecting Weaknesses (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all parties have passed, the Round may either Decrease the advantage of the Dominant
or Consolidate it. The advantage Decreases if and only if at least one Contender has managed to have in front of them a set of cards that can beat all the cards of the Dominant. Otherwise, the Round Consolidates the advantage of the Dominant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all parties but one have been Taken Out, the remaining party is the victor and has complete
narrative control of the situation. As long as it makes sense within the story, this may include deciding that the other parties have been killed to the last person standing, or shamed in front of their peers, leaving no choice but sepukku, or dragged to a convent to spend the rest of their
lives, or ruined and driven to bankrupcy, &amp;hellip; It should be noted that this is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; how most Confrontations end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;benefits-of-advantage&#34;&gt;Benefits of advantage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one of the parties starts a round with an advantage of &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; ranks, it may turn &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; cards (of any side) during this round. This may be used to un-reverse their own cards, or to reverse adversary
cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning a card may only be done immediately after the card is drawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;handling-multiple-players-or-characters-per-party&#34;&gt;Handling multiple players or characters per party&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one party consists in several players or characters, they are free to decide which of
the player or character is taking part each time the party participates in a bid. The number of players, however, does not increase the number of bids by the party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weaknesses are attached to whoever character/player in the party drew last. Regardless of which character/player received the Weakness, the Weakness may be used against the entire party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;case-1-balance-breakers&#34;&gt;Case 1: Balance Breakers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A round is a Balance Breaker if no side has the advantage. In this case, each side draws one card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the Excuse shows up, the balance remains unbroken. End the round without an advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one side has a card that beats the cards of the other sides, this side takes an advantage of 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, end the round without an advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with other situations, collect upside down cards (see &lt;strong&gt;Growing weaker&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;case-2-unbalanced-situation&#34;&gt;Case 2: Unbalanced Situation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one side has an advantage of &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;, it immediately draws &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;growing-weaker&#34;&gt;Growing weaker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-weaknesses&#34;&gt;Using weaknesses&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Out There</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-out-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 22:22:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-out-there/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Well, after the &lt;a href=&#34;../the-space-time-deck&#34;&gt;Triumphs&lt;/a&gt; and four suits (&lt;a href=&#34;../suit-paper&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-rock&#34;&gt;Rock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-blade&#34;&gt;Blade&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-serpents&#34;&gt;Serpent&lt;/a&gt;), it is time to conclude the Space·Time Deck with its last suit: the &lt;strong&gt;Suit of Out There&lt;/strong&gt; (also known as &lt;strong&gt;Suit of Spock&lt;/strong&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out There symbolizes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;imagination;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;confusing dream and reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-43.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-44.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-45.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-46.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-47.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-48.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-49.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-50.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-851.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-52.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy bear&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-53.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cards&lt;/strong&gt; David Teller. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; (source: author).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out There logo&lt;/strong&gt; A resolution diagram of the game «Rock, Paper, Scissors, Lizard, Spock». Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;DMacs&lt;/code&gt;. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; Frank E. Schoonover - Cover of A Princess of Mars by Edgar Rice Burroughs, published by McClurg. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Princess_of_Mars_large.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; Photograph by Wikipedia User &lt;code&gt;Colin&lt;/code&gt; – Paisley Abbey gargoyle 10. Replacement from 1991. &amp;ldquo;Alien&amp;rdquo;. Licensed under the Creative Commons &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; license (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Paisley_Abbey_gargoyle_10.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt;  Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;Madman2001&lt;/code&gt; – A drawing of the lid of the tomb of Maya ruler Pacal the Great. Licensed under the Creative Commons &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Attribution-Share Alike 2.0 Generic&lt;/a&gt; license.
(source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Pacal_the_Great_tomb_lid.svg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; Henry Fuseli – Macbeth consulting the vision of the armed head. Oil on canvas with original inscribed frame, 1793. Licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/detail/FOLGERCM1~6~6~17235~101571:Macbeth-Consulting-the-Vision-of-th&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Folger Shakespeare Library&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; Plate found on page 7 of Marey Wollstonecraft Shelley&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein or the Modern Prometheus&lt;/em&gt;, captioned &amp;ldquo;FRANKENSTEIN AT WORK IN HIS LABORATORY.&amp;rdquo; Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Frankenstein,_pg_7.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Diego Delso – Aerial view of the &amp;ldquo;Owlman&amp;rdquo; aka &amp;ldquo;Astronaut&amp;rdquo;, the most enigmatic geoglyph of the Nazca Lines, which are located in the Nazca Desert in southern Peru.
Licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:L%C3%ADneas_de_Nazca,_Nazca,_Per%C3%BA,_2015-07-29,_DD_46.JPG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; Film poster &lt;em&gt;Plan 9 from Outer Space&lt;/em&gt;. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Plan_9_Alternative_poster.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Jean Pezzali – Crâne déformé pour des raisons esthétiques. Musée de Nasca. Licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Cr%C3%A2ned%C3%A9form%C3%A9.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; A &amp;ldquo;flat-Earth&amp;rdquo; map drawn by Orlando Ferguson in 1893. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://fr.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fichier:Orlando-Ferguson-flat-earth-map_edit.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; A good child and a bad child (wearing dunce cap with ass’s ears) in a schoolroom, from &lt;em&gt;The Affectionate Parent’s Gift&lt;/em&gt;, 1828. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Contrast_a_child_that%E2%80%99s_good_with_one_who_hates_his_book_and_school.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to jlorenzo, pnkfelix, nickwedig, Alamantus, mxfraud, GiantKumquat, Solal for their help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, Indie Rpg Planet!</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/hello-indie-rpg-planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 22:10:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/hello-indie-rpg-planet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks Alex Schroeder for putting together the &lt;a href=&#34;https://campaignwiki.org/indie/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Indie RPG Planet&lt;/a&gt;! I believe that the Indie RPG community was sorely missing something like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/card-52.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Serpents</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-serpents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 12:37:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-serpents/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Did you think the Space·Time Deck was done after&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href=&#34;../the-space-time-deck&#34;&gt;Triumphs&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-paper&#34;&gt;Suit of Paper&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-rock&#34;&gt;Suit of Rock&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-blade&#34;&gt;Suit of Blade&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Were it only that it were so simple!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the fourth suit: the &lt;strong&gt;Suit of Serpents&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serpents traditionally symbolize:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;guardians or enablers of forbidden knowledge or power;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;threats;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;survival.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-77.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-78.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-79.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-80.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-81.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-82.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-83.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-84.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-85.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-86.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy bear&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-87.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cards&lt;/strong&gt; David Teller. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; (source: author).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serpent logo&lt;/strong&gt; A resolution diagram of the game «Rock, Paper, Scissors, Lizard, Spock». Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;DMacs&lt;/code&gt;. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; Merlin and Vivien in &lt;em&gt;The yellow book : an illustrated quarterly&lt;/em&gt;, 1895.
Believed to be Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/internetarchivebookimages/14787661353/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Flicker Commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt;  The samurai Hanagami Danjo no jo Arakage in Izumo stabbing a giant salamander with his short sword. Public Domain(source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Hanagami_Danjo_no_jo_Arakage_fighting_a_giant_salamander.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; Hans Canon – Der Salamander. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Hans_Canon_Der_Salamander.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; Émile Bayard – Mélusine. Illustration from &lt;em&gt;The History of Magic&lt;/em&gt;. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Melusine_(Bayard).jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; Illumination of a 15th century manuscript of Historia Regum Britanniae showing king of the Britons Vortigern and Ambros watching the fight between two dragons. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Vortigern-Dragons.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Jean-Pierre Dalbéra – Tenture de l&amp;rsquo;Apocalypse: Satan (le Dragon) remet à La Bête de la mer (à droite) le pouvoir figuré par un sceptre (détail du panneau III.40). Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Vortigern-Dragons.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; Isobel Lilian Gloag – &lt;em&gt;The Knight and the Mermaid&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Kiss of the Enchantress&lt;/em&gt;. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:The_knight_and_the_mermaid.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; Devotions to Nagadevata. Believed to be Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Brooklyn_Museum_-_Devotions_to_Nagadevata.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; Snakes &amp;amp; Ladders, Game of Heaven &amp;amp; Hell. This file is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International&lt;/a&gt; license (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Snakes_and_Ladders_(Game_of_Heaven_%26_Hell)_Wellcome_L0035004.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to jlorenzo, pnkfelix, nickwedig, Alamantus, mxfraud, GiantKumquat for their help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflict Resolution With the Space·Time Deck</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/conflict-resolution-with-the-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 17:35:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/conflict-resolution-with-the-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Most Role-Playing Games resolve conflicts with dice. But since
we have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/tags/space-time-deck&#34;&gt;Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt; at hand
(or any other kind of Tarot-like Deck), let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can
use it to bring about a different manner of resolving conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-conflicts&#34;&gt;About Conflicts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Conflict&lt;/strong&gt; is a scene in which two parties or more have
agendas, which cannot be fulfilled simultaneously. In most role-playing
games, the most common form of conflict is the combat, but that is by
no mean the only form possible: conflict could be car races, social wit,
political campaigns, chess, battlefield strategy, attempting to ruin your
opponent&amp;rsquo;s reputation or fortune, popularity contests, football matches,
etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflict does not have to be symmetrical. A guerilla may be attempting to
cause maximal damage to infrastructure while the government forces attempt
to destroy the guerilla forces. An outlying party may be attempting to
propagate its doctrine while the more traditional parties attempt to
maintain the status quo. A sniper may attempt to kill a target. A child
may be attempting to attract attention during a kidnapping attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflicts assumes that both parties have some manner of assessing their
situation, and have some ability to act. In other words, as long as the
target of the sniper is not aware of the sniper, there is no conflict &lt;em&gt;between
the sniper and the target&lt;/em&gt;. In other words, if no other factors are in play,
the act of sniping will most likely be a simple case of &lt;strong&gt;Overcoming an obstacle&lt;/strong&gt;.
On the other hand, if the target is running away, there is a – very asummetrical —
conflict between the sniper and the target. Similarly, if an enemy patrol is
currently looking for an infiltrator, there is a conflict between the sniper&amp;rsquo;s
smarts, stealth and sniping ability and the enemy patrol&amp;rsquo;s smarts and detection
ability. Similarly, if the traditional parties are busy quelling a political
crisis or are unaware of the outlying party, there is no conflict between the
outlying party and the traditional parties – although there could be a
conflict between the outlying party and a specific candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflicts decide whether any of the parties manage to reach their desired
outcome. In the case of a race, the desired outcome is typically arriving
first. In the case of a gang fight, the desired outcome is typically getting
the other gang to end up broken and bleeding or fleeing. In the case of a
sniper vs. patrol, the desired outcome is typically evading the patrol and
killing the target vs. capturing the intruder before he has the chance to
cause damage. The players representing each party must have a clear idea
of the desired outcome for the conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/illustrations/Combat Knights 6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Credits: Flickr user Paul K&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are, of course, entirely free to change the desired outcome, but this
may end up completely changing the state of the conflict. For instance, if
the hidden sniper finds themself cornered, they may decide to change plan,
create maximum chaos and attempt to escape – but that&amp;rsquo;s a new conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following conflict resolution mechanics are, by design, as minimal as
possible. They assume that the players already know how to estimate the difference
of strengths between the parties in a conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;setting-up-conflict&#34;&gt;Setting up Conflict&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the Conflict starts, the Table needs to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agree that the scene is a Conflict.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the Parties involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the Desired Outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the initial Balance of the Conflit. It may be either

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balanced&lt;/strong&gt; – while the parties may be widely different,
they have roughly the same chances of succeeding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unbalanced&lt;/strong&gt; – one party has a strong advantage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overwhelming&lt;/strong&gt; – one party is nearly certain of victory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not cover this last point – it is left up to the Table, depending
on how each Party is defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/illustrations/Bodleian_Libraries,_The_balance_of_power.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Credits: Digital Bodleian – Williams, C – The Balance of Power – Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;resolving-a-conflict&#34;&gt;Resolving a Conflict&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflict Resolution takes place in rounds. Rounds do &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; have a specific
duration. One round may last a few seconds while the next one lasts several
months - as long as it makes sense in-story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each Round starts with each party describing broadly their current tactics to
reach their Desired Outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Round will let the Table determine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;which party, if any, has advanced towards their Desired Outcome;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how it happened;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whether the Conflict continues, stops entirely or changes shape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;drawing-cards&#34;&gt;Drawing cards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the Conflict is &lt;strong&gt;Balanced&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each side picks a card of the Space·Time Deck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the Conflict is &lt;strong&gt;Unbalanced&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The advantaged side draws two cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each disadvantaged side draws one card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the Conflict is &lt;strong&gt;Overwhelming&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The advantaged side draws two cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each disadvantaged side also draws two cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once drawn, cards are visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;establishing-the-flow&#34;&gt;Establishing the flow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If any of the cards drawn is the Excuse

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Balance of Conflict moves towards &lt;strong&gt;Balanced&lt;/strong&gt;:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balanced -&amp;gt; Balanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unbalanced -&amp;gt; Balanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overwhelming -&amp;gt; Unbalanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discard the Excuse and draw another one for narration purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, if the Conflict is &lt;strong&gt;Balanced&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the card of a party beats the card of all other parties, the Balance moves in favor of the winning party

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balanced -&amp;gt; Unbalanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, the round is a stalemate, the Balance does not change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If, for &lt;em&gt;every one of the&lt;/em&gt; disadvantaged parties involved, there is one card of the advantaged side and one card of the disadvantaged side such that the the advantaged side wins, the Balance moves in favor of the side that is already advantaged

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balanced -&amp;gt; Unbalanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unbalanced -&amp;gt; Overwhelming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overwhelming -&amp;gt; Victory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If, for &lt;em&gt;every one of the&lt;/em&gt; disadvantaged party involved, all the combinations of one card of the advantaged side
and one card of the disadvantaged side imply that the advantaged side loses, the Balance moves towards &lt;strong&gt;Balanced&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unbalanced -&amp;gt; Balanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overwhelming -&amp;gt; Unbalanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, the Balance remains unchanged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/illustrations/Retaliations.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Credits: Flickr User neekoh.fi – Attribution 2.0 Generic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;narrating-the-outcome-of-the-round&#34;&gt;Narrating the outcome of the round&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage, each side knows whether their tactics have
succeeded or failed. The cards that they have drawn will
answer the Question: &lt;em&gt;How did my tactics succeed?&lt;/em&gt; or
&lt;em&gt;How did my tactics failed?&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, the player who drew the card picks the Answer
and the Facts. If the players decides to interpret the
card as meaning that reinforcements are coming, or that
a mysterious deity has blessed that quest, this is
entirely acceptable, as long as it makes sense with the
Facts that have already been established – so no deity
in a Film Noir set in our world&amp;rsquo;s 1920s, no reinforcements
if you are the last human alive. If playing with a GM,
the GM is the ultimate responsible for maintaining
consistency and Facts has the power to veto any
description if it causes a contradiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, this freedom does not extend to one side dictating
what other sides have been doing. In other words, if you
narrate that you have been dodging bullets from the Undead
Marines, the player in charge of the Undead Marines may
overrule the sentence and inform you that no, the Undead Marines were
launching grenades or were busy attempting experimenting with
vodka to see if they still could get drunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within these limitations, the player who drew the card has full
narrative authority. Again, the player is expected to interpret the
cards but only the player can decide on the actual interpretation.
This may mean that players will come up with uninteresting
interpretations from time to time. That&amp;rsquo;s ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/illustrations/640px-Ruse_with_an_Empty_City_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ruse with an Empty City&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deciding-whether-the-conflict-continues&#34;&gt;Deciding whether the Conflict continues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any side reached Victory, the Conflict is over,
congratulations, that side&amp;rsquo;s Desired Outcome has been
reached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, any side may decide to stop the Conflict.
This may represent a concession of defeat, such as
a thief escaping the scene empty-handed before being
caught. This may represent a postponed Conflict,
such as two duelling enemies being forced to hide
their weapons and bid each other farewell to avoid
the police. This may represent a party &lt;strong&gt;Reformulating
the Conflict&lt;/strong&gt;, as would be the case in a chess tournament
if one of the players decides to resort to threats
and blackmail against their opponent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the Conflict is Reformulated, the process restarts
from scratch: establish the Desired Outcomes, the
starting Balance of Conflict, then start drawing
cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very common case of Conflict Reformulation is the
fleeting alliance: wherever there are more than two
parties involved, two of the parties may decide to
temporarily join forces, with the Desired Outcome
of getting rid of a third side. Of course, two sides
who had temporarily joined forces may just as easily
break their alliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another common case is the Table deciding that the
Conflict has lasted enough and that it is now either
a stalemate or a victory. Again, if you are playing
with a GM, the GM gets final say on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RpgGeek: &lt;code&gt;SteamCraft&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;adularia25&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mawilson4&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ctimmins&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reddit: &lt;code&gt;Salindurthas&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Kaebl&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;bogglingsnog&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;matsmadison&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Scissors (or Blades)</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-scissors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 10:50:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-scissors/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After the &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-paper&#34;&gt;Suit of &lt;strong&gt;Paper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-rock&#34;&gt;Suit of &lt;strong&gt;Rock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, here comes the Suit of &lt;strong&gt;Scissor&lt;/strong&gt; (or perhaps Blades – name to be finalized).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt; Museum-level nudity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scissors/blade traditionally symbolize:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;change;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;violence;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unavoidability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-66.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-67.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-68.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-69.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-70.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-71.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-72.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-73.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-74.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-75.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy bear&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-76.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there
to delimit the safe-to-draw zone. Printed cards should have a little
white margin between the part you can see above and the border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cards&lt;/strong&gt; David Teller. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; (source: author).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scissors logo&lt;/strong&gt; A resolution diagram of the game «Rock, Paper, Scissors, Lizard, Spock». Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;DMacs&lt;/code&gt;. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; David Teniers the Younger - A monkey barber-surgeon&amp;rsquo;s establishment. Oil painting after. Public domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:A_monkey_barber-surgeon&#39;s_establishment._Oil_painting_after_Wellcome_V0017621.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia commons&lt;/a&gt;).
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/deed.en&lt;/a&gt;) (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; John Tenniel –  &amp;ldquo;The Jabberwocky&amp;rdquo;. An illustration to the poem Jabberwocky.
First published in Carroll, Lewis. 1871. Through the Looking-Glass, and What Alice Found There.
Public domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Jabberwocky.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; Grandville et Eugène Forest, illustrateurs. Michel Delaporte, lithographe. – Résurrection de la Censure. Public domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fichier:R%C3%A9surrection_de_la_censure.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; / Gallica).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; Ira Aldridge as Aaron in Shakespeare&amp;rsquo;s Titus Andronicus. Quote: &amp;ldquo;He dies upon my scimetar&amp;rsquo;s [sic] sharp point, / That touches this my first-born son and heir!&amp;rdquo; Act 4, sc. 2. Public domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Ira_Aldridge_as_Aaron_in_Titus_Andronicus.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia commons&lt;/a&gt; / Library of Congress).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;Fablesindia&lt;/code&gt; – A scuptor at work in Konark, Orissa, India.
Licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported license&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Sculptor_Orissa_India.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia commons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; Atelier d&amp;rsquo;Evrard d&amp;rsquo;Espinques –  Lancelot passant le pont de l&amp;rsquo;Épée, enluminure d&amp;rsquo;un manuscrit en quatre volumes réalisés pour Jacques d&amp;rsquo;Armagnac, duc de Nemours. Believed to be Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fichier:Lancelot_passant_le_pont_de_l&#39;%C3%89p%C3%A9e.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; / BnF).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; Photograph by Städel Museum – Max Liebermann – Simson und Delila. Believed to be Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:1902_Liebermann_Simson_und_Delia_anagoria.JPG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; Medieval illustration of men harvesting wheat with reaping-hooks, on a calendar page for August. Queen Mary&amp;rsquo;s Psalter (Ms. Royal 2. B. VII), fol. 78v[1]. Believed to be public domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Reeve_and_Serfs.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; First aid kit which belonged to King Edward VII. Licensed  under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:First_aid_kit_which_belonged_to_King_Edward_VII_Wellcome_M0004578.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International&lt;/a&gt; license (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:First_aid_kit_which_belonged_to_King_Edward_VII_Wellcome_M0004578.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt; / Wellcome Trust).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; No image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy Bear&lt;/strong&gt; No image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to jlorenzo, pnkfelix, nickwedig, Alamantus, mxfraud, GiantKumquat for their help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: Afterlife and the Time Adjustment Foundation</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-time-adjustment-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 17:40:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-time-adjustment-foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the Time Federation is forever limited by its Prime Directive, the militarist branches managed to get away with murder, kidnapping and torture by finessing paradoxes. Some cadres of the Time Federation wanted the ability to counter-attack, and managed to create a covert operations branch called the &lt;strong&gt;Time Adjustment Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;. And further is exactly where it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How bad have you been? How much evil did you do in your time? Are you a rapist? A serial killer? A slaver? Better even, a genocidal dictator? Fear not, Space·Time is so complicated that justice won&amp;rsquo;t be done. There are so many timelines and so many opportunities to cause Observable Contradictions that punishing you would be counter-productive. On the other hand, if you are bad enough, or at least if files and histories report you as sufficiently evil, the &lt;strong&gt;Time Adjustment Foundation&lt;/strong&gt; might well be after you and your deeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someday, while you&amp;rsquo;re looking away, things may change. The blood on your hand may be replaced with a synthetic imitation. The screams of your victims may be turned into recordings. Your victims themselves may turn out to be non-sentient recordings of their own lives. Your crimes may turn out to be simulations. Files and histories may be turned into fakes &lt;em&gt;with the exact same content&lt;/em&gt;. You, yourself, might be whisked away and replaced with a recording of your life, while you are punished, in some remote future far from contradictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all you know, you might already be innocent. But nobody will ever find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aspects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evil MUST NOT remain unundone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Victims will be much happier in Time Reservations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloaked Spaceships, armies of Replicants and life-long scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extract of &lt;a href=&#34;https://legacy.gitbook.com/book/yoric/rogue-time-bureaucrats/details&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://yoric.gitbooks.io/rogue-time-bureaucrats/content/here-there-and-right-behind-you-the-bureaucracy.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here, There and Right Behind You: The Bureaucracy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more about afterlife in Ronin Time Bureaucrats, see also &lt;a href=&#34;../rtb-afterlife&#34;&gt;the Time After Time After Time Corporation&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is part of the RPG Blog Carnival of October 2018: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ofdiceanddragons.com/character-death-resurrection-and-the-undead-october-2018-rpg-blog-carnival/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Character death, resurrection, and the undead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ofdiceanddragons.com/RPG-Carnival/RPGBlogCarnivalLogoSmall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;RPG Blog Carnival&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Rock</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After the &lt;a href=&#34;../suit-paper&#34;&gt;Suit of &lt;strong&gt;Paper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, here comes the Suit of &lt;strong&gt;Rock&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt; Museum-level nudity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rock traditionally symbolizes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stability;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reliability;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-55.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-56.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-57.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-58.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-59.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-60.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-61.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-62.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-63.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-64.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy bear&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-65.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there
to delimit the safe-to-draw zone. Printed cards should have a little
white margin between the part you can see above and the border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cards&lt;/strong&gt; David Teller. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; (source: author).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rock logo&lt;/strong&gt; A resolution diagram of the game «Rock, Paper, Scissors, Lizard, Spock». Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;DMacs&lt;/code&gt;. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; Edmonia Lewis – The Death of Cleopatra. This file is made available under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons CC0 1.0 Universal Public Domain Dedication&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Denis Bourez – Double-headed serpent, British Museum. This file is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic license&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;Sockenbaer&lt;/code&gt; - Roman-Germanic Matres and Matrones: Detail of a replica of an altar for the Mothers of Aufania (Matronae Aufaniae) from Nettersheim, Germany. This file is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; No information. Public Domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.maxpixel.net/Archer-Sculpture-Warrior-3290774&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MaxPixel&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; Photo by Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;Wmpearl&lt;/code&gt; – The Fall of Icarus, 17th century, Musée Antoine Vivenel. Public domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; William Blake&amp;rsquo;s Newton (1795), colour print with pen &amp;amp; ink and watercolour. &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/mark/1.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Public Domain&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Newton-WilliamBlake.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; Jean-Léon Gérôme – Pygmalion and Galatea. &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/mark/1.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Public Domain&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Jean-L%C3%A9on_G%C3%A9r%C3%B4me,_Pygmalion_and_Galatea,_ca._1890.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; Bild aus Seite 016 in &amp;ldquo;Die Gartenlaube&amp;rdquo;. Image from page 016 of journal Die Gartenlaube, 1887. Public domain (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Die_Gartenlaube_(1887)_b_016.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; Gustave Doré – &lt;em&gt;Farinata degli Uberti addresses Dante&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Divine Comedy: The Inferno: Canto 10.&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/mark/1.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Public Domain&lt;/a&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Dore_woodcut_Divine_Comedy_01.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; No image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy Bear&lt;/strong&gt; No image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to jlorenzo, pnkfelix, nickwedig, Alamantus, mxfraud, GiantKumquat for their help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Paper</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 21:37:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, we introduced &lt;a href=&#34;../the-space-time-deck&#34;&gt;the Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;rsquo;s time for a second delivery: the Suit of &lt;strong&gt;Paper&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paper traditionally symbolizes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;knowledge and wisdom;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;riches;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fragility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-32.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-33.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-34.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-35.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-36.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-37.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-38.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-39.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-40.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foot&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-41.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teddy bear&lt;/strong&gt; (blank, customizable) &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/space-time-deck/card-42.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there
to delimit the safe-to-draw zone. Printed cards should have a little
white margin between the part you can see above and the border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cards&lt;/strong&gt; David Teller. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; (source: author).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper logo&lt;/strong&gt; A resolution diagram of the game «Rock, Paper, Scissors, Lizard, Spock». Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;DMacs&lt;/code&gt;. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruler&lt;/strong&gt; Details of a transparent ruler with 4 scales : centimeters, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; inches. Wikipedia user &lt;code&gt;Tangopaso&lt;/code&gt;. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; Scary picture prank of a big dog monster in form of an origami dragon. Author: &lt;code&gt;epSos.de&lt;/code&gt;. Available under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure&lt;/strong&gt; 500 Millionen Papiermark vom 1. September 1923. This image depicts a unit of currency issued by Germany. It is believed to be in the public domain (under § 5 Abs.1 UrhG) as an official work issued by a German federal or state authority, or by a predecessor state (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; Ishi-jo, wife of Oboshi Yoshio, one of the &amp;ldquo;47 loyal ronin.&amp;rdquo; Print by Kuniyoshi, from the series Seichi Gishin Den, 1848. This file is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/fr/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.0 France&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt; Noah Building the Ark (Dalziels&amp;rsquo; Bible Gallery). This file is made available under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons CC0 1.0 Universal Public Domain Dedication&lt;/a&gt; (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeker&lt;/strong&gt; James Watt, inventor of the steam engine. Library of Contress. Public Domain (source: Picryl).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lover&lt;/strong&gt; Isaac Cruikshank – The Old Bachelor Alarmed By an Unexpected Present. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servant&lt;/strong&gt; Georges de la Tour – The Cheat with the Ace of Diamonds. Public Domain (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt; Library of Alexandria (sepia) – This file is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International&lt;/a&gt; license (source: Wikipedia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to jlorenzo, pnkfelix, nickwedig, Alamantus, mxfraud, GiantKumquat for their help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: On the way to proof printing!</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/cards-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 10:04:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/cards-draft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;../the-space-time-deck&#34;&gt;22 Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt; are now on
their way to proof printing! We should receive the
proofs in early December. If everything is alright,
we should be able to sell them through DriveThru
by End of Year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An idea for a future Role-Playing Game: Toys of the Gods</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-toys-of-the-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 18:46:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-toys-of-the-gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are gods in this story, almighty or as near can be. This is not their story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These gods shape and make history of mankind, Earth and beyond. This is not the story of mankind, Earth or beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let it be known that the gods have children, and that some of these children will ascend to godhood, while others will stop mere heroes or monsters, and the rest will fail and fall. This is not the story of children, or heroes, or monsters, or failing and falling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let it be whispered that very few are the gods who show any kind of love for their children, that most will abandon them, and that some, in their wisdom and madness, will kill them at birth, to prevent the blood or their blood from falling in the hands of their siblings, their competitors, their pretenders. This is not the story of love, or abandon, or wisdom, or madness, or blood, or siblings, or competitors or pretenders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let it be claimed throughout the realms that these children, even those who grow up abandoned or ignored, are off-limit, and that no god, not even the most worthless one, will leave a child of theirs without a token, marking them as sacred, as beyond the reach of mortals and immortals a like. This is the story of these tokens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These is the story of these birthmarks, of these feathers abandoned in a crib, of these unbreakable capes marked with symbols from other worlds, of these necklaces and stuffed dolls and love letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is your story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For when the children are in danger, you wake up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Idea for a future Role-Playing Game: Wandering Spirits</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-wandering-spirits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 14:00:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-wandering-spirits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a possible idea for a setting. It owns to &lt;em&gt;Hurlements&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Nephilim&lt;/em&gt;,
&lt;em&gt;Highlander&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Continuum&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is set on our Earth, past, present and future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The heroes are immortal, Wandering Spirits. They have existed on Earth
since before Mankind, and will still be there after Mankind. In a way,
they are gods: free to roam at will, to experience it all, without fear
of consequences. In another way, they are but prisoners, condemned to
live and relive the history of the world, either as passive observers,
or as mere humans, borrowed for a day or a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is a way out – a different one for each campaign, one which
is decided during campaign setup by the players and the GM. Perhaps
mankind needs to find its way to harmony, or perhaps it needs to reach
the stars before it kills itself. Or perhaps mankind needs to willingly
fade into oblivion, or perhaps it needs to raise a Messiah, or to
commit self-genocide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each story starts with each Wandering Spirit borrowing a human body,
at a given point in time and space. They have something to do in that
period. They have access to both the memories of the Wandering Spirit
and that of the human, but only the physical skills and resources
of the latter. They have picked this point in time and space, because
they can change the world, veering it towards its way out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But something in their past is tracking them. Something, or someone,
is ready for their arrival, and has taken steps to crush their hopes,
whatever they are. And of course, there is that nagging feeling that
the something in question might be the Wandering Spirits themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvising with the Space·Time Deck: V. Hello, you gorgeous!</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/deck-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 12:05:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/deck-5/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is an extract from &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/plotonomicon&#34;&gt;the Plotonomicon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that we have just changed the picture from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/space-time-deck/old-card-6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old picture (The Slaughter of the Innocents) one was considered too
violent – while both are museum pieces,
the first one depicts mass murder of children, and was thus discarded
as not-safe-for-children&amp;rsquo;s-hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new version gets rid of almost all violence, and offers much more
symbolism, hence much more freedom of improv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;interpretations&#34;&gt;Interpretations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Default interpretations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The futility of running away from Destiny?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The burden of knowledge?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This picture depicts &lt;strong&gt;Oedipus&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Sphinx of Thebes&lt;/strong&gt; facing – or
perhaps embracing – each other. In Greek Mythology, Oedipus is the
son of Queen Jocasta and King Laius of Thebes. Before Oedipus&amp;rsquo;
birth, it was prophecized that he would murder his father
and marry his own mother. To avoid the fulfilling of this
prophecy, Oedipus&amp;rsquo; parents had him wounded at birth
and abandoned to die in the wilderness. Of course, Oedipus
survived and was adopted by loving parents – the Queen and
King of Corinth. When, as a young adult, Oedipus eventually learnt of the
prophecy, not knowing that he had been adopted, he fled his
home to, once again, forestall the prophecy.
Oedipus ended up meeting and killing King Laius, his real
father, defeating the Sphinx of Thebes, and, as savior of
Thebes, marrying the recently widowed Queen Jocasta. This
unknowingly incestuous marriage cursed the city of Thebes,
but it is only years later that Queen Jocasta and King Oedipus
realized, after a series of coincidences and revelations, that
they were mother and son. In shame, Jocasta killed herself,
and Oedipus blinded himself, walking the roads as a blind
beggar. Just to make sure that this story couldn&amp;rsquo;t have any
kind of happy ending, their children continued the curse -
life was hard in Ancient Greek Myths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the Sphinx, she was a guardian of sorts, who choked
and ate whoever could not answer her riddles, until she
met a man who could, at which point she killed herself.
In a later version of the story, she actually gave Oedipus
the answer to the riddle, because that was her only way out
this role of evil monster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-image&#34;&gt;The image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fight between a hero and a monster, or a dance
    of seduction, or two arrogant figures, or a woman, more forward
    than what society expects, and a younger man, surprised.
    Also, a desolate landscape, the only entrance to a mysterious
    city. Also, a guardian of secrets, willing to shed her charge.
    Also, a blundering teenager, surprised by a question or a
    secret whispered and about to be trapped into power.
    Also, the clinging hand of a victim not fully dead yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-burden-of-knowledge&#34;&gt;The burden of knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information, but an information that
    comes with a cost. Maybe the cost is upfront and visible, and the
    heroes will have to meet it to get the information. More
    likely, this information comes with a responsibility that
    the characters should not have wanted, perhaps in the
    form of a choice to make, or a long-ignored debt to own.
    Perhaps it is time for a character to learn of a bastard they
    have sired, or a child thought dead, or a lover or a friend
    or a mentor in hardship. Perhaps it is time for the heroes
    to make a choice where no option is acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-futility-of-running-away-from-destiny&#34;&gt;The futility of running away from Destiny&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If something was
    hunting down the heroes, or perhaps their antagonists,
    that something has arrived, or at
    least a good reason to believe that it cannot be escaped.
    Perhaps a countdown had started for some doomsday clock?
    Doomsday has arrived while the characters were looking
    away. Maybe a prophecy was under way, or a paradox? In
    either case, it is time to tie the knot. Or maybe it is
    something less scary that cannot be escaped anymore,
    something like love, or a conversation that needs to
    happen now, even in the middle of a dungeon. Or maybe
    it is time for a character to realize their role in the
    story and perhaps even to accept it – a hero may be
    born, or a villain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-going-beyond-the-enemy-lines&#34;&gt;Example: Going beyond the enemy lines&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;World War 2 in Europe. The sarge and his men have been tasked
with a secret mission. They have spent two days half-lost
beyond the enemy lines, and have finally just reached the hill
behind Château Maniais. They only have a few hours before
the Obersturmführer escapes towards Berlin. The sarge looks
at the Château from his goggles. &lt;em&gt;What does he see?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Either side:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entire surroundings of Château Maniais have been turned
into fortifications. Sandbags and barbwires everywhere,
guard towards and machine guns. The only path leads towards
the entrance and it is covered by Panzers. It&amp;rsquo;s going to
be a tough job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The landscape is desolate, but only one of the windows is alight.
At the window, two shapes seem to be dancing. One of them is
uniformed, clearly the Obersturmführer. The other one is a womanm,
probably his mistress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The burden of knowledge:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Obersturmführer&amp;rsquo;s retinue is getting ready to leave, that much
is obvious – they are currently cleaning house. Which, among
other things, means that they are taking a bunch of civilians – women,
all of them – to the trench behind the castle, to be executed.
The heroes have a chance to save them, if they act now, but
this might come at the cost of the mission. Or the sarge can
decide to stay mute, to spare the rest of the team from the
responsibility of letting these innocents be murdered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Obersturmführer is getting ready to leave alright, and he&amp;rsquo;s not
leaving empty-handed. The sarge witnesses two trucks being loaded
with paintings, gold bars, jewels. Now, some squad members could
decide to go for the gold after – or instead of – their mission.
This could be desertion. Or the sarge might decide not to tell them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The futility of running away from Destiny:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sarge takes one second to focus, then drops the goggles.
The Obersturmführer is right here, not twenty paces from the squad,
relieving himself in front of a tree, or perhaps smoking
a cigarette. Destiny has come for him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was only a matter of time before the squad was spotted.
Well, while the sarge was spotting, a sentry noticed something
in the bushes. A patrol is dispatched to the squad&amp;rsquo;s position,
right now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-the-shifting-maze&#34;&gt;Example: The shifting maze&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of random strangers has awakened in a deadly shifting maze,
in which they must band together to survive. Or not. &lt;em&gt;Why were they
put in the labyrinth?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Either side:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a social experiment, pure and simple.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a rite of passage. If they manage to make it through, well,
some secret will be revealed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The burden of knowledge:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the strangers knows more than he lets on. He&amp;rsquo;s somehow
responsible for everybody being here, perhaps because he built
the maze, or perhaps because he&amp;rsquo;s the target, and everybody else
was just caught with him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The maze is an interrogation device. This is not the first time
the strangers awake in the maze. They have died already, and died
again, and been cloned or resurrected. Each time, the maze rearranges
itself, trying to get the strangers to talk and share. This will
continue until one of the strangers finally reveals their secret.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The futility or running away from Destiny:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everybody is sent to the maze, at least once on their lifetime.
They don&amp;rsquo;t remember, because if they survive, their memory is erased.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All these strangers are actually dead. This is some form of purgatory or hell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-what-does-the-alchemist-want&#34;&gt;Example: What does the Alchemist want?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The heroes need the expertise of an alchemist to identify the Stone
of Power that they managed to trick away from the Lord of Wind Castle.
As it turns out, there is only one alchemist of renoun in the region,
and she serves in the Temple of the All-seeing. &lt;em&gt;What does she want?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Either side:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Alchemist is busy dealing with arcane knowledge. Maybe, if the
heroes somehow find a way to help her in her investigation, she
might make a little time to look at their babble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Alchemist is in the middle of a lover&amp;rsquo;s quarel. Her companion,
the professional hero, wants her tame and housebroken. She will have
none of that, and she has enough arrogance to match that of her
hero. For the moment, neither of the lover is willing to listen
to the heroes, but there may be a way to try and get them to
one-upman each other through piercing the enigma of the Stone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The burden of knowledge:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Alchemist is old, perhaps dying. She knows so many things,
and has nobody to pass that knowledge. At this stage, the Alchemist
wants – needs – an apprentice more than anything in this world.
Everything else is secondary, including answering the questions
of annoying heroes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oh, that Alchemist? You mean, your mom? Well, I&amp;rsquo;m sure she&amp;rsquo;d like
to hear about your latest adventures. Also, any grandchildren yet?
No? Well, it just happens so that she knows someone your age,
someone you should absolutely meet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The futility of running away from Destiny:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Stone of Power was created by the Alchemist, dozens of years
ago. When she found out what the Stone could do, she did her
best to destroy it or hide it. After all these years, the Stone
is returning to its creator. The Alchemist only wants one thing:
she wants to be far away from the Stone of Power!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Lord of Wind Castle is the former lover of the Alchemist.
When they broke up, he stole the Stone. The Alchemist wants
only one thing: the Stone itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Ronin Time Bureaucrats</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/ronin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:19:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/ronin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re currently working on a Role-Playing Game called &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/tags/ronin-time-bureaucrats&#34;&gt;Ronin Time Bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect brains-over-brawn, improv and handwavy time paradoxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/ronin/Agency.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the latest draft (mostly complete, unformatted) &lt;a href=&#34;https://yoric.gitbooks.io/rogue-time-bureaucrats/content/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;.
Even in this unfinished form, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to leave feedbak!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plotonomicon</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/plotonomicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:18:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/plotonomicon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oops, the heroes have ruined the story, again. They managed to get Camelot invaded by the peaceful Seelie while King Arthur was at war, to kill teenage Karl Marx while vacationing in Space·Time or to blow up the Magical University where the entire campaign was meant to take place. Also, they have just entered the Unknowable Dungeon of Unspeakable Death, for which you have no maps, or they are due to meet the Ambassador of the Qfew&amp;rsquo;dhi Confederation, the one you just invented by pushing random keys on your keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to switch to improv mode!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How will King Arthur Pendragon react to news of the invasion?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How will history readjust itself without Karl Marx?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How will the Unseen Council protect the Mundane Sphere without the Sevenfold Anchor?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What evil lurks in the Unknowable Dungeon of Unspeakable Death?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does a Qfew&amp;rsquo;dhi even look like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog knows! The Space·Time Deck knows!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(well, or at least, they can help you improvise an answer)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/plotonomicon/cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a Game Master, a Player, a Writer, or any kind of Storyteller, this book and its companion Space·Time Deck
are designed for you. Because you may need to improvise characters on the fly, to explore dungeons without maps,
to spice up fights and altercations and pursuits and confrontations of all sorts, to come up with exotic planets,
unheard of magical creatures, threats past and future, not to mention stories, stories-within-stories and
ultimate plot twists, all of this without breaking pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, we are here for you. We bring you improv and storytelling tricks and techniques,
examples, and a tarot-like deck of cards designed to help you keep your stories varied,
interesting and fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the latest draft (incomplete and unformatted) &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Space-TimeWillTell/Channeling-Keyser-Soze/blob/master/SUMMARY.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;,
and we&amp;rsquo;re posting extracts &lt;a href=&#34;http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/tags/plotonomicon&#34;&gt;on this blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in this unfinished form, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to leave feedbak!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>