<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rpg on Space-Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/tags/rpg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rpg on Space-Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 10:50:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/tags/rpg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Scissors (or Blades)</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-scissors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 10:50:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-scissors/</guid>
      <description>After the Suit of Paper and the Suit of Rock, here comes the Suit of Scissor (or perhaps Blades – name to be finalized).
Warning Museum-level nudity.
Scissors/blade traditionally symbolize:
 change; violence; unavoidability.  The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: Afterlife and the Time Adjustment Foundation</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-time-adjustment-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 17:40:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-time-adjustment-foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the Time Federation is forever limited by its Prime Directive, the militarist branches managed to get away with murder, kidnapping and torture by finessing paradoxes. Some cadres of the Time Federation wanted the ability to counter-attack, and managed to create a covert operations branch called the &lt;strong&gt;Time Adjustment Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;. And further is exactly where it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Rock</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</guid>
      <description>After the Suit of Paper, here comes the Suit of Rock.
Warning Museum-level nudity.
Rock traditionally symbolizes:
 stability; reliability; power.  The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there to delimit the safe-to-draw zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Paper</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 21:37:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, we introduced the Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck. It&amp;rsquo;s time for a second delivery: the Suit of Paper.
Paper traditionally symbolizes:
 knowledge and wisdom; riches; fragility.  The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: On the way to proof printing!</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/cards-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 10:04:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/cards-draft/</guid>
      <description>The 22 Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck are now on their way to proof printing! We should receive the proofs in early December. If everything is alright, we should be able to sell them through DriveThru by End of Year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An idea for a future Role-Playing Game: Toys of the Gods</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-toys-of-the-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 18:46:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-toys-of-the-gods/</guid>
      <description>There are gods in this story, almighty or as near can be. This is not their story.
These gods shape and make history of mankind, Earth and beyond. This is not the story of mankind, Earth or beyond.
Let it be known that the gods have children, and that some of these children will ascend to godhood, while others will stop mere heroes or monsters, and the rest will fail and fall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Idea for a future Role-Playing Game: Wandering Spirits</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-wandering-spirits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 14:00:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-wandering-spirits/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a possible idea for a setting. It owns to Hurlements, Nephilim, Highlander, Continuum.
The story is set on our Earth, past, present and future.
The heroes are immortal, Wandering Spirits. They have existed on Earth since before Mankind, and will still be there after Mankind. In a way, they are gods: free to roam at will, to experience it all, without fear of consequences. In another way, they are but prisoners, condemned to live and relive the history of the world, either as passive observers, or as mere humans, borrowed for a day or a lifetime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvising with the Space·Time Deck: V. Hello, you gorgeous!</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/deck-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 12:05:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/deck-5/</guid>
      <description>This is an extract from the Plotonomicon.
Note that we have just changed the picture from
The old picture (The Slaughter of the Innocents) one was considered too violent – while both are museum pieces, the first one depicts mass murder of children, and was thus discarded as not-safe-for-children&amp;rsquo;s-hands.
This new version gets rid of almost all violence, and offers much more symbolism, hence much more freedom of improv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Ronin Time Bureaucrats</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/ronin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:19:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/ronin/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re currently working on a Role-Playing Game called Ronin Time Bureaucrats.
Expect brains-over-brawn, improv and handwavy time paradoxes.
You can find the latest draft (mostly complete, unformatted) online. Even in this unfinished form, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to leave feedbak!
Stay tuned for more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: The Plotonomicon</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/plotonomicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:18:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/plotonomicon/</guid>
      <description>Oops, the heroes have ruined the story, again. They managed to get Camelot invaded by the peaceful Seelie while King Arthur was at war, to kill teenage Karl Marx while vacationing in Space·Time or to blow up the Magical University where the entire campaign was meant to take place. Also, they have just entered the Unknowable Dungeon of Unspeakable Death, for which you have no maps, or they are due to meet the Ambassador of the Qfew&amp;rsquo;dhi Confederation, the one you just invented by pushing random keys on your keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re on DriveThruRPG!</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/now-on-drivethru/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:09:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/now-on-drivethru/</guid>
      <description>After a few weeks spent composing, recomposing and polishing our Fate comic book tutorial, it&amp;rsquo;s now available on DriveThruRPG for pay-as-you-want, starting at $0.
As previously, the license allows you to share, reproduce and modify, provided you maintain credits, so feel free to bring it to your playing table.
We&amp;rsquo;re working on making it available print-on-demand.
Thanks to all the fine folks on Reddit communities /u/RPGdesign and /u/FATErpg for the feedback, and thanks to Evil Hat for making such a great game!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improv(is)ing stories with cards</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/why-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 19:01:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/why-cards/</guid>
      <description>Earlier, we have posted the Space·Time Deck.
It&amp;rsquo;s a set of cards, designed to help with improv.
But why cards?
In theory, an improv Storyteller should be able to use anything as support for improvisation. That&amp;rsquo;s true whether they&amp;rsquo;re performing for an audience, or improvising a plot for an ongoing Role-Playing Game, or improvising their character as a RPG player, or writing a book.
Do you know the ideal improviser? His name is Keyser Söze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Space·Time Deck</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 17:43:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>The Space·Time Deck is a card deck designed to be used as an improv tool, both for storytelling and role-playing games.
 The Excuse.  I.  II.  III.  IV.  V.  VI.  VII.  VIII.  IX.  X.  XI.  XII.  XIII.  XIV.  XV.  XVI.  XVII.  XVIII.  XIX.  XX.  XXI.  Back.  Blank 1  Blank 2  Blank 3  Blank 4  Blank 5  Cheatsheet Front  Cheatsheet Back   More about this deck in future posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comic book tutorial for Fate Core</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/fate-rules-comic-leaflet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:04:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/fate-rules-comic-leaflet/</guid>
      <description>If you are interested in improv/narrative role-playing games, you may have heard of Fate Core, a great ruleset made by Evil Hat exactly for this purpose. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, it&amp;rsquo;s excellent, and it&amp;rsquo;s missing a tutorial, so here is one:
As you can see, it fits in one sheet, and it&amp;rsquo;s designed to be printed and brought with you at your table.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to make it available in other languages – if you wish to help, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: Is there an afterlife?</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-afterlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 19:24:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-afterlife/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is there an afterlife?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, of course, there is, and you came to the right place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 09:30:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</guid>
      <description>« Nobody remembers with certainty in which year the Great Snafu took place, but people generally agree that it was on a September, or perhaps on a Saturday afternoon, on some even-numbered millenium. Also, it involved blowing up the Universe, which made pretty much everybody unhappy, except for a few people who had been waiting for this opportunity to loudly exclaim &amp;ldquo;I told you so&amp;rdquo;, and even they were not happy for long.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>