<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Plotonomicon on Space-Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/categories/plotonomicon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Plotonomicon on Space-Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:04:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/categories/plotonomicon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Rock Suit</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</guid>
      <description>After the Paper Suit, here comes the Rock Suit.
Warning Some nudity.
Rock traditionally symbolizes: - stability; - reliability; - power.
The cards: - Ruler - Dragon - Treasure - Soldier - Builder - Seeker - Lover - Servant - Home - Foot (blank, customizable) - Teddy bear (blank, customizable) Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there to delimit the safe-to-draw zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Paper Suit</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 21:37:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, we introduced the Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck. It&amp;rsquo;s time for a second delivery: the Paper Suit.
Paper traditionally symbolizes: - knowledge and wisdom; - riches; - fragility.
The cards: - Ruler - Dragon - Treasure - Soldier - Builder - Seeker - Lover - Servant - Home - Foot (blank, customizable) - Teddy bear (blank, customizable) Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvising with the Space·Time Deck: V. Hello, you gorgeous!</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/deck-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 12:05:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/deck-5/</guid>
      <description>This is an extract from the Plotonomicon.
Note that we have just changed the picture from
The old picture (The Slaughter of the Innocents) one was considered too violent – while both are museum pieces, the first one depicts mass murder of children, and was thus discarded as not-safe-for-children&amp;rsquo;s-hands.
This new version gets rid of almost all violence, and offers much more symbolism, hence much more freedom of improv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: The Plotonomicon</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/plotonomicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:18:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/plotonomicon/</guid>
      <description>Oops, the heroes have ruined the story, again. They managed to get Camelot invaded by the peaceful Seelie while King Arthur was at war, to kill teenage Karl Marx while vacationing in Space·Time or to blow up the Magical University where the entire campaign was meant to take place. Also, they have just entered the Unknowable Dungeon of Unspeakable Death, for which you have no maps, or they are due to meet the Ambassador of the Qfew&amp;rsquo;dhi Confederation, the one you just invented by pushing random keys on your keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Space·Time Deck</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 17:43:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>The Space·Time Deck is a card deck designed to be used as an improv tool, both for storytelling and role-playing games.
 The Excuse.  I.  II.  III.  IV.  V.  VI.  VII.  VIII.  IX.  X.  XI.  XII.  XIII.  XIV.  XV.  XVI.  XVII.  XVIII.  XIX.  XX.  XXI.  Back.  Blank 1  Blank 2  Blank 3  Blank 4  Blank 5  Cheatsheet Front  Cheatsheet Back   More about this deck in future posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>