<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Space-time-deck on Space-Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/tags/space-time-deck/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Space-time-deck on Space-Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 10:50:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/tags/space-time-deck/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Scissors Suit</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-scissors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 10:50:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-scissors/</guid>
      <description>After the Paper Suit and the Rock Suit, here comes the Scissor Suit.
Warning Museum-level nudity.
Scissors traditionally symbolize:
 change; violence; unavoidability.  The cards: - Ruler - Dragon - Treasure - Soldier - Builder - Seeker - Lover - Servant - Home - Foot (blank, customizable) - Teddy bear (blank, customizable) Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there to delimit the safe-to-draw zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Rock Suit</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</guid>
      <description>After the Paper Suit, here comes the Rock Suit.
Warning Some nudity.
Rock traditionally symbolizes: - stability; - reliability; - power.
The cards: - Ruler - Dragon - Treasure - Soldier - Builder - Seeker - Lover - Servant - Home - Foot (blank, customizable) - Teddy bear (blank, customizable) Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there to delimit the safe-to-draw zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Paper Suit</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 21:37:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, we introduced the Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck. It&amp;rsquo;s time for a second delivery: the Paper Suit.
Paper traditionally symbolizes: - knowledge and wisdom; - riches; - fragility.
The cards: - Ruler - Dragon - Treasure - Soldier - Builder - Seeker - Lover - Servant - Home - Foot (blank, customizable) - Teddy bear (blank, customizable) Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: On the way to proof printing!</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/cards-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 10:04:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/cards-draft/</guid>
      <description>The 22 Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck are now on their way to proof printing! We should receive the proofs in early December. If everything is alright, we should be able to sell them through DriveThru by End of Year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improv(is)ing stories with cards</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/why-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 19:01:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/why-cards/</guid>
      <description>Earlier, we have posted the Space·Time Deck.
It&amp;rsquo;s a set of cards, designed to help with improv.
But why cards?
In theory, an improv Storyteller should be able to use anything as support for improvisation. That&amp;rsquo;s true whether they&amp;rsquo;re performing for an audience, or improvising a plot for an ongoing Role-Playing Game, or improvising their character as a RPG player, or writing a book.
Do you know the ideal improviser? His name is Keyser Söze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Space·Time Deck</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 17:43:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>The Space·Time Deck is a card deck designed to be used as an improv tool, both for storytelling and role-playing games.
 The Excuse.  I.  II.  III.  IV.  V.  VI.  VII.  VIII.  IX.  X.  XI.  XII.  XIII.  XIV.  XV.  XVI.  XVII.  XVIII.  XIX.  XX.  XXI.  Back.  Blank 1  Blank 2  Blank 3  Blank 4  Blank 5  Cheatsheet Front  Cheatsheet Back   More about this deck in future posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>