<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Perfect Reality on Space·Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/tags/perfect-reality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Perfect Reality on Space·Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 21:06:21 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/tags/perfect-reality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Perfect Reality (Working Title)</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-divine-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 21:06:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-divine-reality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This world still looks very much like our own. Governments, companies, global warming, Internet of Things, online porn, spam, spyware everywhere. The web itself has evolved into immersive Augmented Reality-like experiences backed by both glasses, holograms and pseudo-solid fields dubbed Perfect Reality. Telling the real from the virtual slowly becomes impossible. Tele-commuting has&#xA;replaced many workplaces and massive automation has killed many jobs but due to peak energy and the cost of sophisticated AI mean that people still need to work and you&amp;rsquo;ll still find a few humans at your local restaurant, clinic or childcare center. Perfect Reality has shaped a society of distributed yet insular communities with entirely distinct lifestyles, which interact each other mostly through a global LARP/strategy hybrid game called &lt;em&gt;The Alterlight&lt;/em&gt;. Democracy and capitalism still exists in many countries, but once a government or a large company have picked objectives, they delegate most of their strategy to AI experts. Medicine has continued improving and a few dozen types of muscular, nervous or encephalic brain implants have become affordable [FIXME: Is this cyberware? Wetware? Nanotech? Something else entirely?]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
