<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Enemies on Space·Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/tags/enemies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Enemies on Space·Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 16:33:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/tags/enemies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: The Most Benevolent Administrators</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-most-benevolent-administrators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 16:33:50 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-most-benevolent-administrators/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Most Benevolent Administrators&lt;/strong&gt; are believed to be leftovers of a dead branch of the &lt;strong&gt;Time Bureaucracy&lt;/strong&gt;. They may be found scattered around time and space. While they look quite harmless – who would fear something that appears essentially to be photocopier on wheel tracks – the sheets of paper that they print sometimes make them very dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most Benevolent Administrators are generally Poets and Philosophers, able of deep reflections on the nature of the human psyche, among others. They are also extremely perceptive and their writings are eloquent as very few human beings can be. Surprisingly, they often use these skills, combined, for the perceived benefits of others. Wherever a Most Benevolent Administrator shows up – which may be pretty much anywhere in Space·Time – expect that within a few months, people will be inventing Social Security and Universities and Parliaments, building Cathedrals, Towers of Babel and Starships and Utopias. Sadly, very few civilizations can survive such a level of ascension, and the rule of a Most Benevolent Administrator most often ends with bloody revolutions, invasions, cataclysms or self-immolation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
