<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Space-time-deck on Space·Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/categories/space-time-deck/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Space-time-deck on Space·Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 17:50:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/categories/space-time-deck/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Dimensional Tourists: Conflict Resolution</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-conflict-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 17:50:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-conflict-resolution/</guid>
      <description>About these rules These rules are part of the N-Dimensional Tourists ruleset.
Specifically, this entry describes a mechanism to resolve Conflicts between two parties or more during a role-playing game.
This mechanism is designed to be abstract and generic – it works just as well with a pirate crew boarding a merchan ship as with two Formula 1 pilots racing each other or three political parties attempting to win or steal the elections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Out There</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-out-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 22:22:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-out-there/</guid>
      <description>Well, after the Triumphs and four suits (Paper, Rock, Blade, Serpent), it is time to conclude the Space·Time Deck with its last suit: the Suit of Out There (also known as Suit of Spock)!
Out There symbolizes:
 imagination; dream confusing dream and reality.  The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Credits  Cards David Teller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Serpents</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-serpents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 12:37:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-serpents/</guid>
      <description>Did you think the Space·Time Deck was done after
 the Triumphs; the Suit of Paper; the Suit of Rock; the Suit of Blade?  Were it only that it were so simple!
Here&amp;rsquo;s the fourth suit: the Suit of Serpents.
Serpents traditionally symbolize:
 guardians or enablers of forbidden knowledge or power; threats; survival.  The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Credits  Cards David Teller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflict Resolution With the Space·Time Deck</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/conflict-resolution-with-the-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 17:35:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/conflict-resolution-with-the-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>Most Role-Playing Games resolve conflicts with dice. But since we have a Space·Time Deck at hand (or any other kind of Tarot-like Deck), let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can use it to bring about a different manner of resolving conflicts.
About Conflicts A Conflict is a scene in which two parties or more have agendas, which cannot be fulfilled simultaneously. In most role-playing games, the most common form of conflict is the combat, but that is by no mean the only form possible: conflict could be car races, social wit, political campaigns, chess, battlefield strategy, attempting to ruin your opponent&amp;rsquo;s reputation or fortune, popularity contests, football matches, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Scissors (or Blades)</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-scissors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 10:50:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-scissors/</guid>
      <description>After the Suit of Paper and the Suit of Rock, here comes the Suit of Scissor (or perhaps Blades – name to be finalized).
Warning Museum-level nudity.
Scissors/blade traditionally symbolize:
 change; violence; unavoidability.  The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Rock</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</guid>
      <description>After the Suit of Paper, here comes the Suit of Rock.
Warning Museum-level nudity.
Rock traditionally symbolizes:
 stability; reliability; power.  The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there to delimit the safe-to-draw zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Paper</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 21:37:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, we introduced the Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck. It&amp;rsquo;s time for a second delivery: the Suit of Paper.
Paper traditionally symbolizes:
 knowledge and wisdom; riches; fragility.  The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvising with the Space·Time Deck: V. Hello, you gorgeous!</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/deck-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 12:05:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/deck-5/</guid>
      <description>This is an extract from the Plotonomicon.
Note that we have just changed the picture from
The old picture (The Slaughter of the Innocents) one was considered too violent – while both are museum pieces, the first one depicts mass murder of children, and was thus discarded as not-safe-for-children&amp;rsquo;s-hands.
This new version gets rid of almost all violence, and offers much more symbolism, hence much more freedom of improv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Space·Time Deck</title>
      <link>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 17:43:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>The Space·Time Deck is a card deck designed to be used as an improv tool, both for storytelling and role-playing games.
 The Excuse.  I.  II.  III.  IV.  V.  VI.  VII.  VIII.  IX.  X.  XI.  XII.  XIII.  XIV.  XV.  XVI.  XVII.  XVIII.  XIX.  XX.  XXI.  Back.  Blank 1  Blank 2  Blank 3  Blank 4  Blank 5  Cheatsheet Front  Cheatsheet Back   More about this deck in future posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>