<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rpg on Space·Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/categories/rpg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rpg on Space·Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 16:33:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/categories/rpg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: The Most Benevolent Administrators</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-most-benevolent-administrators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 16:33:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-most-benevolent-administrators/</guid>
      <description>The Most Benevolent Administrators are believed to be leftovers of a dead branch of the Time Bureaucracy. They may be found scattered around time and space. While they look quite harmless – who would fear something that appears essentially to be photocopier on wheel tracks – the sheets of paper that they print sometimes make them very dangerous.
Most Benevolent Administrators are generally Poets and Philosophers, able of deep reflections on the nature of the human psyche, among others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Dimensional Tourists: In two sheets</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourist-comic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 11:31:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourist-comic/</guid>
      <description>This is a two-sheets comic-book tutorial for N-Dimensional Tourists. Leave it lying on your tables and use it to create worlds, characters, plot twists and more!
Download the high-resolution pdf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plotonomicon: In One Sheet</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-comic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 10:26:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-comic/</guid>
      <description>This is a one-sheet comic-book tutorial for the Plotonomicon. Leave it lying on your tables and use it to create worlds, characters, plot twists and more!
Download the high-resolution pdf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plotonomicon: Creating Worlds</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-creating-worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 20:10:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-creating-worlds/</guid>
      <description>In the Plotonomicon, creating a world is, much like creating a character, a series of Questions. Where creating a player&amp;rsquo;s character is generally a dialogue between the GM and that player, creating a world is one that involves everybody around the table.
Before starting, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to decide how much detail you want to put in your world – there&amp;rsquo;s no limit to how much time you can spend creating a world, if you enjoy doing so, but maybe you want to use that world immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Dimensional Tourists: Stronger Together</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 13:48:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-parties/</guid>
      <description>Together, we&amp;rsquo;re stronger. Well-prepared, we&amp;rsquo;re stronger. Well-fed, well-rested, well-equipped, well-informed, well-trained, that&amp;rsquo;s even better. Well, whenever you group be together, or ensure that you&amp;rsquo;re well-prepared, well-fed, well-rested, well-equipped, well-informed, well-trained or pretty much anything else, you are Creating an Advantage.
As most things in N-Dimensional Tourists, Advantages are basically Aspects and may represent just about anything that makes sense in-story. It could be a strong character providing the team with Muscle during a streetfight, or a Hand-up for climbing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Dimensional Tourists: Aspects and your Sleeve</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-the-sleeve/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 12:09:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-the-sleeve/</guid>
      <description>While we have met Aspects a few times in this manual, so far, we have mostly contented ourselves with writing them down. Some are on your character sheet, some have been used to describe NPCs, or consequences of actions. In this chapter, we will discuss further what Aspects are and how they maybe used, both for the benefit of your character and against them.
Aspects in Narration Aspect are Facts First and foremost, Aspects are Facts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role-Playing Game Pitch: Kingdom Came</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-kingdom-came/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 11:56:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-kingdom-came/</guid>
      <description>Rejoice, for the Kingdom of Death is no more.
It was first reported Last Thursday, at 0421 GMT and it happened all over the globe: the dead have returned to walk among the living. They are disoriented, surely, and returned from Heaven or Hell or other places, but they are peaceful, for the most part.
What most of them are no more is human. For all the dead have returned, all since the first step of our kind, or possibly before, and few of them have a body to return to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotonomicon: Let&#39;s not prepare anything</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-the-art-of-not-preparing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 13:29:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-the-art-of-not-preparing/</guid>
      <description>All good things start with stories. It&amp;rsquo;s not just a buzzphrase, by the way. If you are building a story, whether you are role-playing, storytelling for an audience or writing a book, the story comes first and everything else tends to follow naturally.
So let us start with, once again, a story.
Hope renewed Our story is set in a fantasy archipelago inhabited by dozens of sentient species, and loosely inspired from Ancient Greece, with larger ships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Dimensional Tourists: Meeting Challenges</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-overcoming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 19:19:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-overcoming/</guid>
      <description>So your character needs to find a key, lost somewhere in the mess left by the previous owner, or perhaps to pick the lock. Or maybe that piano needs to be moved into the living room, or you need to find a way through an opaque bureaucratic process, or to look innocent in front of a judge, or intimidating in front of a lowly thug. Or perhaps you&amp;rsquo;re fishing in a river or piloting your starship or settling a duel with another Musketeer before the Guards of the Cardinal show up?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plotonomicon: A Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 23:26:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>You know what? Let&amp;rsquo;s keep explanations for later. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with some action!
Imagine cars racing in the streets of Rio de Janeiro. It&amp;rsquo;s the present. Two of the heroes (let&amp;rsquo;s call them Desmond and Erika) share a sportscar, driving as fast as they can away from the HQ of Evil Corporation, where they just stole a USB stick. Our third hero (Frank) is in the gadget van, driving more slowly while keeping an eye on a map of traffic lights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plotonomicon: The Space Time Deck</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 13:45:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Space·Time Deck is a deck of 67 cards and a few blanks, loosely inspired
from Tarot decks, and designed to aid with story improv, including
Role-Playing Games and other forms of Storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of the cards is designed to be interpreted on its own, and to be used
as part of a narrative role-playing ruleset. For both reasons, cards
have both illustrations and symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Space·Time Deck is used throughout &lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/plotonomicon&#34;&gt;the Plotonomicon&lt;/a&gt;
for building plots, characters, places, factions, twists, etc. and
throughout &lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/n-dimensional-tourists&#34;&gt;the N-Dimensional Tourists&lt;/a&gt;
as a base for resolving obstacles, conflicts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Space Time Deck</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 13:45:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Space·Time Deck is a deck of 67 cards and a few blanks, loosely inspired
from Tarot decks, and designed to aid with story improv, including
Role-Playing Games and other forms of Storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of the cards is designed to be interpreted on its own, and to be used
as part of a narrative role-playing ruleset. For both reasons, cards
have both illustrations and symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Space·Time Deck is used throughout &lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/plotonomicon&#34;&gt;the Plotonomicon&lt;/a&gt;
for building plots, characters, places, factions, twists, etc. and
throughout &lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/n-dimensional-tourists&#34;&gt;the N-Dimensional Tourists&lt;/a&gt;
as a base for resolving obstacles, conflicts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Space Time Deck</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 13:45:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Space·Time Deck is a deck of 67 cards and a few blanks, loosely inspired
from Tarot decks, and designed to aid with story improv, including
Role-Playing Games and other forms of Storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of the cards is designed to be interpreted on its own, and to be used
as part of a narrative role-playing ruleset. For both reasons, cards
have both illustrations and symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Space·Time Deck is used throughout &lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/plotonomicon&#34;&gt;the Plotonomicon&lt;/a&gt;
for building plots, characters, places, factions, twists, etc. and
throughout &lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/n-dimensional-tourists&#34;&gt;the N-Dimensional Tourists&lt;/a&gt;
as a base for resolving obstacles, conflicts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plotonomicon: About This Book</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:22:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon-about/</guid>
      <description>As all good things do, this book starts with a story.
It&amp;rsquo;s the story of a Game Master (let&amp;rsquo;s call her Alice), who spent weeks preparing a campaign for her players. Maybe the Players&amp;rsquo;s Characters were to be a company of heroes, who would save the land from a dragon. Or maybe they were students in magics, who were expected to find the sinister secrets of the Sorcerous Highschool. Or maybe they were survivors of a zombie apocalypse, who were to spend each of their days hiding from hordes of shambling undead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Dimensional Tourists: Conflict Resolution</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-conflict-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:15:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-conflict-resolution/</guid>
      <description>THIS CONTENT IS DEPRECATED Playtesting has indicated that these rules don&amp;rsquo;t work as well as hoped.
We&amp;rsquo;ll leave them here for historical reasons, but newer versions of N-Dimensional Tourists do not use these rules.
 These rules describes how to resolve Conflicts between two parties or more during a role-playing game using the N-Dimensional Tourists ruleset. This mechanism is designed to be generic enough to handle pretty much any kind, while remaining mostly narrative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Dimensional Tourists: On your Character Sheet</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-attributes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 19:30:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/tourists-attributes/</guid>
      <description>In N-Dimensional Tourists, each major character is defined by:
 A Card, which is used during improv. Any number of Aspects, which determine what the character can do; 5 Attributes, which determine how good a character is at their tasks; Any number of Specialties, which let them use Attributes in unusual manners; At least one Weakness, which makes their life more complicated.  Minor non-player characters are typically described in even broader strokes, at least until the story calls upon them to be defined in more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Dimensional Tourists</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/n-dimensional-tourists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 19:30:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/n-dimensional-tourists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;N-Dimensional Tourists is a lightweight, generic ruleset for fiction-first, narrative roleplaying.
Instead of dice, it uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/space-time-deck&#34;&gt;Space·Time Deck&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Unknown</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-out-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 22:22:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-out-there/</guid>
      <description>Well, after the Triumphs and four suits (Paper, Rock, Blade, Serpent), it is time to conclude the Space·Time Deck with its last suit: the Suit of Unknown (you are free to call it the Suit of Spock)!
Unknown symbolizes:
 imagination; intuition; perception; illusions; dreams.  Whenever you draw a card of this suit, you are encouraged to integrate any of these concepts to your interpretation.
The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Credits  Cards David Teller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, Indie Rpg Planet!</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/hello-indie-rpg-planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 22:10:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/hello-indie-rpg-planet/</guid>
      <description>Thanks Alex Schroeder for putting together the Indie RPG Planet! I believe that the Indie RPG community was sorely missing something like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Serpents</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-serpents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 12:37:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-serpents/</guid>
      <description>Did you think the Space·Time Deck was done after
 the Triumphs; the Suit of Paper; the Suit of Rock; the Suit of Blade?  Were it only that it were so simple!
Here&amp;rsquo;s the fourth suit: the Suit of Serpents.
Serpents traditionally symbolize:
 speed; stealth; adaptation; survival; lies; forbidden knowledge; forbidden power; temptation.  The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Credits  Cards David Teller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflict Resolution With the Space·Time Deck</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/conflict-resolution-with-the-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 17:35:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/conflict-resolution-with-the-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>Most Role-Playing Games resolve conflicts with dice. But since we have a Space·Time Deck at hand (or any other kind of Tarot-like Deck), let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can use it to bring about a different manner of resolving conflicts.
About Conflicts A Conflict is a scene in which two parties or more have agendas, which cannot be fulfilled simultaneously. In most role-playing games, the most common form of conflict is the combat, but that is by no mean the only form possible: conflict could be car races, social wit, political campaigns, chess, battlefield strategy, attempting to ruin your opponent&amp;rsquo;s reputation or fortune, popularity contests, football matches, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Scissors (or Blades)</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-scissors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 10:50:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-scissors/</guid>
      <description>After the Suit of Paper and the Suit of Rock, here comes the Suit of Scissor (or perhaps Blades – name to be finalized).
Warning Museum-level nudity.
Scissors/blade traditionally symbolize:
 forced change; violence; destiny; death.  The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: Afterlife and the Time Adjustment Foundation</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-time-adjustment-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 17:40:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-time-adjustment-foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the Time Federation is forever limited by its Prime Directive, the militarist branches managed to get away with murder, kidnapping and torture by finessing paradoxes. Some cadres of the Time Federation wanted the ability to counter-attack, and managed to create a covert operations branch called the &lt;strong&gt;Time Adjustment Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;. And further is exactly where it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Rock</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</guid>
      <description>After the Suit of Paper, here comes the Suit of Rock.
Warning Museum-level nudity.
Rock traditionally symbolizes:
 stability; reliability; power.  The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there to delimit the safe-to-draw zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Suit of Paper</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 21:37:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, we introduced the Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck. It&amp;rsquo;s time for a second delivery: the Suit of Paper.
Paper traditionally symbolizes:
 knowledge and wisdom; deduction; riches; fragility.  The cards:
 Ruler  Dragon  Treasure  Soldier  Builder  Seeker  Lover  Servant  Home  Foot (blank, customizable)  Teddy bear (blank, customizable)   Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: On the way to proof printing!</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/cards-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 10:04:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/cards-draft/</guid>
      <description>The 22 Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck are now on their way to proof printing! We should receive the proofs in early December. If everything is alright, we should be able to sell them through DriveThru by End of Year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role-Playing Game Pitch: Toys of the Gods</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-toys-of-the-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 18:46:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-toys-of-the-gods/</guid>
      <description>There are gods in this story, almighty or as near can be. This is not their story.
These gods shape and make history of mankind, Earth and beyond. This is not the story of mankind, Earth or beyond.
Let it be known that the gods have children, and that some of these children will ascend to godhood, while others will stop mere heroes or monsters, and the rest will fail and fall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Idea for a future Role-Playing Game: Wandering Spirits</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-wandering-spirits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 14:00:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/an-idea-wandering-spirits/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a possible idea for a setting. It owns to Hurlements, Nephilim, Highlander, Continuum.
The story is set on our Earth, past, present and future.
The heroes are immortal, Wandering Spirits. They have existed on Earth since before Mankind, and will still be there after Mankind. In a way, they are gods: free to roam at will, to experience it all, without fear of consequences. In another way, they are but prisoners, condemned to live and relive the history of the world, either as passive observers, or as mere humans, borrowed for a day or a lifetime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvising with the Space·Time Deck: V. Hello, you gorgeous!</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/deck-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 12:05:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/deck-5/</guid>
      <description>This is an extract from the Plotonomicon.
Note that we have just changed the picture from
The old picture (The Slaughter of the Innocents) one was considered too violent – while both are museum pieces, the first one depicts mass murder of children, and was thus discarded as not-safe-for-children&amp;rsquo;s-hands.
This new version gets rid of almost all violence, and offers much more symbolism, hence much more freedom of improv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Ronin Time Bureaucrats</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/ronin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:19:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/ronin/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re currently working on a Role-Playing Game called Ronin Time Bureaucrats.
Expect brains-over-brawn, improv and handwavy time paradoxes.
You can find the latest draft (mostly complete, unformatted) online. Even in this unfinished form, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to leave feedbak!
Stay tuned for more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plotonomicon</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:18:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/plotonomicon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oops, the heroes have ruined the story, again. They managed to get Camelot invaded by the peaceful Seelie while King Arthur was at war, to kill teenage Karl Marx while vacationing in Space·Time or to blow up the Magical University where the entire campaign was meant to take place. Also, they have just entered the Unknowable Dungeon of Unspeakable Death, for which you have no maps, or they are due to meet the Ambassador of the Qfew&amp;rsquo;dhi Confederation, the one you just invented by pushing random keys on your keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to switch to improv mode!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How will King Arthur Pendragon react to news of the invasion?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How will history readjust itself without Karl Marx?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How will the Unseen Council protect the Mundane Sphere without the Sevenfold Anchor?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What evil lurks in the Unknowable Dungeon of Unspeakable Death?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does a Qfew&amp;rsquo;dhi even look like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog knows! The Space·Time Deck knows!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(well, or at least, they can help you improvise an answer)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/images/plotonomicon/cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a Game Master, a Player, a Writer, or any kind of Storyteller, this book and its companion Space·Time Deck
are designed for you. Because you may need to improvise characters on the fly, to explore dungeons without maps,
to spice up fights and altercations and pursuits and confrontations of all sorts, to come up with exotic planets,
unheard of magical creatures, threats past and future, not to mention stories, stories-within-stories and
ultimate plot twists, all of this without breaking pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, we are here for you. We bring you improv and storytelling tricks and techniques,
examples, and a tarot-like deck of cards designed to help you keep your stories varied,
interesting and fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re on DriveThruRPG!</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/now-on-drivethru/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:09:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/now-on-drivethru/</guid>
      <description>After a few weeks spent composing, recomposing and polishing our Fate comic book tutorial, it&amp;rsquo;s now available on DriveThruRPG for pay-as-you-want, starting at $0.
As previously, the license allows you to share, reproduce and modify, provided you maintain credits, so feel free to bring it to your playing table.
We&amp;rsquo;re working on making it available print-on-demand.
Thanks to all the fine folks on Reddit communities /u/RPGdesign and /u/FATErpg for the feedback, and thanks to Evil Hat for making such a great game!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improv(is)ing stories with cards</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/why-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 19:01:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/why-cards/</guid>
      <description>Earlier, we have posted the Space·Time Deck.
It&amp;rsquo;s a set of cards, designed to help with improv.
But why cards?
In theory, an improv Storyteller should be able to use anything as support for improvisation. That&amp;rsquo;s true whether they&amp;rsquo;re performing for an audience, or improvising a plot for an ongoing Role-Playing Game, or improvising their character as a RPG player, or writing a book.
Do you know the ideal improviser? His name is Keyser Söze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Space·Time Deck</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 17:43:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>The Space·Time Deck is a card deck designed to be used as an improv tool, both for storytelling and role-playing games.
 The Excuse.  I.  II.  III.  IV.  V.  VI.  VII.  VIII.  IX.  X.  XI.  XII.  XIII.  XIV.  XV.  XVI.  XVII.  XVIII.  XIX.  XX.  XXI.  Back.  Blank 1  Blank 2  Blank 3  Blank 4  Blank 5  Cheatsheet Front  Cheatsheet Back   More about this deck in future posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comic book tutorial for Fate Core</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/fate-rules-comic-leaflet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:04:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/fate-rules-comic-leaflet/</guid>
      <description>If you are interested in improv/narrative role-playing games, you may have heard of Fate Core, a great ruleset made by Evil Hat exactly for this purpose. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, it&amp;rsquo;s excellent, and it&amp;rsquo;s missing a tutorial, so here is one:
As you can see, it fits in one sheet, and it&amp;rsquo;s designed to be printed and brought with you at your table.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to make it available in other languages – if you wish to help, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: Is there an afterlife?</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-afterlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 19:24:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-afterlife/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is there an afterlife?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, of course, there is, and you came to the right place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats</title>
      <link>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 09:30:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://space-timewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</guid>
      <description>« Nobody remembers with certainty in which year the Great Snafu took place, but people generally agree that it was on a September, or perhaps on a Saturday afternoon, on some even-numbered millenium. Also, it involved blowing up the Universe, which made pretty much everybody unhappy, except for a few people who had been waiting for this opportunity to loudly exclaim &amp;ldquo;I told you so&amp;rdquo;, and even they were not happy for long.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>