<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ronin-time-bureaucrats on Space·Time Will Tell</title>
    <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/categories/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ronin-time-bureaucrats on Space·Time Will Tell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:04:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/categories/ronin-time-bureaucrats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Rock Suit</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-rock/</guid>
      <description>After the Paper Suit, here comes the Rock Suit.
Warning Some nudity.
Rock traditionally symbolizes: - stability; - reliability; - power.
The cards: - Ruler - Dragon - Treasure - Soldier - Builder - Seeker - Lover - Servant - Home - Foot (blank, customizable) - Teddy bear (blank, customizable) Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards. They are just there to delimit the safe-to-draw zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: The Paper Suit</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 21:37:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/suit-paper/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, we introduced the Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck. It&amp;rsquo;s time for a second delivery: the Paper Suit.
Paper traditionally symbolizes: - knowledge and wisdom; - riches; - fragility.
The cards: - Ruler - Dragon - Treasure - Soldier - Builder - Seeker - Lover - Servant - Home - Foot (blank, customizable) - Teddy bear (blank, customizable) Note that the blue borders are not part of the cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space·Time Deck: On the way to proof printing!</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/cards-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 10:04:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/cards-draft/</guid>
      <description>The 22 Trump Cards of the Space·Time Deck are now on their way to proof printing! We should receive the proofs in early December. If everything is alright, we should be able to sell them through DriveThru by End of Year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Ronin Time Bureaucrats</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/ronin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:19:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/ronin/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re currently working on a Role-Playing Game called Ronin Time Bureaucrats.
Expect brains-over-brawn, improv and handwavy time paradoxes.
You can find the latest draft (mostly complete, unformatted) online. Even in this unfinished form, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to leave feedbak!
Stay tuned for more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re on DriveThruRPG!</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/now-on-drivethru/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:09:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/now-on-drivethru/</guid>
      <description>After a few weeks spent composing, recomposing and polishing our Fate comic book tutorial, it&amp;rsquo;s now available on DriveThruRPG for pay-as-you-want, starting at $0.
As previously, the license allows you to share, reproduce and modify, provided you maintain credits, so feel free to bring it to your playing table.
We&amp;rsquo;re working on making it available print-on-demand.
Thanks to all the fine folks on Reddit communities /u/RPGdesign and /u/FATErpg for the feedback, and thanks to Evil Hat for making such a great game!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improv(is)ing stories with cards</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/why-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 19:01:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/why-cards/</guid>
      <description>Earlier, we have posted the Space·Time Deck.
It&amp;rsquo;s a set of cards, designed to help with improv.
But why cards?
In theory, an improv Storyteller should be able to use anything as support for improvisation. That&amp;rsquo;s true whether they&amp;rsquo;re performing for an audience, or improvising a plot for an ongoing Role-Playing Game, or improvising their character as a RPG player, or writing a book.
Do you know the ideal improviser? His name is Keyser Söze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Space·Time Deck</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-space-time-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 17:43:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/the-space-time-deck/</guid>
      <description>The Space·Time Deck is a card deck designed to be used as an improv tool, both for storytelling and role-playing games.
 The Excuse.  I.  II.  III.  IV.  V.  VI.  VII.  VIII.  IX.  X.  XI.  XII.  XIII.  XIV.  XV.  XVI.  XVII.  XVIII.  XIX.  XX.  XXI.  Back.   We will be posting more about this deck in future posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comic book tutorial for Fate Core</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/fate-rules-comic-leaflet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:04:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/fate-rules-comic-leaflet/</guid>
      <description>If you are interested in improv/narrative role-playing games, you may have heard of Fate Core, a great ruleset made by Evil Hat exactly for this purpose. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, it&amp;rsquo;s excellent, and it&amp;rsquo;s missing a tutorial, so here is one:
As you can see, it fits in one sheet, and it&amp;rsquo;s designed to be printed and brought with you at your table.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to make it available in other languages – if you wish to help, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats: Is there an afterlife?</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-afterlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 19:24:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/rtb-afterlife/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is there an afterlife?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, of course, there is, and you came to the right place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronin Time Bureaucrats</title>
      <link>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 09:30:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacetimewilltell.yoric.xyz/post/ronin-time-bureaucrats/</guid>
      <description>« Nobody remembers with certainty in which year the Great Snafu took place, but people generally agree that it was on a September, or perhaps on a Saturday afternoon, on some even-numbered millenium. Also, it involved blowing up the Universe, which made pretty much everybody unhappy, except for a few people who had been waiting for this opportunity to loudly exclaim &amp;ldquo;I told you so&amp;rdquo;, and even they were not happy for long.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>